<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Tech News</title><link>https://konrad.website/liveboat-github-runner/</link><description></description><item><title>Astronomers Confirm First &apos;Lone&apos; Black Hole Discovery - and It&apos;s in the Milky Way</title><link>https://science.slashdot.org/story/25/04/20/2153201/astronomers-confirm-first-lone-black-hole-discovery---and-its-in-the-milky-way?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 21:55:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[For the first time, astronomers have confirmed the existence of a lone black hole," reports Science News — "one with no star orbiting it."



It's "the only one so far," says Kailash Sahu, an astronomer at the Space Telescope Science Institute in Baltimore. In 2022, Sahu and his colleagues discovered the dark object coursing through the constellation Sagittarius. A second team disputed the claim, saying the body might instead be a neutron star. New observations from the Hubble Space Telescope now confirm that the object's mass is so large that it must be a black hole, Sahu's team reports in the April 20 Astrophysical Journal.... [And that second team has revised its assessment and now agrees: the object is a black hole.] 

While solitary black holes should be common, they are hard to find. The one in Sagittarius revealed itself when it passed in front of a dim background star, magnifying the star's light and slowly shifting its position due to the black hole's gravity. This passage occurred in July 2011, but the star's position is still changing. "It takes a long time to do the observations," Sahu says. "Everything is improved if you have a longer baseline and more observations." The original discovery relied on precise Hubble measurements of star positions from 2011 to 2017. The new work incorporates Hubble observations from 2021 and 2022 as well as data from the Gaia spacecraft. 

The upshot: The black hole is about seven times as massive as the sun, give or take 0.8 solar masses.... Located 5,000 light-years from Earth, this black hole is much closer than the supermassive one at the Milky Way's center, which also lies in Sagittarius but about 27,000 light-years from us. The star-rich region around the galactic center provides an ideal hunting ground for solitary black holes passing in front of stars. Sahu hopes to find additional lone black holes by using the Nancy Grace Roman Space Telescope, slated for launch in 2027.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Palantir exec defends company’s immigration surveillance work</title><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/04/20/palantir-exec-defends-companys-immigration-surveillance-work/</link><author>Anthony Ha</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 21:48:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[One of the founders of startup accelerator Y Combinator offered unsparing criticism this weekend of the controversial data analytics company Palantir, leading a company executive to offer an extensive defense of Palantir’s work. The back-and-forth came after federal filings showed that U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) — tasked with carrying out the Trump administration’s […]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>OpenAI’s o3 AI model scores lower on a benchmark than the company initially implied</title><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/04/20/openais-o3-ai-model-scores-lower-on-a-benchmark-than-the-company-initially-implied/</link><author>Kyle Wiggers</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 21:19:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A discrepancy between first- and third-party benchmark results for OpenAI’s o3 AI model is raising questions about the company’s transparency and model testing practices. When OpenAI unveiled o3 in December, the company claimed the model could answer just over a fourth of questions on FrontierMath, a challenging set of math problems. That score blew the […]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Linux 6.15-rc3 Released With GCC 15 Build Fixes, Intel Bartlett Lake &amp; Zen 5 Check</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.15-rc3-Released</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 21:05:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Easter doesn't get in the way of Linus Torvalds' weekly kernel release regiment: Linux 6.15-rc3 is now available for testing the latest kernel fixes ahead of the stable Linux 6.15 kernel release coming around the end of May...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Conservations Say &apos;De-Extinction&apos; Not the Answer to Saving Extinct Species</title><link>https://news.slashdot.org/story/25/04/20/2053222/conservations-say-de-extinction-not-the-answer-to-saving-extinct-species?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[There was excitement when biotech company Collosal announced genetically modified grey wolves (first hailed as a "de-extinction" of the Dire wolf species after several millennia). "But bioethicists and conservationists are expressing unease with the kind of scientific research," writes the Chicago Tribune. [Alternate URL here.]

"Unfortunately, as clever as this science is ... it's can-do science and not should-do science," said Lindsay Marshall, director of science in animal research at Humane World for Animals, formerly the Humane Society of the U.S.... Ed Heist, a professor at Southern Illinois University and a conservation geneticist, said the news bothered him. "This is not conservation, but people conflate it," he said. "The point is entertainment...." 

Naomi Louchouarn [program director of wildlife partnerships at Humane World for Animals], has dedicated her studies and research to the relationship between humans and animals, specifically carnivores like gray wolves. "The reason our current endangered species are becoming extinct is because we don't know how to coexist with them," she said. "And this doesn't solve that problem at all." Humans can treat the symptoms of wildlife conflict with "big, flashy silver bullets" and "in this case, advanced, inefficient science," she said, but the real solution is behavioral change. "Assuming that we could actually bring back a full population of animals," Louchouarn said, "which is so difficult and so crazy — that's a big if — I don't understand the point of trying to bring back a woolly mammoth when we already can't coexist with elephants." 

The article notes that even Colossal's chief science officer says their technology is at best one of several tools for fighting biodiversity loss, calling it a battle which humans are 'not close to winning'... We as a global community need to continue to invest in traditional approaches to conservation and habitat preservation, as well as in the protection of living endangered species." 
But the article adds that the Trump administration "is citing the case of the dire wolf as it moves to reduce federal protections under the Endangered Species Act of 1973." (Wednesday U.S. interior secretary Doug Burgum has even posted on X "The concept of 'de-extinction' can serve as a bedrock for modern species conservation.") 

And the article adds that "During a livestreamed town hall with Interior Department employees on April 9, Burgum said: "If we're going to be in anguish about losing a species, now we have an opportunity to bring them back. Pick your favorite species and call up Colossal.

Ken Angielczyk, curator of mammal fossils at the Field Museum who researches extinct species that lived 200 to 300 million years ago, said it's a misguided approach. "If that's the basis ... for changing regulations related to the endangered species list, that is very, very premature," he said. "Because we can't resurrect things.... If the purpose is to restore the damage to the shared ecosystem, we have that opportunity right now," she said. "And that's the necessity immediately...." 

"This whole idea that extinction is reversible is so dangerous," Marshall said, "because then it stops us caring."
 

Thanks to long-time Slashdot reader walterbyrd for sharing the news.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Kids sure love video game movies</title><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/04/20/kids-sure-love-video-game-movies/</link><author>Anthony Ha</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 20:32:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[“A Minecraft Movie” isn’t just a hit — after three weekends in theaters, the film is estimated to have grossed $344 million domestically and $720 million worldwide. That makes it the biggest movie of an admittedly underwhelming year at the box office (so far), and the second biggest video game movie of all time. Coming […]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Famed AI Researcher Launches Controversial Startup to Replace All Human Workers Everywhere</title><link>https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/25/04/20/1921251/famed-ai-researcher-launches-controversial-startup-to-replace-all-human-workers-everywhere?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 19:23:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[TechCrunch looks at Mechanize, an ambitious new startup "whose founder — and the non-profit AI research organization he founded called Epoch — is being skewered on X..."

Mechanize was launched on Thursday via a post on X by its founder, famed AI researcher Tamay Besiroglu. The startup's goal, Besiroglu wrote, is "the full automation of all work" and "the full automation of the economy." 

Does that mean Mechanize is working to replace every human worker with an AI agent bot? Essentially, yes. The startup wants to provide the data, evaluations, and digital environments to make worker automation of any job possible. Besiroglu even calculated Mechanize's total addressable market by aggregating all the wages humans are currently paid. "The market potential here is absurdly large: workers in the US are paid around $18 trillion per year in aggregate. For the entire world, the number is over three times greater, around $60 trillion per year," he wrote. 
Besiroglu did, however, clarify to TechCrunch that "our immediate focus is indeed on white-collar work" rather than manual labor jobs that would require robotics... 

Besiroglu argues to the naysayers that having agents do all the work will actually enrich humans, not impoverish them, through "explosive economic growth." He points to a paper he published on the topic. "Completely automating labor could generate vast abundance, much higher standards of living, and new goods and services that we can't even imagine today," he told TechCrunch. 

TechCrunch wonders how jobless humans will produce goods — and whether wealth will simply concentrate around whoever owns the agents. 
But they do concede that Besiroglu may be right that "If each human worker has a personal crew of agents which helps them produce more work, economic abundance could follow..."]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Bees Are Disappearing Again</title><link>https://news.slashdot.org/story/25/04/20/1649246/the-bees-are-disappearing-again?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 17:34:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA["Honeybee colonies are under siege across much of North America..." reported the New York Times last week. [Alternate URL here.] Last winter beekeepers across America "began reporting massive beehive collapses. More than half of the roughly 2.8 million colonies collapsed, costing the industry about $600 million in economic losses..." 

America's Department of Agriculture says "sublethal exposure" to pesticides remains one of the biggest factors threatening honeybees, according to the article — but it's one of several threats. "Parasites, loss of habitat, climate change and pesticides threaten to wipe out as much as 70% or more of the nation's honeybee colonies this year, potentially the most devastating loss that the nation has ever seen."


Some years are worse than others, but there has been a steady decline over time. Scientists have named the phenomenon colony collapse disorder: Bees simply disappear after they fly out to forage for pollen and nectar. Illness disables their radar, preventing them from finding their way home. The queen and her brood, if they survive, remain defenseless. 

The precise causes remain unknown. 
Bee colonies have become even more vulnerable because of the increase in extreme weather conditions, including droughts, heat waves, monster hurricanes, explosive wildfires and floods that have damaged or destroyed the bees and the vegetation they pollinate. If that isn't bad enough, parasites — and other creatures researchers refer to as "biotic" threats that prey on bees — proliferate when there is damage to ecosystems. 

All that means that the U.S. beekeeping industry has contracted by about 2.9% over the past five years, according to data collected by IBISWorld, a research firm. Annual loss rates have been increasing among all beekeepers over the past decade with the most significant colony collapses in commercial operations happening during the past five years.
 

The article notes that "compounding the troubles for the bee industry are recent federal cuts" proposed by DOGE to America's Department of Agriculture, "where researchers were studying ways to protect the nation's honeybees." And while federal policies like tariffs could make farming more expensive, "Beekeepers also often depend on immigrants to manage their hives and to help produce commercial honey..."]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Your politeness could be costly for OpenAI</title><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/04/20/your-politeness-could-be-costly-for-openai/</link><author>Anthony Ha</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 17:12:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[“I wonder how much money OpenAI has lost in electricity costs from people saying ‘please’ and ‘thank you’ to their models.” It was a seemingly random question posed by a user on X (formerly Twitter), but OpenAI CEO Sam Altman jumped in to reply that typing those words has added up to “tens of millions […]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Is There a Greener Way to Produce Iron?</title><link>https://news.slashdot.org/story/25/04/20/019256/is-there-a-greener-way-to-produce-iron?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 16:34:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA["Using electrochemistry, University of Oregon researchers have developed a way to make iron metal for steel production without burning fossil fuels..." the University of Oregon wrote last year. "Decarbonizing this step would do roughly as much to reduce greenhouse gas emissions as converting every gas-guzzling vehicle on the roads to electric... If scaled up, the process could help decarbonize one of the largest and most emissions-intensive industries worldwide," replacing carbon-spewing industrial blast furnaces. 

Paul Kempler, their research assistant chemistry professor, added "The reason we got excited about this chemistry, is that our reactants are two things that are very cheap: saltwater and iron oxide." And this week he announced that "We actually have a chemical principle, a sort of guiding design rule, that will teach us how to identify low-cost iron oxides that we could use in these reactors." 

"Those reactions conveniently also produce chlorine, a commercially valuable byproduct," writes SciTechDaily, in a new follow-up report this week:


In their latest study, the researchers focused on improving the process by identifying which types of iron oxides make the reaction more cost-effective, an essential step toward scaling the method for industrial use.... In lab tests, the difference was striking: "With the really porous particles, we can make iron really quickly on a small area," Goldman said. "The dense particles just can't achieve the same rate, so we're limited in how much iron we can make per square meter of electrodes...." 

To take their process beyond the lab, Kempler's lab is working with researchers in other fields. A collaboration with civil engineers at Oregon State University is helping them better understand what's needed for the product to work in real-world applications. And collaboration with an electrode manufacturing company is helping them address the logistical and scientific challenges of scaling up an electrochemical process. "I think what this work shows is that technology can meet the needs of an industrial society without being environmentally devastating," Goldman said. 

"We haven't solved all the problems yet, of course, but I think it's an example that serves as a nucleation point for a different way of thinking about what solutions look like. We can continue to have industry and technology and medicine, and we can do it in a way that's clean — and that's awesome!"]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How to Prevent Your Newsletter Sign-Up From Getting Bombarded With Spam</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/how-to-prevent-your-newsletter-sign-up-from-getting-bombarded-with-spam?source=rss</link><author>4rkal</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[\
Got spammed with fake newsletter signups? Learn how to protect your forms using double opt-in, CAPTCHA, and Cloudflare.I woke up to 200 new subscribers on the newsletter of my site, videiro.com. Had it finally happened? Did my site finally go viral?\
Sadly no. After checking the new subscribers, I noticed that none had verified their email addresses, not even one, that’s definitely not a confidence.\
After some quick research, I understood that I had indeed been spammed. But all the emails look legit. Here are some examples:kathyolynn@yahoo.com
lukeckins@gmail.com
dispatch@gonealinc.com
doug_fern@hotmail.com
After some initial research (entering the emails into haveibeenpwned), it looks like most of these email addresses have been in some kind of hack or breach.\
So what was happening? How can I prevent it in the future?\
Someone decided to use compromised email addresses to spam my form. Either to pollute my newsletter, to see how far they could go, or just because they can?When making anything publicly available on the internet, there will be spammers, there will be bots, and there will be people trying to hack it. That is why you should always be making it as secure as possible.\
It turns out that this kind of spam attack is more common than you think (especially since my blog’s newsletter also got spammed a couple of weeks later). Bots crawl the web and look for forms, usually newsletter or contact forms, and then start submitting “leaked” email addresses.\
But why? Here are some reasons I came up with:To pollute your email list (if this is a personal attack, which I don’t think it is in this case)To test the validity of the emails??To annoy the leaked email addresses owners by having them subscribed to thousands of newslettersTo annoy the website owner (me)I have a couple of solutions to this problem.Step 1: Enable Double Opt-inThe first and most important step is to make sure that all your newsletters are ‘double opt-in,’ meaning that the user has to confirm their email address before getting subscribed.\
On Listmonk (the newsletter software I am using), make sure that the list to which you are subscribing your users to is \
This means that even if your form gets spammed, you can just remove all the addresses that haven’t verified their email (after a couple of days/weeks).Step 2: Add Captcha or Cloudflare JS ChallengeThe second step I took was to enable some sort of captcha. Initially, I set up an HCaptcha via Listmonk. But I don’t think that is the best solution, as it’s kind of annoying. I am, however, using it for the videiro.com newsletter. If you're interested in how to do it, here’s how:Under , enable captcha and enter a hCaptcha.com API key (you will first have to sign up at hcaptcha.com)\
However, with this setup, if you are using custom forms (like the email subscription form below), the submission process will be kind of broken.\
So instead, what I came up with and I am currently using on 4rkal.com newsletter is to use Cloudflare JS Challenge on a specific subdomain.The way that I have set up my email newsletter is that I have Listmonk running on , a separate subdomain.\
This means that I can set that specific subdomain as “under attack” on Cloudflare and prompt users to sometimes complete a Captcha.Log in and head to the dashboard of your specific domainUnder  select  and under  select , in  enter the subdomain, in my case, that’s . The expression should look like this (http.host wildcard "newsletter.4rkal.com")Under  select Getting your website spammed is never fun, but I hope this article might have given clarity to people going through the same problem as me.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Grid Modernization Only Succeeds With Strong Cybersecurity</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/grid-modernization-only-succeeds-with-strong-cybersecurity?source=rss</link><author>Zac Amos</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 16:00:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The power grid is slowly approaching the end of its expected lifespan. Even if it were brand-new, much of it is outdated. The world is entering an age of electric vehicles, data centers, and smart technology, so grid modernization is necessary. However, with digitalization comes cyber threats. A robust security posture is vital for success.Grid Modernization Strengthens Critical InfrastructureElectrification is changing how people use the grid. Electric vehicle infrastructure, renewable energy sources, smart grid technologies, and virtual power plants are becoming prevalent. Modernizing aging analog electrical infrastructure in these ways expands access to electricity and reduces reliance on finite fossil fuels, increasing resiliency.\
As power demand surges and electrification evolves, cutting-edge, diverse technology integrations grow increasingly important. Sensors can identify and isolate faults, preventing blackouts. Smart meters can help citizens optimize energy efficiency, reducing resource waste and greenhouse gas emissions.Why Grid Modernization Is Essential in the Long TermModernization is vital because America’s electrical infrastructure is old. Most circuit breakers and transmission lines were  and 1970s, so they are approaching the end of their expected lifespans. As of 2025, various programs are dedicated to upgrading the grid.\
Until then, outdated equipment poses a cybersecurity risk. For instance, after , transformers begin to show signs of age. Age is a strong determinant of equipment failure. The older the unit is, the more vulnerable it is to tampering. Strengthening the nation’s cybersecurity posture may have to come before grid modernization.Why Cybersecurity Is Essential for Grid ModernizationSince power plants, substations, and transmission lines fall under the umbrella of critical infrastructure, strengthening them through grid modernization is important. Resilience is key for ensuring reliability during peak load and preventing extreme weather events from causing blackouts. However, these integrations could introduce cybersecurity risks.\
When power grids were mostly analog, local governments only had to worry about physical threats like vandalism and severe weather. Since  and cybercrime has evolved, they must consider ransomware, data theft, and distributed denial-of-service attacks.\
If a cybercriminal were to cause rolling blackouts or shut down the power grid entirely, untold damage could occur. Within the first few days, food in the fridge would spoil, businesses would close, public transportation would shut down, and cell towers would fail.\
Hospitals and police stations would use backup generators to keep the lights on. However, that is a temporary solution, and they would still be impacted indirectly. Unresponsive traffic lights and a loss of communication would disrupt emergency services.\
Widespread blackouts haven’t happened yet. However, that doesn’t mean an advanced threat group couldn’t cause them, especially since cyberthreats are becoming more frequent and severe.Are Current Cybersecurity Practices Enough?Whether or not current cybersecurity measures are enough to protect power infrastructure during grid modernization is the question on experts’ minds. Even though government agencies are working hard to create a robust, tamperproof system, cyberthreats are evolving rapidly.\
As digitalization progresses, novel attacks targeting electrical infrastructure are emerging. For instance, a cybercriminal could use a software-defined radio  to wirelessly abort a vehicle’s charging session from over 155 feet away. Alternatively, they could tamper with Wi-Fi to rope home charging stations into a malicious botnet.What Security Mechanisms Protect the Power Grid?To be fair, various government agencies have recognized the importance of grid security and have stepped up. For instance, the Office of Cybersecurity, Energy Security and Emergency Response (CESER) is leading the U.S. Department of Energy’s (DOE) efforts to strengthen security and resilience.\
As cyberthreats targeting power systems evolve, CESER  and development and deploys cutting-edge technologies. Facilitating information sharing helps other agencies develop cybersecurity architectures, automate attack prevention, and address gaps in smart electrical interfaces.\
The U.S. DOE’s cybersecurity-by-design approach uses tools like authentication mechanisms and data encryption to strengthen systems, even if there are wide security gaps between legacy and modern grid components.Emerging Technologies Could Strengthen SecurityVarious government agencies spend tens of millions of dollars upgrading the power grid’s safety and resilience with cutting-edge security measures. Will those defenses be enough when cybercriminals can deploy next-generation technologies like malicious machine learning models?\
Despite significant investments, the country’s energy infrastructure is still outdated, making it vulnerable. In 2024, the North American Electric Reliability Corp. found that the number of susceptible points among U.S. electrical networks  per day. Long-term plans to improve security posture are essential, but may not be enough in the short term.\
Deploying artificial intelligence for automatic threat detection would be a huge step forward. Hyperconverged infrastructure should be another consideration. This software-centric information technology (IT) setup combines servers, data storage, and networking components in a distributed platform, simplifying management, monitoring, and maintenance.Fixing the Gaps Between Legacy and Modern SystemsBefore the government can modernize electrical infrastructure, it must strengthen the grid’s security posture. However, since implementing new cybersecurity mechanisms could introduce vulnerabilities, proactive security interventions are essential.\
No matter how IT professionals upgrade energy infrastructure, gaps between legacy and modern technologies are very likely. Replacing everything from transmission lines to control systems simultaneously simply isn’t feasible, so they may face compatibility or technical issues. Informed decision-making is key to preventing unexpected vulnerabilities during this period.\
Decision-makers should also consider which implementation plan produces the fewest security vulnerabilities. Would it be better to upgrade control systems before installing vehicle charging stations? Do transmission lines and circuit breakers need internet-enabled sensors for monitoring, or would that only introduce new risks?Grid Modernization Only Succeeds With CybersecurityCybersecurity professionals — especially those at the U.S. DOE and CESER — know how important securing the nation’s power grid is. They are actively working on improvements. However, the specifics about what to implement and when to upgrade are somewhat of a gray area. As the cybersecurity landscape evolves, so must their tactics.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Water on Earth May Not Have Originated from an Asteroid Impact, Study Finds</title><link>https://news.slashdot.org/story/25/04/19/0436210/water-on-earth-may-not-have-originated-from-an-asteroid-impact-study-finds?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Discover magazine reports that a team of researchers have produced evidence that the ancient building blocks for water have been here on earth "since early in the planet's history, according to a study published in the journal Icarus."
Pinpointing when and where Earth's hydrogen is an essential key to understanding how life arose on the planet. Without hydrogen, there's no water, and without water, life can't exist here. Ironically, researchers turned to a meteorite containing hydrogen to prove that such former bodies did not provide the H2 ingredient of water's H2O recipe. They examined a rare type of meteorite — known as an enstatite chondrite — that was built similarly to early Earth 4.5 billion years ago and the team discovered hydrogen present in the chemical. The logic is that if this material resembling early Earth's composition can contain hydrogen, so too could the young planet.... 


Since the proto-Earth was made of material similar to enstatite chondrites, by the time the immature planet had grown large enough to be struck by asteroids, it would have already stashed enough hydrogen to explain Earth's present-day water supply.Although this study likely won't resolve the debate over Earth's original water source, it tilts the ta ble toward an internal, not external one. "We now think that the material that built our planet — which we can study using these rare meteorites — was far richer in hydrogen than we thought previously," James Bryson, an Oxford professor and an author of the paper, said in a press release. "This finding supports the idea that the formation of water on Earth was a natural process, rather than a fluke of hydrated asteroids bombarding our planet after it formed."]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Henry Samueli and the Rise of Digital Broadband</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/henry-samueli-1999</link><author>Tekla S. Perry</author><category>tech</category><enclosure url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy81OTkwODQ0MC9vcmlnaW4uanBnIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTc1NDQwMzAzMH0.SDNJBVOIqx5n3ogmoo6EZPHoaw-Lc4U9_rORsHlFHg8/image.jpg?width=600" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/">IEEE Spectrum</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The innovative work that made high-speed digital modems a reality]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Uncovered emails showed how Meta struggled to keep Facebook culturally relevant</title><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/04/20/uncovered-emails-showed-how-meta-struggled-to-keep-facebook-culturally-relevant/</link><author>Aisha Malik</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[With the first week of Meta’s antitrust trial behind us, documents shared by the U.S Federal Trade Commission (FTC) offered more insight into Meta’s internal struggles to keep Facebook relevant. In emails from 2022, Meta executives mulled different visions for Facebook’s future to boost its success, acknowledging that its cultural relevance was decreasing.  Fast-forward to […]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>NVIDIA Engineer Posts New NOVA Driver Patches - Still Far From Doing Anything Useful</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/NOVA-16-Patches-Still-Early</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 12:51:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Merged for the Linux 6.15 kernel were the very early boilerplate code around the NOVA driver as a new, open-source and Rust-written NVIDIA Linux kernel graphics/display driver. This successor to the Nouveau kernel driver is going to leverage the NVIDIA GPU System Processor (GSP) to make it easier to develop and maintain this open-source driver. But depending upon the GSP also means the NOVA driver will only work with RTX 20 class GPUs and newer. This driver is going to be built up gradually within the mainline Linux kernel and coming out this Easter were a new set of 16 patches for further laying the NOVA groundwork...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Sway 1.11-rc1 Released With Many New Features &amp; New Wayland Protocols</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Sway-1.11-rc1-Released</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 12:02:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sway 1.11-rc1 is out today as a test release ahead of this next Wayland compositor feature release. Sway 1.11 is bringing a number of new features for this i3-inspired Wayland compositor while also building off the new features laid out in the recent wlroots 0.19-rc1 library...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Open Source Advocate Argues DeepSeek is &apos;a Movement... It&apos;s Linux All Over Again&apos;</title><link>https://news.slashdot.org/story/25/04/20/0332214/open-source-advocate-argues-deepseek-is-a-movement-its-linux-all-over-again?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Matt Asay answered questions from Slashdot readers in 2010 (as the then-COO of Canonical). He currently runs developer relations at MongoDB (after holding similar positions at AWS and Adobe). 

This week he contributed an opinion to piece to InfoWorld arguing that DeepSeek "may have originated in China, but it stopped being Chinese the minute it was released on Hugging Face with an accompanying paper detailing its development."



Soon after, a range of developers, including the Beijing Academy of Artificial Intelligence (BAAI), scrambled to replicate DeepSeek's success but this time as open source software. BAAI, for its part, launched OpenSeek, an ambitious effort to take DeepSeek's open-weight models and create a project that surpasses DeepSeek while uniting "the global open source communities to drive collaborative innovation in algorithms, data, and systems." 

If that sounds cool to you, it didn't to the U.S. government, which promptly put BAAI on its "baddie" list. Someone needs to remind U.S. (and global) policymakers that no single country, company, or government can contain community-driven open source... DeepSeek didn't just have a moment. It's now very much a movement, one that will frustrate all efforts to contain it. DeepSeek, and the open source AI ecosystem surrounding it, has rapidly evolved from a brief snapshot of technological brilliance into something much bigger — and much harder to stop. Tens of thousands of developers, from seasoned researchers to passionate hobbyists, are now working on enhancing, tuning, and extending these open source models in ways no centralized entity could manage alone. 

For example, it's perhaps not surprising that Hugging Face is actively attempting to reverse engineer and publicly disseminate DeepSeek's R1 model. Hugging Face, while important, is just one company, just one platform. But Hugging Face has attracted hundreds of thousands of developers who actively contribute to, adapt, and build on open source models, driving AI innovation at a speed and scale unmatched even by the most agile corporate labs. 

Hugging Face by itself could be stopped. But the communities it enables and accelerates cannot. Through the influence of Hugging Face and many others, variants of DeepSeek models are already finding their way into a wide range of applications. Companies like Perplexity are embedding these powerful open source models into consumer-facing services, proving their real-world utility. This democratization of technology ensures that cutting-edge AI capabilities are no longer locked behind the walls of large corporations or elite government labs but are instead openly accessible, adaptable, and improvable by a global community. 
"It's Linux all over again..." Asay writes at one point. "What started as the passion project of a lone developer quickly blossomed into an essential, foundational technology embraced by enterprises worldwide," winning out "precisely because it captivated developers who embraced its promise and contributed toward its potential." 

We are witnessing a similar phenomenon with DeepSeek and the broader open source AI ecosystem, but this time it's happening much, much faster... 
Organizations that cling to proprietary approaches (looking at you, OpenAI!) or attempt to exert control through restrictive policies (you again, OpenAI!) are not just swimming upstream — they're attempting to dam an ocean. (Yes, OpenAI has now started to talk up open source, but it's a long way from releasing a DeepSeek/OpenSeek equivalent on GitHub.)
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>FreeType Fixes Inefficient Code Causing 10x Startup Time Hit When Loading Arial TTF Font</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeType-Slow-Loading-Arial-TTF</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 10:33:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The FreeType library for rendering text onto bitmaps that is widely used by a variety of applications has landed a set of three patches today providing an important performance improvement to address a significant inefficiency within the existing FreeType codebase...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Linux 6.13 Series Ends With The Linux 6.13.12 Release</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.13-Ends</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 10:19:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman has released a few new Linux kernel stable point releases today for Easter and also capping off the Linux 6.13 kernel cycle in the process...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>OpenVPN DCO Driver Queued In Net-Next Ahead Of Linux 6.16</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/OpenVPN-DCO-In-Net-Next-6.16</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The long-in-development OpenVPN DCO kernel driver for providing data channel offloading (DCO) to yield faster OpenVPN performance looks like it's now in a state for upstreaming with the Linux 6.16 kernel...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Escape Through Board Games</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/escape-through-board-games?source=rss</link><author>Amy Pravin Shah</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 09:49:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[\
Board games you might enjoyPlaying board games can reduce stress and draw you into an imaginary world. Included is a list of some board games you can try. We may not have autonomy over many things, but we have the choice to dream. I am spending a lot of time dreaming now. \
One of the ways I am expressing my dreaming is through board games. Board games have been a fun distraction lately. It's been fun entering imaginary worlds and learning to play various games. What do I like about playing board games?Social aspect - Playing board games with others has been a fun way of interacting while at the same time learning new things. It can be a good way to get to know new people while taking the pressure off conversation and social skills. Stimulating, but not serious - I like feeling challenged but not overly stressed, knowing the outcome is moot/unimportant/for fun.Learning - It’s refreshing learning the rules of the new games to discover how new games worked. Learning how to quickly understand the rules of the new game I am trying has been interesting and meta. I figured out my system for learning new games is a combination of reading the rulebook included in the package and watching a youtube video about the game I am trying. Now, I am finding youtubers with a lot of my same interests. Off-screen time - Working remotely can be very isolating and stressful. Spending time away from the computer screen and my phone has helped a lot. I really crave time away from my computer for a part of each day - whether that be exercising, reading or playing board games.  \n Mentally active - Playing board games is an mentally active hobby (unlike watching tv, seeing a movie or maybe attending zoom meetings) and I liked that about it. You have to initiate playing. You have to spend time learning the rules. Then, you have to try to win!  Normally, I don't find playing games like wordle or crossword puzzles very interesting. This is perhaps because you play those games by yourself and there isn’t any tangible reward.  Board games are enthralling because you can play them socially (though some games are also playable as single player games). There is a social aspect/dopamine hit from playing the games that is satisfying. \
For the last couple of months, I have spent nearly every evening devouring board games that I have checked out free from my local library. We take time learning the rules and then watching a youtube video about the rules. It's been fun learning to set up the various games and struggle to play triumphantly.  I have listed some of the games I have played below. Board games you might like: Collect gems and gain a fortuneSearch for the assassin among 25 operatives Display cunning and character to marry the man Dice rolling, city-building strategy game UNLOCK! Heroic Adventures Card GameRequires smartphone app to play Escape room like adventures Gather commodities to build towns Enjoyable territory building game HODL UP: A Bitcoin Mining GameI met the founders of this game and played the game with them. When working remotely, I spent a lot of time in my home office. It was where I spent most of my day. It began to feel like such a treat not to be jailed in that room. Playing board games gave me a cool and interesting outlet for my social and intellectual needs. It also gave me broader horizons about board game culture and aspirations to one day create my own board game. Playing board games also gave me an escape from myself and my incessant thoughts so that I could rest. It helped me very much to find this hobby and I hope you will also consider it the next time you need a healthy escape. ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New &apos;Star Wars&apos; Movie Announced Set 5 Years After &apos;Rise of Skywalker&apos;</title><link>https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/25/04/19/2211253/new-star-wars-movie-announced-set-5-years-after-rise-of-skywalker?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 07:34:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A new Star Wars movie — starring Ryan Gosling and directed by Shawn Levy — will be released in 2027, the two announced Friday at the "Star Wars Celebration" (a fan event in Japan). CNN reports:

 Set to begin production this fall, the movie will be set approximately five years after "Star Wars: Episode IX — The Rise of Skywalker," released in 2019, but will sit outside the Skywalker story as a standalone film. "The film... is an entirely new adventure featuring all-new characters set in a period of time that has not been explored on screen," said a statement from Lucasfilm, the owner of the "Star Wars" franchise... 

 "The script is just so good, the story, it has so much adventure, so much heart and original character. It's an opportunity to shine the light into a side of the universe that we may not have seen," Gosling said. Levy, the director of "Deadpool & Wolverine," told the crowd the film would have all the "fun of 'Star Wars'" but it would be done "in ways that are new and original...." 

The next movie in the franchise, "The Mandalorian & Grogu," a spin-off of "The Mandalorian" series, directed by Jon Favreau, will hit cinemas in May 2026.
 

USA Today notes that more new Star Wars movies have also been announced:

Daisy Ridley is set to star in a film that will see her character, Rey, building a new Jedi Order after the events of "The Rise of Skywalker." [This is sometimes referred to as "Star Wars Episode X: New Jedi Order."] 

"Logan" filmmaker James Mangold has also been tapped to direct a movie about the dawn of the Jedi, and [Dave] Filoni is directing one said to "close out the interconnected stories" told in the live-action Disney+ shows like "The Mandalorian."]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The TechBeat: LangChain Promised an Easy AI Interface for MySQL—Here’s What It Really Took (4/20/2025)</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/4-20-2025-techbeat?source=rss</link><author>Techbeat</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 06:10:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[By @rsystems [ 4 Min read ] 
 In this winning article by Preeti Verma from R Systems Blogbook Ch. 1, discover how GitHub Copilot boosts developer productivity through automation and learning Read More.By @riteshmodi [ 11 Min read ] 
 Embedding needs to be tested and evaluated; otherwise, hallucinations will happen. Experiment and evaluation on custom data is a must Read More.By @riteshmodi [ 9 Min read ] 
 Embedding and LLM's needs to be tested and evaluated or hallucinations will happen. Experimentation and evaluation on custom data is a must - openai and genai Read More.By @riteshmodi [ 8 Min read ] 
 Embedding and LLM's needs to be tested and evaluated or hallucinations will happen. Experimentation and evaluation on custom data is a must - openai and genai Read More.By @lee.aao [ 8 Min read ] 
 Elon claimed Grok 3 was the world's best AI. Two months later, how does it really stack up against GPT-4o, Claude 3.7 & Gemini 2.5? Read More.By @bigmao [ 7 Min read ] 
 A protocol for trash pickers, not token traders. Blockchain’s most underrated use case is waste—and Web3 might just find redemption in the rubbish. Read More.By @nailyasaf [ 8 Min read ] 
 Learn how color grading works, what color targets are, and build your own palette-based grading tool in React — from scratch and with purpose. Read More.By @clapper [ 5 Min read ] 
 Clapper is a new social media platform for content creators. Read More.By @edwinliavaa [ 4 Min read ] 
  Tonga’s digital government is broken. From Gmail addresses to insecure sites, here’s why basic tech standards could transform public services for everyone. Read More.By @janinegrainger [ 3 Min read ] 
 This past month, hackers stole a staggering $1.5 billion from the crypto exchange Bybit in what the market dubbed “The biggest digital heist ever” Read More.By @haimeng [ 6 Min read ] 
 Learn how I built a multi-stage Langchain agent for MySQL. This article details my journey, challenges, and key steps in creating an intelligent database intera Read More.By @GuyBaz [ 3 Min read ] 
 AI can generate code in seconds, but reviewing it is where real engineering happens.  Read More.By @jroseland [ 8 Min read ] 
 The word insane is drastically overused for everything from mild moodiness and irritability to emotional changes. That's not what this article is about… Read More.By @pawanjswal [ 4 Min read ] 
 In this blog, we will outline the step-by-step journey to establish a successful cybersecurity career—from the fundamentals to becoming an expert. Read More.By @thebojda [ 8 Min read ] 
 Discover how blockchain can help decentralize and democratize AI through open data, decentralized storage, and community-driven governance. Read More.By @tanush29 [ 3 Min read ] 
 How AI agents could’ve helped Pfizer speed up vaccine development by designing trials, tracking research, and predicting risks. Read More.By @missinvestigate [ 2 Min read ] 
 iAsk AI just passed half a billion searches. That’s not a typo. 500,000,000+ questions asked, problems solved, papers summarized, and headaches avoided. Read More.By @escholar [ 9 Min read ] 
 How different blockchain systems decide the correct state using mechanisms like PoW, PoS, ZK rollups, and optimistic rollups for state validation and finality.  Read More.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>US Chipmakers Fear Ceding China&apos;s AI Market to Huawei After New Trump Restrictions</title><link>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/25/04/19/2339227/us-chipmakers-fear-ceding-chinas-ai-market-to-huawei-after-new-trump-restrictions?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 04:34:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Trump administration is "taking measures to restrict the sale of AI chips by Nvidia, Advanced Micro Devices and Intel," especially in China, reports the New York Times. But that's triggered a series of dominoes. "In the two days after the limits became public, shares of Nvidia, the world's leading AI chipmaker, fell 8.4%. AMD's shares dropped 7.4%, and Intel's were down 6.8%." (AMD expects up to $800 million in charges after the move, according to CNBC, while NVIDIA said it would take a quarterly charge of about $5.5 billion.) 

The Times notes hopeful remarks Thursday from Jensen Huang, CEO of Nvidia, during a meeting with the China Council for the Promotion of International Trade. "We're going to continue to make significant effort to optimize our products that are compliant within the regulations and continue to serve China's market." But America's chipmakers also have a greater fear, according to the article: "that their retreat could turn the Chinese tech giant Huawei into a global chip-making powerhouse."
 "For the U.S. semiconductor industry, China is gone," said Handel Jones, a semiconductor consultant at International Business Strategies, which advises electronics companies. He projects that Chinese companies will have a majority share of chips in every major category in China by 2030... Huang's message spoke to one of his biggest fears. For years, he has worried that Huawei, China's telecommunications giant, will become a major competitor in AI. He has warned U.S. officials that blocking U.S. companies from competing in China would accelerate Huawei's rise, said three people familiar with those meetings who spoke on the condition of anonymity. 
 If Huawei gains ground, Huang and others at Nvidia have painted a dark picture of a future in which China will use the company's chips to build AI data centers across the world for the Belt and Road Initiative, a strategic effort to increase Beijing's influence by paying for infrastructure projects around the world, a person familiar with the company's thinking said... 

 Nvidia's previous generation of chips perform about 40% better than Huawei's best product, said Gregory C. Allen, who has written about Huawei in his role as director of the Wadhwani AI Center at the Center for Strategic and International Studies. But that gap could dwindle if Huawei scoops up the business of its American rivals, Allen said. Nvidia was expected to make more than $16 billion in sales this year from the H20 in China before the restriction. Huawei could use that money to hire more experienced engineers and make higher-quality chips. Allen said the U.S. government's restrictions also could help Huawei bring on customers like DeepSeek, a leading Chinese AI startup. Working with those companies could help Huawei improve the software it develops to control its chips. Those kinds of tools have been one of Nvidia's strengths over the years. 
TechRepublic identifies this key quote from an earlier article:

"This kills NVIDIA's access to a key market, and they will lose traction in the country," Patrick Moorhead, a tech analyst with Moor Insights & Strategy, told The New York Times. He added that Chinese companies will buy from local rival Huawei instead.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Scientists Find Rare Evidence Earth is &apos;Peeling&apos; Under the Sierra Nevada Mountains</title><link>https://news.slashdot.org/story/25/04/20/0136216/scientists-find-rare-evidence-earth-is-peeling-under-the-sierra-nevada-mountains?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 01:39:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA["Seismologist Deborah Kilb was wading through California earthquake records from the past four decades when she noticed something odd," reports CNN, "a series of deep earthquakes that had occurred under the Sierra Nevada at a depth where Earth's crust would typically be too hot and high pressure for seismic activity..."

Kilb flagged the data to Vera Schulte-Pelkum, a research scientist at the Cooperative Institute for Research in Environmental Sciences and an associate research professor of geological sciences at the University of Colorado Boulder... Using the newfound data, the researchers imaged the Sierra Nevada through a technique known as receiver function analysis, which uses seismic waves to map Earth's internal structure. The scientists found that in the central region of the mountain range, Earth's crust is currently peeling away, a process scientifically known as lithospheric foundering. Kilb and Schulte-Pelkum reported the findings in December in the journal Geophysical Research Letters. 

The hypothesis lined up with previous speculation that the area had undergone lithospheric foundering, which happens when Earth's outermost layer sinks into the lower layer of the mantle. Now, the study authors believe that the process is ongoing and is currently progressing to the north of the mountain range, according to the study... What's happening under the Sierra Nevada could offer rare insight into how the continents formed, Schulte-Pelkum said. The finding could also help scientists identify more areas where this process is happening as well as provide a better understanding of earthquakes and how our planet operates, she added... 

Evidence for this process has been hard to come by. It is not visible from above ground, and it's an extremely slow process. Scientists theorize that the south Sierra finished the process of lithospheric foundering about 4 million to 3 million years ago, according to the study. It appears that these natural events happen occasionally around the world, Schulte-Pelkum said. "Geologically speaking, this is a pretty quick process with long periods of stability in between. ... This (lithosphere foundering) probably started happening a long time ago when we started building continents, and (the continents) have gotten bigger over time. So it's just sort of this punctuated, localized thing," she added... 


Further study within this area could also help scientists better understand how the Earth evolves on long timescales. If the lithospheric foundering continues underneath the mountain range, one can speculate that the land will continue to stretch vertically, changing the way the landscape looks now [said Mitchell McMillan, a research geologist and postdoctoral fellow at Georgia Tech, who was not involved with the study]. But that could take anywhere from several hundred thousand to a few million years, he added.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>HFS/HFS+ File-System Driver Support For Linux May End Up Being Maintained</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Apple-HFS-2025-Linux-Maintain</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:48:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Just a few days ago there was talk of potentially removing the Apple HFS and HFS+ file-system drivers from the Linux kernel considering they had been orphaned for a decade and beginning to cause a maintenance burden. After briefly being marked for deprecation, it now looks like the drivers may be maintained with new maintainers alleging to step-up to the role...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Could AI and Automation Find Better Treatments for Cancer - and Maybe Aging?</title><link>https://science.slashdot.org/story/25/04/19/0336255/could-ai-and-automation-find-better-treatments-for-cancer---and-maybe-aging?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 22:34:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[CNN looks at "one field that's really benefitting" from the use of AI: "the discovery of new medicines". 


The founder/CEO of London-based LabGenius says their automated robotic system can assemble "thousands of different DNA constructs, each of which encodes a completely unique therapeutic molecule that we'll then test in the lab. This is something that historically would've had to have been done by hand." In short, CNN says, their system lets them "design and conduct experiments, and learn from them in a circular process that creates molecular antibodies at a rate far faster than a human researcher." 
While many cancer treatments have debilitating side effects, CNN notes that LabGenius "reengineers therapeutic molecules so they can selectively target just the diseased cells."
 But more importantly, their founder says they've now discovered "completely novel molecules with over 400x improvement in [cell] killing selectivity." 

A senior lecturer at Imperial College London tells CNN that LabGenius seems to have created an efficient process with seamless connections, identifying a series of antibodies that look like they can target cancer cells very selectively "that's as good as any results I've ever seen for this." (Although the final proof will be what happens when they test them on patients..) "And that's the next step for Labgenius," says CNN. "They aim to have their first therapeutics entering clinics in 2027." 

Finally, CNN asks, if it succeeds is their potential beyond cancer treatment? "If you take one step further," says the company's CEO/founder, "you could think about knocking out senescent cells or aging cells as a way to treat the underlying cause of aging."]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Evaluating TnT-LLM Text Classification: Human Agreement and Scalable LLM Metrics</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/evaluating-tnt-llm-text-classification-human-agreement-and-scalable-llm-metrics?source=rss</link><author>Language Models (dot tech)</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 22:00:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[4.2 Phase 2 Evaluation StrategiesTo quantitatively evaluate text classification, we create a benchmark dataset with reliable ground-truth annotations as follows:\
Task and Annotation Reliability. We first assess the reliability of the label assignment task and the human annotations by involving multiple human annotators and calculating the interrater agreement (Cohen’s Kappa [6] between two raters and Fleiss’ Kappa [7] among multiple raters). We then resolve disagreements between human annotations by either voting or deliberation, and obtain a consensus human annotation for each instance. Then we use an LLM as an additional annotator to perform the same label assignment task, and measure the agreement between the LLM annotation and the consensus human label. Intuitively, this agreement captures how well the LLM is aligned with (the majority of) human annotators and how reliable it is for this label assignment task.\
 We apply both human and LLM annotations on a small-scale corpus sample and calculate the conventional multiclass and multilabel classification metrics (e.g., Accuracy, F1) with human annotations as the ground truth. These metrics evaluate how the label classifier is aligned with human preferences on a small subset of the corpus. We then apply the LLM annotator on a larger-scale corpus sample and leverage the resulting annotations as the oracle to calculate the same classification metrics. These metrics enable a comprehensive diagnosis of the label classifier performance at scale on different aspects of the corpus, such as domains, languages, and time ranges.\
In practice, we recommend leveraging both human evaluation and LLM-based metrics as a holistic evaluation suite, while also taking into account the task and annotation reliability. This approach can help us identify and mitigate the possible bias that may arise from either method or be affected by the task complexity, and enable us to scale up the evaluation and annotation to a large corpus sample with confidence, thus obtaining more robust and informative evaluation results.(1) Mengting Wan, Microsoft Corporation and Microsoft Corporation;(2) Tara Safavi (Corresponding authors), Microsoft Corporation;(3) Sujay Kumar Jauhar, Microsoft Corporation;(4) Yujin Kim, Microsoft Corporation;(5) Scott Counts, Microsoft Corporation;(6) Jennifer Neville, Microsoft Corporation;(7) Siddharth Suri, Microsoft Corporation;(8) Chirag Shah, University of Washington and Work done while working at Microsoft;(9) Ryen W. White, Microsoft Corporation;(10) Longqi Yang, Microsoft Corporation;(11) Reid Andersen, Microsoft Corporation;(12) Georg Buscher, Microsoft Corporation;(13) Dhruv Joshi, Microsoft Corporation;(14) Nagu Rangan, Microsoft Corporation.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Curiosity Rover Finds Hints of a Carbon Cycle on Ancient Mars</title><link>https://science.slashdot.org/story/25/04/19/2119207/curiosity-rover-finds-hints-of-a-carbon-cycle-on-ancient-mars?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 21:34:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Billions of years ago Mars "had a warm, habitable climate with liquid water in lakes and flowing rivers," writes Ars Technica. 

But "In order for Mars to be warm enough to host liquid water, there must have been a lot of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere," says Benjamin Tutolo, a researcher at the University of Calgary. "The question we've been asking for at least 30 years was where the record of all this carbon is."


Tutolo led a new study of rock samples collected by the Curiosity rover that might have answered this question... 

Curiosity rover was called Mars Science Laboratory for a reason. It went to the red planet fitted with a suite of instruments, some of which even the newer Perseverance was lacking. These enabled it to analyze the collected Martian rocks on the spot and beam the results back to Earth. "To get the most bang for the buck, NASA decided to send it to the place on Mars called the Gale Crater, because it was the tallest stack of sediments on the planet," Tutolo says. The central peak of Gale Crater was about 5 kilometers tall, created by the ancient meteorite impact... The idea then was to climb up Mount Sharp and collect samples from later and later geological periods at increasing elevations, tracing the history of habitability and the great drying up of Mars. 

On the way, the carbon missed by the satellites was finally found... 

It turned out the samples contained roughly between 5 and 10 percent of siderite... The siderite found in the samples was also pure, which Tutolo thinks indicates it has formed through an evaporation process akin to what we see in evaporated lakes on Earth. This, in turn, was the first evidence we've found of the ancient Martian carbon cycle. "Now we have evidence that confirms the models," Tutolo claims. The carbon from the atmosphere was being sequestered in the rocks on Mars just as it is on Earth. The problem was, unlike on Earth, it couldn't get out of these rocks... A large portion of carbon that got trapped in Martian rocks stayed in those rocks forever, thinning out the atmosphere.
 
"While it's likely the red planet had its own carbon cycle, it was an imperfect one that eventually turned it into the lifeless desert it is today," the article points out. 

But the study still doesn't entirely explain what warmed the atmosphere of Mars — or why Martian habitability "was seemingly intermittent and fluctuating".]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Congress has questions about 23andMe bankruptcy</title><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/04/19/congress-has-questions-about-23andme-bankruptcy/</link><author>Anthony Ha</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 20:56:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Leaders of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce said they are investigating how 23andMe’s bankruptcy might affect customers’ data. Representatives Brett Guthrie, Gus Bilirakis, and Gary Palmer (all Republicans) sent a letter Thursday to the genetic testing company’s interim CEO Joe Selsavage asking a number of questions about how 23andMe will handle customer data […]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>High School Student Discovers 1.5M New Astronomical Objects by Developing an AI Algorithm</title><link>https://science.slashdot.org/story/25/04/19/1353245/high-school-student-discovers-15m-new-astronomical-objects-by-developing-an-ai-algorithm?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[For combining machine learning with astronomy, high school senior Matteo Paz won $250,000 in the Regeneron Science Talent Search, reports Smithsonian magazine:

The young scientist's tool processed 200 billion data entries from NASA's now-retired Near-Earth Object Wide-field Infrared Survey Explorer (NEOWISE) telescope. His model revealed 1.5 million previously unknown potential celestial bodies.... [H]e worked on an A.I. model that sorted through the raw data in search of tiny changes in infrared radiation, which could indicate the presence of variable objects. 
Working with a mentor at the Planet Finder Academy at Caltech, Paz eventually flagged 1.5 million potential new objects, accoridng to the article, including supernovas and black holes. 
And that mentor says other Caltech researchers are using Paz's catalog of potential variable objects to study binary star systems. 

Thanks to long-time Slashdot reader schwit1 for sharing the article.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>CA/Browser Forum Votes for 47-Day Cert Durations By 2029</title><link>https://it.slashdot.org/story/25/04/19/1745216/cabrowser-forum-votes-for-47-day-cert-durations-by-2029?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link><author>EditorDavid</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 19:34:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source><content:encoded><![CDATA["Members of the CA/Browser Forum have voted to slash cert lifespans from the current one year to 47 days," reports Computerworld, "placing an added burden on enterprise IT staff who must ensure they are updated."


In a move that will likely force IT to much more aggressively use web certificate automation services, the Certification Authority Browser Forum (CA/Browser Forum), a gathering of certificate issuers and suppliers of applications that use certificates, voted [last week] to radically slash the lifespan of the certificates that verify the ownership of sites. 

The approved changes, which passed overwhelmingly, will be phased in gradually through March 2029, when the certs will only last 47 days. 

This controversial change has been debated extensively for more than a year. The group's argument is that this will improve web security in various ways, but some have argued that the group's members have a strong alternative incentive, as they will be the ones earning more money due to this acceleration... Although the group voted overwhelmingly to approve the change, with zero "No" votes, not every member agreed with the decision; five members abstained... 

In roughly one year, on March 15, 2026, the "maximum TLS certificate lifespan shrinks to 200 days. This accommodates a six-month renewal cadence. The DCV reuse period reduces to 200 days," according to the passed ballot. The next year, on March 15, 2027, the "maximum TLS certificate lifespan shrinks to 100 days. This accommodates a three-month renewal cadence. The DCV reuse period reduces to 100 days." And on March 15, 2029, "maximum TLS certificate lifespan shrinks to 47 days. This accommodates a one-month renewal cadence. The DCV reuse period reduces to 10 days."
 
The changes "were primarily pushed by Apple," according to the article, partly to allow more effective reactions to possible changes in cryptography. 

And Apple also wrote that the shift "reduces the risk of improper validation, the scope of improper validation perpetuation, and the opportunities for misissued certificates to negatively impact the ecosystem and its relying parties." 

Thanks to Slashdot reader itwbennett for sharing the news.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Intel Simplifies Its Firmware License For The Integrated Sensor Hub &quot;ISH&quot;</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-ISH-Simplified-Firmware</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 19:22:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Intel Integrated Sensor Hub "ISH" allows for offloading sensor polling and other tasks to a low-power co-processor to help reduce overall system power consumption for extending battery life with tablets, embedded devices, and 2-in1 laptops...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Robots run a half marathon, slowly</title><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/04/19/robots-run-a-half-marathon-slowly/</link><author>Anthony Ha</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 18:32:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[It looks like humanoid robots have a long way to go before catching up with human runners. Beijing’s E-Town tech hub hosted what it described as the world’s first humanoid half-marathon on Saturday, with 21 humanoid robots competing alongside thousands of humans. Bloomberg reports that the winning robot, Tiangong Ultra, was built by the government-backed […]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Which AI Model Should You Use? (Check Benchmarks)</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/which-ai-model-should-you-use-check-benchmarks?source=rss</link><author>Rutkat</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 17:30:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[There are more AI models than what you see in the news and on social media. There are hundreds, including open-source models, private ones, and the tech giant’s own: Gemini, Claude, OpenAI, Grok, Deepseek. What is a model really? Is it just a block box of data? Almost! You can think of it as a zip file of the internet with a bit of C++ code that communicates with the zip file. I credit this analogy to Andrej Karpathy, although I’m not sure if it was his idea, but he is the real industry expert.\
An AI model is a neural network utilizing a set of massive data to recognize specific patterns. Now is the time to take advantage of them and choose wisely whether for business, personal assistance, or creativity enhancement. The objective of this guide is not about “model training”; it is geared for individuals new to the field of AI who want a better understanding and to leverage the technology. You can build with AI, not over it, so after reading this guide, the knowledge gained shall be understanding general concepts, usage, and measuring accuracy.\
In this AI guide, you will learn the following, so you can skip to any section, but if you’re a beginner, read this entire article:Corresponding Tasks of ModelsNaming Convention of ModelsAccuracy Performance of Models\
As a beginner or just hearing about the popular tools, make note that there isn’t one type, multi-use case model that does everything you ask it to do. From the interface, it may appear that you are just typing to a chatbot, but there is a lot more being executed in the background. Business analysts, product managers, and engineers adopting AI can identify the objective they have and select from a category of AI models.\
Here are 4 categories of models among many:Natural Language Processing (general)Generative (Image, Video, Audio, Text, Code)Discriminative (Computer Vision, Text Analysis)\
While most models specialize in one category, others are multi-modal with different levels of accuracy. Every model has been trained on specific data and, therefore, can do specific tasks related to the data it was trained on. Here’s a list of common tasks each category of models can do:Natural Language ProcessingEnables computers to interpret, understand, and generate natural human language using tokenization and statistical models. Examples are chatbots, and the most common one is ChatGPT, which stands for “generative pre-trained transformer”. Most models are actually pre-trained transformers.Generative (Image, Video, Audio, Text, Code)They are Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs), which use two sub-models known as a generator and a discriminator. Realistic imagery, audio, text, and code can be produced based on tons of data it was trained on. Stable Diffusion is the most popular method of generating images and videos.Discriminative (Computer Vision, Text Analysis)These use algorithms designed to learn different classes of datasets for decision-making. They include sentiment analysis, optical recognition, and sentiment analysis.Using trial-and-error methods and human enforcement to produce goal-oriented outcomes, such as robotics, game playing, and autonomous driving.Naming Convention of ModelsNow that you understand the types of models and their tasks, the next step is to identify the model quality and performance. This begins with the name of the models. Let’s break down a model naming. There’s the official convention for naming AI models, but the most popular ones will just have a name followed by the version number, such as chatGPT#, Claude #, Grok #, Gemini #. \
However, the smaller open-source and task-specific models will have longer names. This can be seen on huggingface.co, which will contain the organization name, model name, parameter size, and lastly the context size.\
Let’s elaborate with examples:\
mistralai/Mistral-Small-3.1-24B-Instruct-2053Mistralai is the organizationMistral-Small is the model name3.1 is the version number24B-Instruct is the parameter count in billions of training data2053 is the context size or token countGoogle is the organization27B is the parameter size in billions\
Additional details, which you will see and need to know, are the quantization format in bits. The higher the quantization format, the more computer RAM and storage are required to operate the model. A quantization format is represented in floating point, such as 4, 6, 8, and 16. Other formats can include GPTQ, NF4, and GGML, which indicate usage for specific hardware configurations.\
The real way to determine model quality is to check benchmark scores and leaderboards. There have been several tests which you could say are semi-standardized or maybe fully standardized, but in reality, we are testing “black boxes” with tons of variables. The best measure is to check answers and responses from AI with facts and other scientific sources.\
Leaderboard websites will show sortable rankings with votes, confidence interval scores, usually in a percentage value. The common benchmarks are tests that prompt the AI model with questions and get answers that are measured. They can include: AI2 Reasoning Challenge, HellaSwag, MMLU, TruthfulQA, WinoGrande, GSM8K, HumanEval.\
Here are brief descriptions of the benchmarking methods:\
AI2 Reasoning Challenge (ARC) – 7787 multiple-choice science questions from grade school – commonsense reasoning exercises through sentence completion – Massive multitask language understanding for problem solving – assess truthfulness by encouraging falsehoods and avoiding responses like “I’m not sure”. – Winograd schema challenge with two near-identical sentences based on a trigger word – 8,000 grade school level math questions – measures the ability to generate correct Python code across 164 challenges\
Leaderboard websites for reference:]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A Look at How We Illustrate and Visualize Tech and AI: Plain Text Zine</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/a-look-at-how-we-illustrate-and-visualize-tech-and-ai-plain-text-zine?source=rss</link><author>The Markup</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 17:15:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[. as a guide to writing a transcript that would make this comic more accessible.Cover illustration featuring panels of rough pencil sketches of illustrations that The Markup has published. The center of the cover has the header text “How We Illustrate Text (and AI) at” in its own bubble. Below that is The Markup logo in a speech bubble. At the top and bottom of the cover are the Chinese characters 標記 which translate to “The Markup.”Panel 1: A manga-inspired drawing of Gabriel Hongsdusit, an Asian man with short black hair and glasses. He says, “Hi!”\
Panel 2: “I’m Gabe Hongsdusit, and I’m a visual designer at The Markup, an investigative journalism nonprofit that challenges technology to serve the public good. My job here is to figure out how we can best use visual imagery to tell our stories.”\
Panel 3:  “Many times, we uncover things that cannot be seen by the naked eye.” Below is an illustration of a manga-style eye, with sparkles and pronounced eyelashes.\
Panel 4:  “ helps us communicate the unseen…”Panel 1: “Take this story about a scoring system in Los Angeles that determined who got subsidized housing.”\
Panel 2: An illustration of a Black woman pushing up against an enlarged square with the number seven on it. There is a White person walking over the squares as steps in the background. On each square are survey questions.\
Panel 3: “This illustration by Brian Britigan tied together lots of abstract concepts that didn’t naturally have visuals:”\
Panel 4: The word “racism” written over a close-up image of the Black woman from the previous illustration.\
Panel 5: The phrase “access to resources” written over a close-up image of the White person walking away on squares.\
Panel 6: The phrase “…and the simple algorithm that affected everything” written over a close-up image of one of the squares showing a number seven.Panel 1: “To help people understand our stories, we use four themes and motifs.”\
Panel 2:  The header text “Hands” above an illustration of a hand, with the finger and thumb pressed together like a snap to form a heart shape. There is a little heart icon floating above it.\
Panel 3:  The header text “Humor and Pop Culture” above an illustration of a distorted cartoon mouse with buck teeth.\
Panel 4:  The header text “Characters” above an illustration of a cartoon face with pie eyes (the pupils are shaped like a pie with one slice removed from it) and pronounced eyelashes. The face has a wide button nose and smile.\
Panel 5: The header text “World-building” above an illustration of an open door leading to a winding road and clouds.Panel 1: “There aren’t a lot of opportunities for photography when you report on tech.”\
Panel 2: The header text “Gray building in Silicon Valley” above an illustration of a building.\
Panel 3: The header text “Senator/tech oligarch, usually White and male” above an illustration of a headless suit and tie.\
Panel 4: The header text “Whistleblower who doesn’t want to be photographed” above an illustration of a turtle hiding in its shell.\
Panel 5: “Hands show that people are behind institutions, companies, and technologies. The tech doesn’t exist without them, and it’s the decisions made by people that we want to hold accountable.”\
Panel 6: Illustration of a grayed-out web browser showing a hospital portal. A white hand behind it is pulling off a strip of the browser and pills are falling out of that strip. There is a blue glow behind the edge of the browser window.Panel 1: “Other times, the subject matter in our stories isn’t that visually compelling.”\
Panel 2: The header text “UI Form” above an illustration of four blank fields on top of a button that says “submit.”\
Panel 3: The header text “Backend Code” above an illustration of the code symbols “<…>.”\
Panel 4: The header text “Computer Servers” above an illustration of a computer server.\
Panel 5: “A straight-up image of any of those things won’t make you want to click on the story.\
So, we often use humor and cultural references to make art that’s interesting. Our focus on tech accountability doesn’t mean that we can’t have fun.”\
Panel 6: Illustration of an Italian plumber racing cars against an evil turtle. The plumber is lagging behind and has a low Wi-Fi symbol above his head. The turtle is ahead of the race and has the full Wi-Fi symbol.Panel 1: “Sometimes we integrate digital elements into our illustrations and it works well.”\
Panel 2: Illustration of the close-up of a browser window.\
Panel 3: Illustration of a round upload button, with an up arrow pointing out of a three-sided rectangular line.\
Panel 4: Illustration of a chat bubble.\
Panel 5: Illustration of a location pin.\
Panel 6: “Illustrations of browser windows get stale real fast. Creating characters helps freshen up our aesthetic (and like humor, it can make our work more fun and accessible).”\
Panel 7: An illustration showing a black-tentacled creature chasing a blue cursor with googly eyes.\
Panel 8: An illustration showing water droplets falling from a faucet and wearing ChatGPT headsets.\
Panel 9: An illustration of a square weather-app character wearing red shoes. There’s a close-up vignette on the side of it showing a red pin sticking out of it.\
Panel 10: An illustration of a yellow octopus peeking out of an abstract structure.\
Panel 11: An illustration of a smiling pink vacuum character.\
Panel 12: An illustration of a puzzled character with a round face, behind a computer monitor.Panel 1: “We report a lot on practices that happen on a screen.”\
Panel 2: The header text “Take this story about digital ad auctions, which happen online within milliseconds,” written over an illustration of an auctioneer at a lectern presenting user data in the form of a hologram to an audience of advertisers.\
Panel 3: “Illustrations for topics like this are often conceptual stock images. Boring! Instead, we used illustrations to create a new world that helps you see the narrative: A crowd of jelly bean characters bidding in an underground auction.”\
Panel 4: An illustration of an advertiser character placing the winning bid. The character is wearing a badge showing a teal and purple pill and holding up a paddle.\
Panel 5: A close-up image of a user hologram with floating icons and text around the head (“Taylor Swift”).\
Panel 6: An illustration of a banner unfurling over an image placeholder to reveal the advertisement: a teal and purple pill.Panel 1: “The power of illustration is that you’re not limited to the physical world…”\
Panel 2: The text “You can conjure new surroundings that help communicate a narrative” is written over a dark background.\
Panel 3: An illustration of two people walking into a laptop screen, which has several people inside it working on various screens. The Markup logo appears at the top.\
Panel 4: An illustration of scientists analyzing a wall with boxes of human heads. Some scientists have clipboards, others are picking up the heads off the shelves.Panel 1: “This approach also applies to AI. When we think of illustrating AI, robots immediately come to mind…”\
Panel 2: An illustration of a robotic hand.\
Panel 3: An illustration of an anime-style robot.\
Panel 4: An illustration of a robotic foot.\
Panel 5: “But robots obscure the fact that AI is created and used by .”\
Panel 6: An illustration of a woman, with her left hand holding her elbow. Next to her are magnifying glasses showing a close-up of her X-ray, but the image dissolves into pixels.Panel 1: “Julien Posture, who writes a weekly newsletter on visual culture, wrote this spot-on quote:”\
Panel 2: “From abuse of underpaid labour in post-colonial settings to the objectification of people’s lives and work as ‘data’ to the extraction of rare minerals to power increasingly demanding computational needs, AI runs not on sci-fi futuristic utopia but on the appropriation of today’s world’s material and human resources.”\
Panel 3: “It can feel like we’re living in end-times for artists when AI, trained on images without consent from their creators, can conjure up new images within seconds.”\
Panel 4: “But our hope is to use illustration to hold PEOPLE and the decisions they’ve made through AI and other forms of technology accountable.”Copy Editing and Production]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Week in Review: Google loses a major antitrust case</title><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/04/19/week-in-review-google-loses-a-major-antitrust-case/</link><author>Karyne Levy</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Welcome back to Week in Review! We’ve got tons of stuff for you this week: antitrust lawsuits against Google and Meta; Grok can now remember; Bolt CEO Ryan Breslow wants to make his mark; and much, much more. Have a great weekend! It’s over: Google violated antitrust laws in the ad tech market, a judge […]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Reality Is Flexible: You Just Have to Believe</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/reality-is-flexible-you-just-have-to-believe?source=rss</link><author>Scott D. Clary</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Most people live as if the world is fixed.\
They accept circumstances as "just the way things are." They assume industries can't be disrupted. They believe systems are too entrenched to change. They see barriers as permanent rather than temporary.\
This mindset isn't just wrong. It's the single biggest limitation keeping you from creating the life, business, and impact you're capable of.\
Mark Andreessen, the founder of Netscape and a legendary Silicon Valley venture capitalist, captured this perfectly:\
"The world is a very malleable place. If you know what you want, and you go for it with maximum energy and drive and passion, the world will often reconfigure itself around you much more quickly and easily than you would think."\
This isn't just inspirational fluff. It's a fundamental truth about how reality actually works.\
And once you understand it, everything changes.The Reality Distortion Field Is RealWhen Steve Jobs told his team the impossible needed to be done in five weeks rather than five months, they pushed back hard.\
It couldn't be done. The timeline was unrealistic. The limitations were too great.\
Jobs didn't budge. "Don't be afraid," he said. "You can do it."\
This happened so often that his team coined a term for it: the "reality distortion field." They meant it as a joke – Jobs' ability to convince people that the impossible was possible through sheer force of will.\
But here's what they missed: The distortion wasn't in Jobs' mind. It was in everyone else's.\
Jobs simply understood that most "impossible" things are merely difficult things no one has been stubborn enough to solve yet.\
What his team viewed as bending reality was actually just refusing to accept artificial limitations.\
The world is far more malleable than most people realize. Not because of magic, but because the barriers we perceive are largely constructions built from:Outdated assumptions that no one has challengedArtificial constraints that exist only through collective agreementLimiting beliefs about what's possible or permissible\
When you push against these barriers with enough force, they often dissolve more easily than you'd expect.Your Permission Isn't RequiredYou've been waiting for permission.\
Whether you realize it or not, there's something you want to build, create, or pursue – but you've been holding back until someone gives you the green light.\
You're not alone. Most people wait their entire lives for permission.\
Permission to start. Permission to lead. Permission to challenge the status quo.\
They assume success comes from following established paths and hitting predetermined milestones. Get the degree. Build the resume. Pay your dues. Wait your turn.\
But the people who reshape industries don't wait for permission. They take action while others are still waiting to be called on.\
Sara Blakely didn't ask the male-dominated undergarment industry if she could revolutionize shapewear. She just cut the feet off her pantyhose and created Spanx.\
Brian Chesky and Joe Gebbia didn't ask hotel chains if they could turn spare bedrooms into accommodations. They just put air mattresses on their floor and created Airbnb.\
What would you do differently tomorrow if you stopped waiting for someone to tell you it's okay to proceed?\
Think about it. Really think. What idea, project, or career move would you immediately pursue?\
The most dangerous form of self-deception is believing that you need someone else's approval or authorization to pursue your vision.\
The world is malleable, but only for those willing to start reshaping it without an engraved invitation.The Muscle Behind MalleabilityAndreessen's quote contains a critical qualifier that most people miss.\
He doesn't say the world bends for anyone with a wish or a hope. He specifically says it reconfigures for those who pursue what they want "with maximum energy and drive and passion."\
This isn't about magical thinking. It's about applied force.\
Reality has inertia. It resists change. But that resistance isn't infinite – it's just enough to filter out the uncommitted.\
This filtering mechanism is actually a feature, not a bug. It ensures that the world only reconfigures around those who care enough to push through initial resistance.\
When Jan Koum was building WhatsApp, he was rejected by Facebook for a job. Five years later, Facebook acquired his company for $19 billion.\
The difference wasn't luck. It was persistence applied to a clear vision.\
The world tests your commitment before it yields. It asks: How badly do you want this? What are you willing to sacrifice? How long can you persist when results aren't immediate?\
Your answers to these questions determine whether reality will reconfigure around you or remain stubbornly fixed.\
Look at your current projects. Where are you applying casual effort and expecting significant results? Where have you backed off at the first sign of resistance?\
This isn't about judgment. It's about clarity. The path you're on right now is giving you exactly the results your current energy level deserves.The Paradox of ResistanceHere's something counterintuitive about how reality bends: Resistance isn't evidence that you're going in the wrong direction. Often, it's confirmation you're pushing on something worth changing.\
Think about it. If what you're attempting would make no meaningful difference, the world wouldn't bother to resist. Systems only defend themselves against genuine threats to the status quo.\
The pushback you're experiencing might be the strongest validation that you're onto something significant.\
I was struck by this when studying Richard Branson's early days building Virgin Atlantic. Every established airline and industry expert told him he would fail. Regulations were designed to keep newcomers out. Existing players actively worked to block his entry.\
This wasn't just bad luck. It was the system protecting itself.\
Had Branson interpreted this resistance as a sign he was on the wrong path, Virgin Atlantic would never have existed.\
What resistance are you facing right now that you've misinterpreted as a sign to retreat rather than advance?\
The obstacles in your path often aren't warnings. They're filters—separating those who want change from those who demand it.Most people never experience how malleable the world can be because they've internalized a fixed view of reality.\
This mental model creates a self-fulfilling prophecy:You believe change is extremely difficultThis belief reduces your effort and expectationsReduced effort leads to minimal resultsMinimal results confirm your original beliefThe cycle reinforces itself\
The highest price you pay for seeing the world as fixed isn't the opportunities you miss – it's the person you never become.\
When you believe fundamental change is nearly impossible, you naturally dial back your ambitions. You "be realistic." You set "achievable goals." You focus on small improvements rather than a big vision.\
This approach guarantees you'll never discover what's actually possible.\
The alternative isn't delusion. It's calculated boldness – testing assumptions about what can be changed rather than accepting them as fixed truths.3If the world is truly malleable, is there a formula for bending it to your vision?\
Based on studying those who've successfully reshaped reality, a pattern emerges:Vague intentions produce vague results. The world doesn't bend for fuzzy thinking.\
Those who successfully change reality can clearly state exactly what they want. Not just the outcome, but the reasoning, the values, and the non-negotiables.\
This clarity focuses their energy. Rather than splitting effort across many targets, they concentrate on specific points that matter.The world pushes back against anyone trying to change it. This resistance filters out the casually interested from the truly committed.\
Those who successfully reshape reality maintain their conviction despite setbacks, skepticism, and slow progress.\
This isn't blind stubbornness. It's a belief based on insight – seeing possibilities others miss because you've thought more deeply about the problem.3. Disproportionate ActionThe degree to which reality bends correlates directly with the amount of force applied.\
Those who reshape their world don't just work hard – they work with an intensity that makes others uncomfortable. They take action at a pace and scale that seems excessive to outside observers.\
This doesn't mean burnout or hustle culture. It means focused effort on what actually matters, not spreading yourself thin across a hundred small tasks.Reality doesn't bend equally in all directions. It has weak spots – places where less force can create bigger change.\
Those who successfully reshape their world develop a sense for these opportunities. They position themselves where new trends, unmet needs, and their unique skills overlap.\
This lets them create impact far beyond their direct effort.No one bends reality entirely alone. Even the most determined individual has limits.\
Those who successfully reshape their world inspire others to join them. Their clarity, conviction, and action attract allies, resources, and opportunities.\
This turns personal force into team momentum.The Decision That Changes EverythingThe world has always been malleable to those willing to test its flexibility.\
From the Wright brothers proving flight was possible to Katherine Johnson calculating the mathematics that put humans on the moon. \
From Steve Jobs creating the smartphone to Greta Thunberg mobilizing millions for climate action.\
The people who reshape reality aren't fundamentally different from you. They've simply made a different decision about what's possible and what's worth pursuing with maximum energy.\
This decision is available to you right now.\
You can choose to see barriers as fixed or flexible. You can choose to accept conditions or challenge them. You can choose to work within existing frameworks or create new ones.\
Your perception of what's changeable directly determines what you can change.\
The greatest revolution isn't external but internal – the moment you realize that many of the limitations you've accepted exist only because everyone agrees they exist.The Malleable Future Waiting For YouSo, where should you apply this understanding that the world is more flexible than it appears?\
Start with the constraints you've internalized as fixed:"The market is too crowded for new entrants.""I don't have the right background or connections.""This problem is too complex to solve quickly.""That's just how this industry works."\
Each of these beliefs deserves scrutiny. Not blind rejection, but careful examination. Is this truly an immovable reality, or simply a collective assumption no one has sufficiently challenged?\
Then ask yourself: What would I pursue if I truly believed Andreessen's observation that the world would reconfigure around my vision and energy?\
Not as a hypothetical exercise, but as a genuine question about what matters enough to warrant your maximum drive and passion.\
The answer might scare you. It should. Anything worth applying your full force toward should feel somewhat intimidating.\
But remember – the world is far more malleable than most people ever discover. The barriers that seem solid often dissolve when pushed against with enough determination.Your Next Step (The Only One That Matters)Theory without action is just entertainment.\
So, here's your immediate next step:\
Identify one "immovable" constraint in your business or life that you've been accepting without question. Just one.\
Tomorrow, take a specific action that assumes this constraint is flexible. It doesn't have to be dramatic – just a meaningful step that would make no sense if the limitation were truly fixed.\
Maybe it's reaching out to someone "unreachable." Perhaps it's setting a deadline that seems "impossible." Or proposing a solution others would call "unrealistic."\
This single action won't reshape your entire reality. But it will start training the most important muscle you have – your ability to test rather than accept the boundaries others take for granted.\
As Mark Andreessen reminds us, reality will reconfigure itself around you "much more quickly and easily than you would think."\
The only question is whether you'll test this truth or continue living as if the world is fixed.\
The choice is yours. And it changes everything.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Famed AI researcher launches controversial startup to replace all human workers everywhere</title><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/04/19/famed-ai-researcher-launches-controversial-startup-to-replace-all-human-workers-everywhere/</link><author>Julie Bort</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 16:09:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Every now and then, a Silicon Valley startup launches with such an “absurdly” described mission that it’s difficult to discern if the startup is for real or just satire. Such is the case with Mechanize, a startup whose founder – and the non-profit AI research organization he founded called Epoch – is being skewered on […]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The HackerNoon Newsletter: Where Were You When the World Shut Down? I Was on BreachForums. (4/19/2025)</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/4-19-2025-newsletter?source=rss</link><author>Noonification</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 16:03:50 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[🪐 What’s happening in tech today, April 19, 2025?By @blackheart [ 6 Min read ] It was just another scroll through the usual: freshly dumped data, stolen credentials, drama between low-tier skids and ego-filled “veterans,” and whispers of b Read More.🧑‍💻 What happened in your world this week?We hope you enjoy this worth of free reading material. Feel free to forward this email to a nerdy friend who'll love you for it.See you on Planet Internet! With love, 
 The HackerNoon Team ✌️]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Where Were You When the World Shut Down? I Was on BreachForums.</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/where-were-you-when-the-world-shut-down-i-was-on-breachforums?source=rss</link><author>blackheart</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The day BreachForums went down, I was logged in.It was just another scroll through the usual: freshly dumped data, stolen credentials, drama between low-tier skids and ego-filled “veterans,” and whispers of big leaks coming soon. The forum had become a weird digital blend of marketplace, flex zone, and intelligence source. But underneath all the posturing, it was a pulse—one you learned to feel when you spent enough time watching the flow of stolen data from breach to sale. And then… silence.No splashy deface. No drawn-out farewell post. No FBI seizure page. At least not now anyway.This wasn’t the first time I experienced a BreachForums seizure. In the world of dark web research, I am in the “National Guard” of website search and seizures. It comes with the job description. All you need to do is follow a few simple rules, don’t be stupid, and you will be fine if a seizure happens. Speaking of seizures, I need to first tell you what BreachForums is and what it isn’t. Strap in, grab your favorite drink and get ready to hear some wild sh*t.Instead of the red pill, I took the sketchy-looking blue one.What was BreachForums? I am glad you asked, you curious little monkey you. BreachForums, sometimes referred to as Breached, is an English-language black hat–hacking crime forum. The website acted as an alternative and successor to RaidForums following its shutdown and seizure in 2022. Like its predecessor, BreachForums allows for the discussion of various hacking topics and distributed data breaches, pornography, hacking tools, and various other services.On March 21, 2023, BreachForums was shut down following the arrest of the forum's owner, Conor Brian Fitzpatrick. The forum was later reopened under the ownership of the hacking group ShinyHunters and the previous BreachForums administrator "Baphomet". Fitzpatrick was later sentenced to 20 years’ supervised release. The site was again shut down and the domain seized on May 15, 2024, though the domain was back under the owner's control just hours later.Something else that is suspicious is that BreachForums, along with other dark web forums, uses DDoS-Guard or Cloudflare for its web hosting services. You don’t believe me? Say hello to my little friend.I know it’s not impressive to find DNS records, but doesn’t it make you question how legitimate businesses protect websites like BreachForums, Doxbin, etc.? But that is for another article I am writing. Keep in mind, this wasn’t the first seizure of BreachForums and will not be the last.On June 23, 2023, three months after shutting down, the clearnet domains for BreachForums were seized by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Office of Inspector General, and the Department of Justice in accordance with a seizure warrant issued by the U.S. District Court for Eastern Virginia.Second seizure? Once wasn’t good enough?On May 15, 2024, the FBI seized the most recent BreachForums clearnet site along with its onion site and the associated Telegram. The seizure followed a significant data leak involving Europol's portal. The forum briefly displayed an FBI seizure notice, highlighting cooperation with international partners. The FBI is examining the forum's backend data, which may lead to identifying members and advancing investigations. The forum administrator, Baphomet, was arrested according to ShinyHunters. The site came back online on May 29, 2024.What could you find on BreachForums?To a dark web researcher, BreachForums was a melting pot of information on stolen data. You could literally watch the “Shout box” as threat actors discuss current or future data breaches. Having said that, it was one of the best places to go if you were looking for stolen data. Items such as:Data breaches were not the only items that were for sale or on display. If you were someone who wanted to disappear or gain initial access to a company, it was the place to go. All items were either for sale on Escrow, or you can purchase with credits from the forum. The one thing that BreachForums was good at was variety.Even though BreachFrorums was successful in being able to stay operational through all the seizures, it did have a lot of issues, but from within itself. Its own users and staff.The kids are not alright.You would think in the criminal underground of ill repute, it would be a free-for-all with no rules. You would be wrong. You would also think that a group of criminals who all have one thing in common would get along. You would also be wrong. Being a member of BreachForums is a lot like having an older brother or being in a fraternity. It’s messy, annoying, and like seeing your favorite Disney character in real life….disappointing.Paranoia was the main flavor when it came to BreachFroums. You might have well been a “Fed” because you would be accused of it more time than anything. Rightfully so because the rumor was, the feds were running the website after the first or second take down. Talk about pressure. Yet knowing this, the criminals were still active on the forum and selling stolen data like the very first “Thigh master”.It would also not be outlandish to see outrageous claims in the forums. I can’t count how many times I would see things that I didn’t believe, and coming from someone on a shady forum, it should be taken lightly. From a supposed DNC server attack to continued back-and-forth banter was the set tone most days on the forum.There was also the part when a criminal would brag about how they breached a company. I always knew they were talkative, but not at this level. Can you imagine watching someone tell you how they committed a crime with no strings attached? It would be a good time to wear your brown pants.Catching smoke with your hands.Since the forum’s takedown, there have been riddles in the dark and chatter about the arrest of IntelBroker. For those of you who don’t know, IntelBroker was one of the key players of the breach forum. If the rumors are true, it would be a huge win for the Justice Department. If it is not true, it will be embarrassing because this is the third takedown without anyone being arrested as IntelBroker.What do I know about IntelBroker? Not much. I never met him and only spoke to him once on the forum. It was for a ban appeal over “Leeching,”…which is exactly what I was doing anyway. That is all. He is someone who makes me wish I had multiple middle fingers. He was the first cybercriminal I have been following in hopes of helping bring to justice. I know I don’t know more than the FBI, but I have to help. Here is what I know so far:It’s not enough to help anyone, but that is how dark web research works. It’s a lot like fishing. You go out in hopes of catching something great, but sometimes, it doesn’t always go to plan. At least you show up, right?Now, there’s just fragmentation. Scattered chatter across platforms. More noise, less signal. The takedown didn’t kill the trade—it just pushed it into darker, quieter corners of the web. So, where was I when the world shut down? I was on BreachForums. Watching a chapter of internet history collapse in real time. Watching a torch fall—but knowing someone else would pick it up. Because in the world of breaches, nothing truly disappears. It just moves. Evolves. Hides better. And I’ll be there. Watching. Waiting. Writing.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Evaluating TnT-LLM: Automatic, Human, and LLM-Based Assessment</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/evaluating-tnt-llm-automatic-human-and-llm-based-assessment?source=rss</link><author>Language Models (dot tech)</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Due to the unsupervised nature of the problem we study and the lack of a benchmark standard, performing quantitative evaluation on end-to-end taxonomy generation and text classification can be challenging. We therefore design a suite of strategies to evaluate . Our evaluation strategies may be categorized into three buckets, depending on the type and source of the evaluation criteria. The three categories are as follows:\
• Deterministic automatic evaluation: This type of approach is scalable and consistent, but requires well-defined, gold standard rules and annotations. It is less applicable for evaluating the abstract aspects studied in this paper, such as the quality and usefulness of a label taxonomy.\
 These approaches are useful for evaluating the abstract aspects that the automatic evaluations cannot address. However, they are also time-consuming, expensive, and may encounter data privacy and compliance constraints.\
 Here, LLMs are used to perform the same or similar tasks as human evaluators. This type of evaluation is more scalable and cost-effective than human evaluation, albeit potentially subject to biases and errors if not applied properly. We therefore aim to combine and validate LLM-based evaluation with human evaluation metrics on small corpora so that we can extrapolate conclusions with sufficient statistical power.4.1 Phase 1 Evaluation StrategiesFollowing prior studies [23, 30], we evaluate a label taxonomy on three criteria: Coverage, accuracy, and relevance to the use-case instruction. Note that we require implementing the native primary label assignment to apply these metrics. For clustering-based methods, this is instantiated through the clustering algorithm. For  this is done by a label assignment prompt as described in Section 3.2. We also note that the label accuracy and use-case relevance metrics discussed here are applicable to both  and  raters.\
 This metric measures the comprehensiveness of the generated label taxonomy for the corpus. Conventional text clustering approaches (e.g., embedding-based k-means) often achieve 100% coverage by design. In our LLM-based taxonomy generation pipeline, we add an ‘Other’ or ‘Undefined’ category in the label assignment prompt by design and measure the proportion of data points assigned to this category. The lower this proportion, the higher the taxonomy coverage.\
 This metric quantifies how well the assigned label reflects the text data point, relative to other labels in the same taxonomy. Analogous to mixture model clustering, the primary label should be the most probable one given the text. We assume human and LLM raters can assess the label fit by its name and description. We treat accuracy as a pairwise comparison task: for each text, we obtain the primary label and a random negative label from the same taxonomy, and ask a rater to choose the more accurate label based on their names and descriptions.[1] If the rater correctly identifies the positive label, we consider it as a "Hit" and report the average hit rate as the label accuracy metric. We do not explicitly evaluate the overlap across category labels and rather expect it to be implicitly reflected in the pairwise label accuracy metric.\
Relevance to Use-case Instruction. This metric measures how relevant the generated label taxonomy is to the use-case instruction. For example, “Content Creation” is relevant to an instruction to “understand user intent in a conversation”, while “History and Culture” is not. We operationalize this as a binary rating task: for each instance, we provide its primary label name and description to a human or LLM rater, and ask them to decide if the label is relevant to the given use-case instruction or not. Note that we instruct the rater to use the presented instance as the context, and rate the relevance conditioned on the label’s ability to accurately describe some aspect of the text input. The goal of this metric is not to evaluate the label accuracy, but rather to rule out the randomness introduced by taxonomies that are seemingly relevant to the use-case instruction, but irrelevant to the corpus sample – and therefore useless for downstream applications.[1] Raters are also offered a "None" option besides the pair, but are instructed to minimize the use of it.(1) Mengting Wan, Microsoft Corporation and Microsoft Corporation;(2) Tara Safavi (Corresponding authors), Microsoft Corporation;(3) Sujay Kumar Jauhar, Microsoft Corporation;(4) Yujin Kim, Microsoft Corporation;(5) Scott Counts, Microsoft Corporation;(6) Jennifer Neville, Microsoft Corporation;(7) Siddharth Suri, Microsoft Corporation;(8) Chirag Shah, University of Washington and Work done while working at Microsoft;(9) Ryen W. White, Microsoft Corporation;(10) Longqi Yang, Microsoft Corporation;(11) Reid Andersen, Microsoft Corporation;(12) Georg Buscher, Microsoft Corporation;(13) Dhruv Joshi, Microsoft Corporation;(14) Nagu Rangan, Microsoft Corporation.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>FFmpeg AV1 Vulkan Encoder Patch Posted</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FFmpeg-AV1-Vulkan-Encoder</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 15:33:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[While the FFmpeg multimedia library merged Vulkan Video encode support last year, it was initially limited to H.264 and H.265 formats. With a new patch posted for review this week, AV1 encode support using the Vulkan Video API is now underway...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>AI Agents Need To Come With An Emergency Button</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/ai-agents-need-to-come-with-an-emergency-button?source=rss</link><author>Neer Varshney</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 15:30:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Some of you may remember a newsletter I sent out a month ago, saying how a startup in China has released a new AI agent that is getting raving reviews.\
Following that, the startup Monica gave me early access to Manus AI with plenty of free credits to play around with the AI agent.\
Now that I have first-hand experience, I can confirm, it really ups the game on the AI front.Its ability to define the checklist needed to take an objective to completion and perform one task after another to get there is breathtaking.\
So, the one big task I chose to perform with Manus AI was to high-level design a game where the player would live through Indian history by trying to build and defend cities.\
Manus had clear instructions — we would brainstorm to come up with the perfect gameplay, but then only code a minimally viable game.Instead, it tried to achieve the “objective” anyhow within a single execution — and we ended up with this landing page for the game it deployed on its own, rather than having an MVP of a gameplay.\
If you think, I could just ask it to refine and go back to what we were trying to do, uh oh, bad luck, we are all out of credits.\
So, I ended up blowing all of those fancy free credits Monica gave me, just so we could all learn this valuable lesson. We need a red button on AI.\
AI agents are all the rage. And I am very, very optimistic about them as somebody who is building multiple AI agents of my own.\
But, we need to acknowledge the negative side.\
That AI agents, even top-of-the-line ones, are not yet ready to perform complex tasks autonomously.\
This needs to be on the label.\
Because users can’t be expected to have blown up 100s (or even 1000s) of dollars before realizing this.\
This isn’t just a case with Manus AI, though. This is a similar problem I face from time to time with Cursor — my go-to AI agent for coding.\
Sometimes, it introduces unnecessary components or even new libraries, entirely different from what you are currently using, into your code.\
Take your eyes off what the agent is doing for a second, and you may just end up with a disaster of epic proportions.\
Now, to be fair, Cursor does have a “Reject All” button. But this only works if you review the code immediately.Many times, you may notice the issue after doing some more work on the code, and then a git rollback remains the only option.\
This isn’t to dissuade you from trying out AI agents (they really are the future), but just something I needed to say out loud, especially since I have contributed to the hype around them.\
AI agents are currently already a viable option to end-to-end code and deploy things like landing pages, classic games, and in-depth research on any given topic.\
I just want that button within reach on my desk that, when hit, just stops whatever task the AI is executing at a time, and just rolls the whole thing back.\
This post is an excerpt from the 12th edition of the Artificially Boosted newsletter.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Read what Mark Zuckerberg and Facebook execs said about Instagram before buying it</title><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/04/19/read-what-mark-zuckerberg-and-facebook-execs-said-about-instagram-before-buying-it/</link><author>Sarah Perez, Aisha Malik, Lauren Forristal</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The first week of the Meta antitrust trial brought new revelations about how the company formerly known as Facebook approached the competitive threat posed by Instagram in the early 2010s. The U.S. government is accusing Meta of violating competition laws by acquiring companies like Instagram and WhatsApp that threatened the Facebook monopoly. If lawyers for […]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Solar-Powered Tech Transforms Remote Learning</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/educational-tech-remote-locations</link><author>Maurizio Arseni</author><category>tech</category><enclosure url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy81OTk0OTIyNC9vcmlnaW4uanBnIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTc2NTgwNTQ4NX0.fT8Yqnefw96Z0Y8CHEIjjgv9A26L6djcLOc-t0cGHDY/image.jpg?width=600" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/">IEEE Spectrum</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Swiss startup brings offline-first e-learning to world’s remote locations]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>GCC 16 Adding Support For GNU/Hurd On RISC-V Targets</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-16-RISC-V-GNU-Hurd-Targets</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 10:47:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[GNU/Hurd has long struggled with hardware support and is still working on its x86_64 support while having a host of various hardware limitations but it also appears they are eager to explore Hurd on RISC-V platforms...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Google Engineers Exploring Distributed ThinLTO Builds Of The Linux Kernel</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Distributed-ThinkLTO-Linux-Kern</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 10:28:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Engineers from Google are proposing that distributed ThinLTO build support be introduced for LLVM/Clang when compiling the Linux kernel. The distributed ThinLTO mode for link-time optimizations can lead to quicker build times than the current in-process ThinLTO mode while also being more convenient and work with kernel live-patching solutions...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>KDE Preps More Wayland Improvements, Addresses Another Possible KWin Crash</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-Mid-April-2025</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 10:11:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[KDE developers continue to be very busy working toward the Plasma 6.4 desktop release and making other enhancements throughout this open-source desktop...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The TechBeat: INSANE One-click MCP AI Agent Hits the Market (4/19/2025)</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/4-19-2025-techbeat?source=rss</link><author>Techbeat</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 06:10:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[By @zbruceli [ 5 Min read ] 
 Google A2A - a first look at another agent-agent protocol and compared to Anthropic’s MCP. Read More.By @asitsahoo [ 3 Min read ] 
 Discover how Claude Desktop with MCP tools eliminated digital fragmentation, enabling deeper product thinking and transforming weeks of work into hours. Read More.By @ishanpandey [ 2 Min read ] 
 A new partnership between Addressable and Sevio will enable programmatic display ads on major crypto platforms, making web3 target more efficient.  Read More.By @vladimirgorbunov [ 3 Min read ] 
 In 2025, gold and Bitcoin rise as trust in global finance crumbles. Are they safe havens—or signals of a system in collapse? Read More.By @jonstojanjournalist [ 4 Min read ] 
 Carl “Moon” Runefelt’s January 2025 crash prediction is coming true. As markets tumble, his warning about rate cuts and Bitcoin gains new relevance. Read More.By @muhammdusman [ 8 Min read ] 
 So you want to become better than 99% of programmers. But you are doing the exact same things that 99% of programmers are already doing. Read More.By @hristow [ 2 Min read ] 
 A new way to learn SQL: solve crimes using real SQL queries. Build database logic fast with interactive storytelling and gamified practice. Read More.By @benidev [ 4 Min read ] 
 HackerNoon adds Tailwind CSS to the front end experience of its native publishing platform.  Read More.By @ishanpandey [ 4 Min read ] 
 Fuse partners with Check Point to introduce the first real-time blockchain firewall, aiming to shift from detection to threat prevention. Read More.By @David [ 4 Min read ] 
 Avi Schiffmann on HackerNoon: It’s mostly millenials+ that try & fuck their robots. It’s mostly GenZ & younger that are able to view AI as a platonic companion. Read More.By @proflead [ 5 Min read ] 
 Firebase Studio is a free, browser-based tool from Google that allows you to build full-stack web apps with AI assistance. Read More.By @thisweekinaieng [ 8 Min read ] 
 Genspark AI has emerged as a formidable new player in the AI agent space, positioning itself as a comprehensive super agent. Read More.By @marcushaldd [ 5 Min read ] 
 Terraforming Mars in the near future is impossible, but preparatory steps can be taken, such as moon bases, Skyhook, Synthetic Biology, ISRU, and nuclear fuel. Read More.By @escholar [ 5 Min read ] 
 Explains how blockchains use logs, virtual machines, and functional transactions to manage state, design tradeoffs, and finality. Read More.By @sshshln [ 23 Min read ] 
 A philosophical journey through Ethereum—exploring code, consensus, and decentralization as metaphysical, ethical, and aesthetic forces.  Read More.By @fatman [ 3 Min read ] 
 A step-by-step walkthrough for configuring your PC running Simhub work support Gran Turismo 7 on the PS5 Read More.By @escholar [ 3 Min read ] 
 How blockchain defines finality—from logging transactions to securing state changes and recovering from system-wide failures. Read More.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Markup Wants to Investigate Companies Like Axon That Expand Their Reach With Public Dollars</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/the-markup-wants-to-investigate-companies-like-axon-that-expand-their-reach-with-public-dollars?source=rss</link><author>The Markup</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 01:07:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hackernoon.com/">Tech - HackerNoon</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Hello World is a weekly newsletter—delivered every Saturday morning—that goes deep into our original reporting and the questions we put to big thinkers in the field. Browse the archive here.\
What’s up, world? 🤓 I’m Ese Olumhense, one of the latest hires at The Markup. I’ll be reporting on government here: the ways federal, state, and local agencies are finding, vetting, and using new technologies. I’m fascinated by the ways these products are packaged and marketed to our leaders—and by the private companies making fortunes from public dollars.\
These interests meet in my first story for The Markup: a juicy look at Axon’s seemingly ongoing plans to develop Taser-equipped drones as a response to mass shootings. The company, which makes both Taser devices and body-worn cameras, boasts that its products are already used by more than 95 percent of state and local law enforcement agencies in the United States. Its CEO has proposed embedding weaponized drones in school classrooms, armed with surveillance cameras and microphones, to be used to incapacitate active shooters. (Yes, you read that right.)\
When Axon made this surprising announcement last year, three quarters of its ethics board—a panel of academics, attorneys, activists, and former law enforcement officials—resigned in protest, saying they had “lost faith in the company’s ability to be a responsible partner.” The explosive exodus halted the weaponized drone development program, Axon’s CEO said.\
But it didn’t kill it, folks, as our latest shows. Axon still appears to be moving forward with its armed drone plan. In July, the company acquired Sky-Hero, a company based in Belgium that manufactures drones and unmanned ground vehicles. Sky-Hero has already developed so-called “distraction” technology for some of its drones and rovers that produces the same sound pressure levels as a semiautomatic rifle, it said in the description of a YouTube video showing off the tech, acting as a “true non-lethal flashbang.”\
As you can read in the piece, I tracked down members of the former ethics advisory board to learn more about the implications of weaponizing drones. (Spoiler alert: there are M A N Y, including the obvious risks of physical harm and potential misuse.) I also spent lots of time reading through Axon statements, investor reports, patent documents, and even the book “The End of Killing,” written by Axon CEO Rick Smith.\
Ultimately, I also asked Axon how soon we could see Taser-equipped drones on the market. They still haven’t gotten back to me.\
A little bit more about me, since you’ve read this far: I am obsessed with creative approaches to investigative storytelling. Before I got to The Markup, for example, I used body-cam footage from companies like Axon to add dimension to my reporting on voting crimes investigations. Using those images and sound, obtained through public records requests, I was able to illustrate just how deeply these investigations stirred fear and chilled voters. \
Now, I’m looking at government and technology, and I would love your help. What are journalists missing here? I’m interested in how technology is pitched as a solution for issues not only in policing and our criminal legal system, but in schools, government workplaces, and emergency management capacities. I’d also love to hear more about how tech is changing public transportation, public housing, and our environment and infrastructure.\
There is near-unlimited latitude here: Almost all of us deal with government in some way, and corporations and their products seem to have an increasing say in how we’re governed. I recently had a conversation with Matthew Guariglia, a senior policy analyst at the Electronic Frontier Foundation, about how this affects policing, and he blew me away with the following: “Critical decisions about public safety are being decided by marketing departments.” !!!!!!!!\
I’m looking forward to reporting on tech in our collective interest. Please reach me if you have tips, thoughts, or leads that might be helpful. (Or if you’re a government employee and you want to say hello ☺️.) I’m at ese@themarkup.org, on Signal or Whatsapp at (917) 407-0635, and you can send me some snail mail at The Markup, P.O. Box 1103, New York., NY 10159.Copy Editing and Production]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Linux 6.15-rc3 To Bring AMD Zen 5 Microcode Protection, Intel Bartlett Lake ID Addition</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.15-rc3-x86-Fixes</link><author>Michael Larabel</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:23:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.phoronix.com/">Phoronix</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Merged today ahead of the Linux 6.15-rc3 kernel test release on Sunday were the set of "x86 fixes" for the week. Of these x86 fixes are two notable changes in particular...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A comprehensive list of 2025 tech layoffs</title><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/04/18/tech-layoffs-2025-list/</link><author>Cody Corrall, Alyssa Stringer, Kate Park</author><category>tech</category><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:19:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A complete list of all the known layoffs in tech, from Big Tech to startups, broken down by month throughout 2024.]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>