<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Youtube</title><link>https://konrad.website/liveboat-github-runner/</link><description></description><item><title>Why China’s Ports Empire Has the US Worried</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NfiIXoWyOLI</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NfiIXoWyOLI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:00:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[China has invested more than $60 billion building ports around the world, from Tanzania and Australia to Nigeria and Peru, dwarfing similar investments by any other country. Dominating global trade infrastructure through ports, shipping, highways and rail is a central pillar of China’s Belt and Road Initiative. And it’s paying off, with a network of ports providing strategic advantage amid rising global trade tensions.

But this unparalleled influence is also sparking security concerns. Some 14 ports with Chinese majority ownership have been identified as having potential military uses, a fact that has the rest of the world, and particularly the US, concerned. 

00:00 Introduction
01:29 China’s ports network
03:38 Ownership model
04:21 Chancay port
06:15 Security concerns
08:00 Trade implications

#China #Ports #XiJinping #Trump #TradeWar #Military


--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Christmas with The Tabernacle Choir feat. Ruthie Ann Miles &amp; Dennis Haysbert | Full Concert | PBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=obZDWSUxwVo</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/obZDWSUxwVo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:01:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Official site: https://to.pbs.org/48nFZwH | #TabernacleChoirPBS
Experience the magic of the season with Hope of the Season: Christmas with The Tabernacle Choir. Tony Award–winner Ruthie Ann Miles joins The Tabernacle Choir and Orchestra at Temple Square for an unforgettable celebration of joy and hope. This spectacular holiday special brings together a 500-member cast — including The Tabernacle Choir and Orchestra at Temple Square, Bells at Temple Square, and the Gabriel Trumpet Ensemble — for a breathtaking musical experience.

Enjoy cherished carols and hymns performed by Miles alongside the world-renowned Choir, blending sacred and popular music into a universal message of peace. Adding depth to the program, acclaimed actor Dennis Haysbert narrates the original Christmas story from Luke. He also tells the remarkable true story of African philanthropist Dr. Charles Mulli, a man who rose from poverty in Kenya to become a successful businessman, then gave it all up to rescue thousands of abandoned children. This moving program captures the true spirit of Christmas — a celebration for all ages that will fill your heart with hope and joy.

To listen to the music, watch behind the scenes videos, view slideshows and more, visit https://to.pbs.org/48nFZwH 

Hope of the Season: Christmas with the Tabernacle Choir | Full Concert

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS App: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

CHAPTERS  
00:00 O Come, O Come, Emmanuel
03:46 'Twas Midnight in the Stable
09:20 Hark! The Herald Angels Sing
11:49 Ruthie Ann Miles and O Little Town of Bethlehem
18:03 Welcome Christmas Morning!
20:33 Gamelan
24:31 Joy To the World
27:52 Spirit of the Season, from The Polar Express
35:06 Alleluia, Amen (Air in G)
37:40 Alleluia, from Psalm 150
41:16 Hallelujah, from Messiah
46:00 When You Hear the Pipe and Drum (Patapan)
49:33 A Season for Shepherds: The True Story of Dr. Charles Mulli
1:11:57 What Shall We Give?
1:16:20 The Christmas Story: Luke 2
1:19:14 Angels from the Realms of Glory

#TabernacleChoir #ChristmasSongs #holidaymusic 

Hope of the Season: Christmas with The Tabernacle Choir, featuring Ruthie Ann Miles and Dennis Haysbert, was made possible in part by Ronald C. & Kaye Gunnel, Charles & Janet Stoddard, and David B. and Jolynn Davies. The Tabernacle Choir provides artistic expressions of faith from The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. This program is co-presented by GBH Boston and BYUtv.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Happy Thanksgiving. Here’s a little reel I made today about Jasper Johns’ “Flag” from 1954-55.</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/y4raWGPCWpk</link><author>Great Art Explained</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/y4raWGPCWpk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 22:18:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCePDFpCr78_qmVtpoB1Axaw">Great Art Explained</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Napoleon vs Metternich: The Diplomatic Duel That Decided The Fate Of Europe</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w2XyFkR08qw</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/w2XyFkR08qw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 22:01:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[On June 26, 1813, two powerful men gathered in Dresden to discuss the future of war and peace in Europe. Napoleon Bonaparte met with diplomat Metternich, known as Austria’s “strong man” and the Emperor’s closest confidant. This fateful showdown between two of the most powerful men of this time period marked the beginning of the end for Napoleon. By rejecting Metternich’s proposal, Napoleon missed an opportunity to build the foundations of a future Europe. In this documentary, join us as we are guided by international historians to reconstruct this key chapter of European history and trace the steps of Napoleon's downfall.

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How to Tell What’s Real Online</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o4I_hOz_MLw</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/o4I_hOz_MLw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 20:13:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In a world overflowing with opinions, clips, conspiracies, and AI-generated answers, how do you know what’s actually true? Neil deGrasse Tyson breaks down his personal checklist for navigating the modern information landscape—yellow flags, red flags, and why evidence-based thinking matters more than ever. From scientific claims and podcasts to clipped videos and industry commentary, Neil shows you how to separate signal from noise and think like a scientist in the digital age.

How do you tell what’s real? Neil deGrasse Tyson breaks down how to tell which sources are trustworthy and which yellow flags to look out for. In an age of so much information, how do you parse what’s real and what’s misinformation?

00:00 - What to Trust
00:45 - AI for Research
01:50 - The Influence of Industry
04:15 - Telling You How You Should Feel
5:34 - Content Lifted From Its Source
7:00 - Further Research
9:00 - Conspiracy Theories
10:21 - Is “Mainstream” a Bad Word? 
11:18 - Indicting Demographics
13:15 - Laws of Physics, Inventions, & Aliens

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We Explored the Hidden Medieval City of London | Full Series</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jEDSfIp8axc</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/jEDSfIp8axc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 19:01:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">History Hit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[If you were asked to picture London during the Middle Ages, you might think of The White Tower, Westminster Abbey or Guildhall - some of the capital’s most famous landmarks. But scratch beneath the surface and you’ll find there are lots more clues to this medieval metropolis.

In this series London tour guide Katie Wignall seeks out the London of the Middle Ages - a city of narrow streets and soaring spires, almost completely destroyed by the Great Fire of 1666… and the Blitz during the Second World War. But despite the devastation and centuries of development, not all of that city is lost.

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world-renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.

Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ/join

#medievalcity #crusades #knightstemplar]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>X Ray Telescope Discovery</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/McaqhzY58XY</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/McaqhzY58XY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:30:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Stone Age or Bone Age</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/RCQ7J5Cv5ns</link><author>PBS Eons</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/RCQ7J5Cv5ns?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:15:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzR-rom72PHN9Zg7RML9EbA">PBS Eons</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[*****
PBS Member Stations rely on viewers like you. To support your local station, go to http://to.pbs.org/DonateEons
*****

Eons is a production of Complexly for PBS Digital Studios.

Super special thanks to the following Patreon patrons for helping make Eons possible:
Perseus Bluejay, Mary Sammartino , Hugo van den Hoek, Melodie Chen-Glasser, rene fuqua, John Hildebrandt, Irene Wood, Derek Helling, Casey Hague, Susan Freund, CalamityBangs, Brian Clubb, William Sunderland, Kerry Conneely, Mark Talbott-Williams, Nomi Alchin, Nicholas Arger, Josh L, Duane Westhoff, Yu Mei, A.B. Heckert, Lea Nisay, Beth K, Eric Younge, Hillary Ryde-Collins, Elyssa, Albert Folsom, Alex Hackman, Ruth Orr, Steve Hill, Jennifer Courtemanche, Steven Kern, Jason Rostoker, Lianne Lairmore, John H. Austin, Jr., Walter Ray-Dulany, Eric Franklin, John D Elias, Willie, Gizmo, Nquiztor, Annemiek Arkema, Wookiee Henderson, Randall George, SKS PHD, John Celio, Eric Edwards, Karen Farrell, raus , Aaditya Mehta, IAmHere, Collin Dutrow, Beth-Ann Cheney, Travis Bauer, Sarah Grunow-Mau, Deanna Hernandez, Christopher Samuel, AllPizzasArePersonal, lyric1981, Mary Tevington, Kevin Lacson, Dan Caffee, Nick Ryhajlo, Nathan Paskett, Stephanie Schlea, Jeff Graham, Betsy Radley

If you'd like to support the channel, head over to http://patreon.com/eons and pledge for some cool rewards!

Want to follow Eons elsewhere on the internet?
Facebook - https://www.facebook.com/eonsshow
Instagram - https://www.instagram.com/eonsshow/
Bluesky - https://bsky.app/profile/pbseons.bsky.social
#Eons

References:]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Benedict Arnold and The Battle of Quebec | The American Revolution | PBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=88LPNK6CJgk</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/88LPNK6CJgk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:00:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Official website: https://to.pbs.org/amrevpbs | #AmericanRevolutionPBS
Benedict Arnold leads his army north up the Kennebec River as part of the American invasion of Canada. His forces lose much of their provisions and face terrible winter weather, causing many to turn back. Benedict Arnold's force launches an assault on their target, Quebec City, on New Year's Eve that turns disastrous for the Patriots.

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

#americanhistory #revolutionarywar #history #ushistory #warhistory 

THE AMERICAN REVOLUTION | A Film By Ken Burns, Sarah Botstein and David Schmidt
An expansive look at the virtues and contradictions of the war and the birth of the United States of America, the film follows dozens of figures from a wide variety of backgrounds. Through their individual stories, viewers experience the war through the memories of the men and women who experienced it: the rank-and-file Continental soldiers and American militiamen (some of them teenagers), Patriot political and military leaders, British Army officers, American Loyalists, Native soldiers and civilians, enslaved and free African Americans, German soldiers in the British service, French and Spanish allies, and various civilians living in North America, Loyalist as well as Patriot, including many made refugees by the war.

The Revolution began a movement for people around the world to imagine new and better futures for themselves, their nations, and for humanity. It declared American independence with promises that we continue to strive for. The American Revolution opened the door to advance civil liberties and human rights, and it asked questions that we are still trying to answer today.

The film, narrated by Peter Coyote, includes the first-person voices of nearly 200 individual historic figures, read by a cast of actors, including Adam Arkin, Jeremiah Bitsui, Corbin Bleu, Kenneth Branagh, Josh Brolin, Bill Camp, Tantoo Cardinal, Josh Charles, Hugh Dancy, Claire Danes, Jeff Daniels, Keith David, Hope Davis, Marcus Davis-Orrom, Bruce Davison, Leon Dische Becker, Alden Ehrenreich, Craig Ferguson, Morgan Freeman, Christian Friedel, Paul Giamatti, Domhnall Gleeson, Amanda Gorman, Michael Greyeyes, Jonathan Groff, Charlotte Hacke, Tom Hanks, Ethan Hawke, Maya Hawke, Lucas Hedges, Josh Hutcherson, Samuel L. Jackson, Gene Jones, Michael Keaton, Joe Keery, Joel Kinnaman, Tracy Letts, Damian Lewis, Laura Linney, Josh Lucas, Michael Mando, Carolyn McCormick, Lindsay Mendez, Tobias Menzies, Joe Morton, Edward Norton, David Oyelowo, Mandy Patinkin, Wendell Pierce, Jon Proudstar, Matthew Rhys, LaTanya Richardson, Liev Schreiber, Chaske Spencer, Dan Stevens, Meryl Streep, and Yul Vazquez, among others.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Amazon: Who pays the price? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6r3x2t872Pc</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6r3x2t872Pc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:00:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Online retailer Amazon has been repeatedly criticized for its business practices. The US company puts pressure on retailers and exerts influence on pricing policies, thus fueling cut-throat competition.

Amazon attracts customers with low prices - but according to a former manager at the company, the reason for this is not what consumers might think. She claims that the company's aim is not to give customers fair deals but to put retailers and manufacturers under enormous pressure.

This investigative documentary reveals the questionable methods used by the company: suppliers are prevented from selling their products below the Amazon-listed price - whether that be online or in a physical store. Insiders say that this practice not only distorts competition, but also has direct consequences for customers in the form of price rises

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #amazon 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Greed or Inflation? Why We Pay More For Less</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GPcdighO0eU</link><author>ColdFusion</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GPcdighO0eU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:21:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC4QZ_LsYcvcq7qOsOhpAX4A">ColdFusion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Use code COLDFUSION at the link below to get an exclusive 60% off an annual Incogni plan: https://incogni.com/your-unique-code

Watch or listen to ColdFusion on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/1YEwCKoRz8fEDqheXB6UJ1


ColdFusion Music: 
https://www.youtube.com/@ColdFusionmusic
http://burnwater.bandcamp.com   

Get my book: 

http://bit.ly/NewThinkingbook 

ColdFusion Socials: 

https://discord.gg/coldfusion
https://facebook.com/ColdFusionTV 
https://twitter.com/ColdFusion_TV 
https://instagram.com/coldfusiontv

Created by: Dagogo Altraide
Producers: Tawsif Akkas, Dagogo Altraide]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>I turned my phone into a microscope</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/Bb0uDpvitoE</link><author>Veritasium</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Bb0uDpvitoE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:04:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA">Veritasium</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#Sponsored @madebygoogle A single drop of water is all it takes to turn the new Google #Pixel10Pro into a makeshift microscope.

Promotional code offer expires 12/05/2025 at 11:59p.m. PT; while supplies last. Must be redeemed on Google Store only. User must be signed-in to their Google Account and checkout with Google Pay profile, including a valid form of payment. Limit 1 per customer.Available only to US residents, aged 18 years or older, with US shipping addresses. Google Pay profile must be registered in the US and promotional code can only be used in the US.To redeem, visit store.google.com, add the desired item to the cart, then enter promotional code during checkout for an instant discount on your purchase on one of four eligible items: Pixel 10 (unlocked), Pixel 10 Pro (unlocked), Pixel 10 Pro XL (unlocked), Pixel 10 Pro Fold (unlocked). Promotional code is for one-time use only with no residual balance; is not transferable; and is not valid for cash or cash equivalent. May be combined with other offers on Google Store. Void where prohibited. Terms of sale and additional Promotional code terms apply: https://store.google.com/terms/google_store_promo_codes]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Will Fungi Infect Us All?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/omNvSHfIv7s</link><author>Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/omNvSHfIv7s?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:01:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q">Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Who watched or played The Last of Us? Hopefully, with continuous research, we can make sure those scenarios stay on the screen, far away from the reality. 

#kurzgesagt
#inanutshell #kurzgesagt_inanutshell #learnwithshorts #science #lastofus #fungi 

Sources & further reading: 
https://sites.google.com/view/kgs-tiktok-sources

Follow us for more sciencey content! 🦆

OUR CHANNELS
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
German:        https://kgs.link/youtubeDE
Spanish:        https://kgs.link/youtubeES
French:          https://kgs.link/youtubeFR
Portuguese:  https://kgs.link/youtubePT
Arabic:           https://kgs.link/youtubeAR
Hindi:             https://kgs.link/youtubeHI
Japanese:     https://kgs.link/youtubeJA
Korean:          https://kgs.link/youtubeKO


HOW CAN YOU SUPPORT US?
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
This is how we make our living and it would be a pleasure if you support us!

Get Products designed with ❤ https://shop.kgs.link/shorts
Become a Part of kurzgesagt by joining the Patreon Bird Army 🐧  https://kgs.link/patreon  


DISCUSSIONS & SOCIAL MEDIA
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Instagram:     https://kgs.link/instagram
TikTok:           https://kgs.link/tiktok
Reddit:            https://kgs.link/reddit
Discord:          https://kgs.link/discord
Twitter:           https://kgs.link/twitter
Bluesky:          https://kgs.link/bluesky
Facebook:      https://kgs.link/facebook
Newsletter:    https://kgs.link/newsletter


OUR VOICE
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
The Kurzgesagt voice is from 
Steve Taylor:  https://kgs.link/youtube-voice


OUR MUSIC ♬♪
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
700+ minutes of Kurzgesagt Soundtracks by Epic Mountain:

Spotify:            https://kgs.link/music-spotify
Soundcloud:   https://kgs.link/music-soundcloud
Bandcamp:     https://kgs.link/music-bandcamp
Youtube:          https://kgs.link/music-youtube
Facebook:       https://kgs.link/music-facebook]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why has Ecuador become a “war zone”? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/BgI-TWLTkgA</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/BgI-TWLTkgA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:00:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Images of masked gunmen storming a TV station live on air in Ecuador in 2024 shocked the world. But how did this country, once considered one of Latin America’s most peaceful, became a “war zone”? 

Ecuador has become an attractive logistical hub for local and international cartels – due in part to its location between two of the world's largest cocaine producers, Colombia and Peru. 

Growing demand for cocaine in Europe, one of its main markets, is considered to be fuelling the surge in extreme violence seen in cities like Guayaquil.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #EcuadorCrisis #DrugTrafficking 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Modern Full-Stack Web Development with ASP.NET Core • Alexandre Malavasi &amp; Albert Tanure • GOTO 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B0hGGRkEotk</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/B0hGGRkEotk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:00:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for the GOTO Book Club. #GOTOcon #GOTObookclub
http://gotopia.tech/bookclub

Check out more here:
https://gotopia.tech/episodes/413

Alexandre Malavasi - CTO at Marelo & Author of “Modern Full-Stack Web Development with ASP.NET Core” @alexandremalavasi-software101 
Albert S. Tanure - Cross Solutions Architec at Microsoft & Author of "ASP.NET Core 9 Essentials" @CodeFC 

RESOURCES
Alexandre
https://x.com/alemalavasi
https://github.com/alexandremalavasi
https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexandremalavasi

Albert
https://x.com/alberttanure
https://github.com/tanure
https://www.linkedin.com/in/albert-tanure
https://www.codefc.io/en

Links
https://youtu.be/GqJfsDJuwCI
https://youtu.be/O91hJJ5KMLs
https://youtu.be/Mu9zKpGhX1Y
https://youtu.be/dK4Yb6-LxAk
https://youtu.be/n8ERFbkt_h8
https://youtu.be/BKaxtBSgueQ
https://youtu.be/PzEox3szeRc
https://youtu.be/HKS5sKsIkkc
https://youtu.be/VMmkHZ4wShA
https://youtu.be/7NAyn1DC420
https://youtu.be/Saaz6D1azlU
https://youtu.be/Zyz_2lELqG8
https://youtu.be/ESOaDiv3lXA
https://youtu.be/WKx9E3DRqXc

DESCRIPTION
Microsoft Cloud Solution Architect Albert Tanure interviews Microsoft MVP Alexandre Malavasi about his fourth book, "Modern Full-Stack Web Development with ASP.NET Core". The discussion explores the challenges of writing comprehensive technical books, the importance of foundational knowledge in full stack development, and how to integrate ASP.NET Core with modern JavaScript frameworks like React, Angular, and Vue.js.

Alexandre emphasizes that successful architecture decisions depend primarily on team expertise and the ability to facilitate change, rather than following trends.
The conversation also highlights the critical importance of looking beyond just coding - encompassing project planning, DevOps practices, monitoring, and continuous optimization - to truly bring value to customers and become well-rounded software engineers.

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
01:33 Covering the full-stack
07:22 Book structure & foundation concepts
13:13 Planning & structuring full-stack projects
21:09 Design patterns & avoiding over-engineering
24:35 DevOps mindset & beyond development
31:03 Outro

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Alexandre Malavasi • Modern Full-Stack Web Development with ASP.NET Core • https://amzn.to/4pvEXnY
Alexandre Malavasi • Implementing Design Patterns in C# 11 and .NET 7 • https://amzn.to/49Capwn
Alexandre Malavasi • Enterprise Applications with C# and .NET • https://amzn.to/4iiVidk
Alexandre Malavasi • Implementing Design Patterns in C# and .NET 5 • https://amzn.to/3JU5UD2
Albert Tanure • ASP.NET Core 9 Essentials • https://amzn.to/43bH73t

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#dotNET #ASPdotNET #ASPdotNETCore #ASPdotNET9 #ReactJS #VueJS #AngularJS #Programming #SoftwareArchitecture #DevOps #FullStack #DesignPatterns #Observability #ModernSWDevelopment #SoftwareEngineering #Programming #TodayInTech #AlexandreMalavasi #AlbertTanure #BookClub

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>England on the Brink of Civil War, 1642 (RA Winter Lecture)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4mDyRaCXqgs</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4mDyRaCXqgs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 03:38:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Royal Armouries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The year is 1642 and England is on the brink of Civil War. Discover the political crisis that plunged the country into conflict.

Speaker: Dr Jonathan Healey, Associate Professor in Social History, University of Oxford.

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Will the Voting Rights Act survive the Supreme Court’s ruling in Louisiana v. Callais? #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/LgJJb4ZBKeo</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LgJJb4ZBKeo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:07:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Voting Rights Act of 1965 transformed America, marking the end of the Jim Crow era and effectively banning racial discrimination in elections.

This video explains how, 60 years later, a redistricting case out of Louisiana called Louisiana v. Callais has the potential to upend the Voting Rights Act and political representation for a generation.

Join our community on Patreon to watch the full episode. For every annual membership purchased between now and the end of the year, we’ll gift a free annual membership to someone who can’t afford one. #voting #scotus #elections #votingrightsact #politics #vox #patreon

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hypertension is a silent killer. Here’s how to look out for it. #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/jHaaNwxTnNM</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/jHaaNwxTnNM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:01:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Mashed potatoes, turkey, mac and cheese… While these are all delicious Thanksgiving Day foods, they can also be instigators of one of the most prevalent silent killers in the US: hypertension. So, as you get ready to sit down and celebrate with your loved ones, check if you’re at risk and use these tips from Vox senior correspondent Dylan Scott for keeping your blood pressure down. #hypertension #bloodpressure #thanksgiving #health #highbloodpressure

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What’s Next for The World? | An Optimist’s Guide to the Planet</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T2RlKDNUkX0</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/T2RlKDNUkX0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[When solutions prove elusive close to home, humanity’s instinct has always been to venture into the unknown. As season two of An Optimist’s Guide to the Planet draws to a close, Nikolaj Coster-Waldau looks to the future—traveling from India to Finland and Peru to uncover how people with imagination are forging a new path forward for the planet. From communities in India’s Eastern Ghats overcoming fear of snakes to restore fragile ecosystems, to Helsinki’s bold reimagining of nuclear energy and the reforestation efforts in Peru’s Cusco region bringing water back to the Andes—this episode reveals how challenging assumptions and redefining humanity's relationship with nature can lead to a cleaner, more sustainable future.


--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Remains of Young Girl Reveal Jamestown Colony Mystery | Full Episode | Secrets of the Dead | PBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9gN8z4MNd9M</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9gN8z4MNd9M?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:00:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Watch more: https://to.pbs.org/3mHxfbj | #SecretsDeadPBS
Archaeologists have been excavating in Jamestown, Virginia for more than 20 years. In April 2012, a team of Historic Jamestowne archeologists discovered something surprising. In the trash layer of a cellar, among the butchered animal bones and household trash discarded by the Jamestown colonists, they found the mutilated skull and severed leg of a 14-year-old English girl dating back to 1609.

Jamestown, Virginia is the site of the first permanent English colony the Americas settled in 1607 and the home of the archaeological site “Historic Jamestowne” today. It has long been speculated that the harsh conditions faced by the colonists during the winter of 1609, often referred to as the “starving time,” might have made them desperate enough to participate in the unthinkable.

Jamestown's Dark Winter | Secrets of the Dead

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

Secrets of the Dead on YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/@secretsofthedead

#SecretsoftheDead #jamestown #history #archaeology 

Secrets of the Dead
Part detective story, part true-life drama, @secretsofthedead unearths evidence from around the world, challenging prevailing ideas and throwing fresh light on unexplained events.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Operation Gunnerside: The Allied Mission To Sabotage The Nazi Nuclear Program</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2jPYoqlbLpc</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2jPYoqlbLpc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 22:00:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Uncover the thrilling true story of "The Heavy Water War" during WW2, a desperate Allied effort to prevent Nazi Germany from developing an atomic bomb. This documentary details the critical role of heavy water in nuclear fission and the audacious covert operations, including the daring "Operation Gunnerside," undertaken by Norwegian commandos to sabotage the Vemork plant in occupied Norway. Witness the high-stakes race for the ultimate weapon and the unsung heroes who risked everything to stop Hitler's nuclear ambitions.

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>This graph will change how you see the world</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HBluLfX2F_k</link><author>Veritasium</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HBluLfX2F_k?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA">Veritasium</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The world is not Normal. Sponsored by NordVPN. 🌏 Get exclusive NordVPN deal here ➵  https://NordVPN.com/veritasium It’s risk free with Nord’s 30 day money-back guarantee!✌

Get your exclusive edition of Veritasium’s first tabletop game - join 6,000+ backers - https://ve42.co/pld

To play around with the simulations in the video, you can follow these links:
Sandpiles - https://www.veritasium.com/simulation3 
Ising model (magnetism) - https://www.veritasium.com/simulation4
Forest fires - https://www.veritasium.com/simulation5  

▀▀▀
A huge thanks to Steven Strogatz, Mark Buchanan and Mark Newman for their time and expertise.

▀▀▀
CHAPTERS: 
0:00 What is a power law?
4:31 Expected Values
8:49 The St. Petersburg Paradox
11:37 Outliers Dominate Averages
15:23 Fractals and Power Laws 
19:28 Self-Organized Criticality
24:08 Why do we light controlled forest fires?
26:40 How We Can Predict Earthquakes
32:11 Critical Systems and Universality 
36:31 How Some Businesses Are Built On Power Laws 
39:30 What game are you playing? Normal or power?

▀▀▀
References: https://ve42.co/PowerLawsRefs

▀▀▀
Special thanks to our Patreon supporters:

Adam Foreman, Albert Wenger, Alex Porter, Alexander Tamas, Anton Ragin, Anupam Banerjee, armedtoe, Bertrand Serlet, Blake Byers, Bruce, Dave Kircher, David Johnston, David Tseng, Evgeny Skvortsov, Garrett Mueller, Gnare, gpoly, Hayden Christensen, Ibby Hadeed, Jeromy Johnson, Jon Jamison, Juan Benet, KeyWestr, Kyi, Lee Redden, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Matthias Wrobel, Meekay, meg noah, Michael Bush, Michael Krugman, Orlando Bassotto, Paul Peijzel, Richard Sundvall, Robert Oliveira, Sam Lutfi, Tj Steyn, Ubiquity Ventures & wolfee

▀▀▀
Writers - James Moore, Casper Mebius & Derek Muller
Producer & Director - James Moore
Presenters - Derek Muller & Casper Mebius
Editors - Jack Saxon & Peter Nelson
Animators -  Fabio Albertelli, Emma Wright, Saif Javed & Andrew Neet
Additional Editor - James Stuart
Researchers - Aakash Singh Bagga & Callum Cuttle
Simulations - Aakash Singh Bagga
Thumbnail Designers - Abdallah Rabah, Ren Hurley & Ben Powell
Production Team -  Josh Pitt, Matthew Cavanagh, Anna Milkovic & Katy Southwood 
Executive Producers - Derek Muller & Casper Mebius


Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Images, Storyblocks
Music from Epidemic Sound]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Baltimore’s Secret Language</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/QrBZ87okKYM</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/QrBZ87okKYM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:41:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hope</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/7mQLZiMX1sM</link><author>Horses</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7mQLZiMX1sM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 20:41:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrx2zrPjhGRi9TwszZiLwEg">Horses</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Reese Witherspoon on Picking the Perfect Part</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/8MORX-I6wuc</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8MORX-I6wuc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 20:08:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Emily Chang spends a day with Reese Witherspoon – they talk about power, business and why playing Elle Woods was more radical than anyone realized.

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Is The Human Brain Smart Enough To Understand Universe?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/rLANht463PI</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/rLANht463PI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:00:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We Finally Know Why Betelgeuse Behaves So Strangely</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SbCHSYJfLu8</link><author>Astrum</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SbCHSYJfLu8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-9b7aDP6ZN0coj9-xFnrtw">Astrum</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Everything you need to know about Betelgeuse, plus a surprising new discovery. 
Start uncovering your story with MyHeritage, and don't forget to use my link for a 14-day free trial: https://bit.ly/Astrum_MH 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

This Supercut dives into the enigma of Betelgeuse, our red giant neighbour star on the brink of supernova. But will this spectacular death happen in our lifetime? And should we be worried here on Earth? Beyond the impending explosion, we uncover the exciting new discovery of Betelgeuse’s companion, affectionately dubbed "Betelbuddy." See how this partner star could be the key to understanding Betelgeuse’s strange, erratic activity.

To those returning and new to the channel: This video is a supercut of our previous videos about Betelgeuse, along with new and updated science content. We’ve edited this into a new seamless video, remastered in 4K resolution, and re-recorded the older voiceover to match the quality of the recent episodes. 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

0:00 What You Need to Know About Betelgeuse
2:54 Will Betelgeuse Explode?
7:57 How Supernovae Happen
12:44 Could It Destroy Earth?
17:15 How Long Left?
20:47 Betelgeuse’s Buddy
24:39 The Problem With Betelgeuse’s Rotation
30:01 Cannibal Stars

▀▀▀▀▀▀

WIN A 5-DAY VIP SPACE COAST TRIP! 🚀
Check out this sweepstakes from our friends at ScienceAlert.com. They are giving one reader and their guest a 5-day VIP space adventure vacation in Florida. You’ll participate in Astronaut Training at Kennedy Space Center, dine at EPCOT’s Space 2020 restaurant and experience a bioluminescent night kayaking tour.
All you need to do to enter is subscribe to their free, fact-checked science newsletter - Spark. No purchase necessary. Open to US residents only.
➡️ ENTER HERE: https://www.sciencealert.com/spark-into-space-comp?utm_source=astrum

▀▀▀▀▀▀

To stay on top of space news, sign up to the Astrum newsletter: https://astrumspace.kit.com 
 
Astrum Displate Posters: https://astrumspace.info/Displates 
Astrum Infographic Artwork: https://electrify.art/collections/astrum  
Astrum Merch: https://astrum-shop.fourthwall.com/ 

Join us on the Astrum discord: https://discord.gg/TKw8Hpvtv8 

A huge thanks to our Patreons who help make these videos possible. Sign-up here to support the channel: https://bit.ly/4aiJZNF 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Astrum Podcast on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/6jPRrbq3o3dpvBb173ZTKi?si=a90d3efe3b704c83 

Astrum Earth: https://youtube.com/@AstrumEarth 
Astrum Extra: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumextra 

Astrum Spanish: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumespanol 
Astrum Portuguese: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChn_-OwvV63mr1yeUGvH-BQ 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

References:
Betelgeuse: A Review”, via academic.oup.com https://astrumspace.info/betelgeusereview 
“What Is Betelgeuse? Inside the Strange, Volatile Star”, via nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/insidebetelgeuse 
“Supernovae: Types I and II”, via cfa.harvard.edu https://astrumspace.info/supernovatypes 
“The Great Dimming of Betelgeuse”, via eso.org https://astrumspace.info/greatdimming 
“Betelgeuse Companion Discovered”, via noirlab.edu https://astrumspace.info/betelbuddy 
“Direct Imaging of the ‘Betel-Buddy’: A Companion to Betelgeuse”, via iop.org https://astrumspace.info/betelbuddyimage 
“Hubble Sees Red Supergiant Star Betelgeuse Slowly Recovering After Blowing Its Top”, via nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/betelgeuserecovery 
“Is Betelgeuse Really Rotating?”, via iop.org https://astrumspace.info/betelgeuserotation 
“Convective Outbursts, Mode Switching, and Mass Ejection in Betelgeuse”, via iop.org https://astrumspace.info/betelgeuseoutbursts 
“Betelgeuse Pulsation and Impending Explosion”, via arxiv.org https://astrumspace.info/betelgeusepulsation

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Credits:
Writer: Jon McColgan
Video Editor: Nathália Huzian
Researcher: Shourya Shrivastava
Script Editor: Damaris McColgan
Thumbnail Designer: Peter Sheppard
Publishing Lead: Georgina Brenner
Production Manager: Raquel Taylor
Edit Producer: Poppy Pinnock
Head of Astrum: Jess Jordan
Creator of Astrum: Alex McColgan

With special thanks to:
NASA/ESO/ESA

#Astrum #Space #Betelgeuse]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hair: Why it&apos;s important and what it reveals about us | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f1rNyA1-sg4</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/f1rNyA1-sg4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:01:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Our hair doesn't just provide protection from sun and cold, it also says a great deal about us. In a society that's predominantly focused on outward appearance, hair wields huge social capital. It can either elicit admiration — or turn into a problem.

A full, glossy head of hair is synonymous with beauty, youth and vitality. But what happens when that hair loses its shine? As we age, our hair gets thinner, alters its structure or falls out. Can anything be done to address these changes? How do we learn to be content with the hair we have — or with no hair whatsoever? Are hair transplants worth the bother?

This documentary observes people for whom hair is of particular importance: an actor who is happy to be bald, a man who decides to have a hair transplant and a hair artist whose hair can do incredible things, such as supporting her entire body weight. This is due to the structure of hair: each individual strand consists of numerous protein spirals linked together by chemical bonds. That makes it incredibly elastic and highly stable: a single hair can hold up to 100 grams without breaking.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #hair 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What does Ken Burns leave on the cutting floor? 🎬 #AmericanRevolutionPBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/02LwbVY8cUQ</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/02LwbVY8cUQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:00:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Ken Burns discusses the choices that go into making his documentaries. A documentary can't always include "everything that happened", otherwise it would be a million hours long, so what material doesn't make the final cut? 

Made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app!

The American Revolution | A Film by Ken Burns, Sarah Botstein and David Schmidt
Thirteen American colonies unite in rebellion, win an eight-year war to secure their independence, and establish a new form of government that would inspire democratic movements at home and around the globe. What begins as a political clash between colonists and the British government grows into a bloody struggle that will engage more than two dozen nations and forever change the world.

#AmericanRevolutionPBS #documentary #PBS #history]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Albanian AK of the Kosovo Liberation Army (UÇK) with firearms expert Jonathan Ferguson ft. IWM</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yHtx4obL8I0</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/yHtx4obL8I0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:15:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Royal Armouries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This week we’re looking at an Albanian Kalashnikov (that Ian recently looked at...) with a very personal mark carved into it: “UCK” (UÇK), standing for the Kosovo Liberation Army.

We're also joined by our friends at IWM for this episode and we'd like to thank them for providing footage and collaborating with us.

You can find their channel here: @ImperialWarMuseums 

0:00 Intro
1:11 ASh-78
2:40 “UCK” on the Handguard & The KLA
3:49 Kosovo War, NATO Intervention & How the Rifle Was Captured
5:04 Imperial War Museum Drawing & Albanian-Supplied Rifles
7:00 IWM Segment
8:52 From Rough AK to Historical Object & Ongoing Legacy
9:54 Outro

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Did Britain Fight a Guerrilla War in Malaya?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zVkwQO3HdH4</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/zVkwQO3HdH4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:30:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This video explores the Malayan Emergency, a brutal counter-insurgency conflict in colonial Malaya spanning from 1948 until 1960.  

00:00:00:00 The Malayan Emergency
00:01:27:15 Importance of Malaya to the British Empire
00:02:39:10 Japanese Occupation
00:04:22:06 The Malayan Union
00:05:58:04 Social Climate
00:08:12:03 Declaration of Emergency and Jungle Warfare
00:10:11:08 British Tactics
00:13:49:14 Forced Relocation and The Briggs Plan
00:17:44:05 The Baling Talks
00:19:58:22 End of the Emergency and Legacy

Visit Emergency Exits: The Fight for Independence in Mayala, Kenya and Cyprus, open now at IWM London: https://www.iwm.org.uk/events/emergency-exits-the-fight-for-independence-in-malaya-kenya-and-cyprus

Explore and licence the film clips used in this video:
https://film.iwmcollections.org.uk/collections/_e9q63jA5

Follow IWM on social media:
x.com/I_W_M 
instagram.com/imperialwarmuseums 
facebook.com/iwm.london 
tiktok.com/@imperialwarmuseums

The Baling Talks, 28 December 1955 from Wikimedia Commons, THE NEW STRAITS TIMES PRESS (M) BERHAD (NSTP), CC BY-SA 4.0,  https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Building Data Visualisations in Python in Minutes • Kris Jenkins • GOTO 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lQRq4-MiAGA</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/lQRq4-MiAGA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 13:01:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This presentation was recorded at GOTO Copenhagen 2025. #GOTOcon #GOTOcph
https://gotocph.com

Kris Jenkins - Lifelong Computer Geek and Podcast Host @krisajenkins 

RESOURCES
https://bsky.app/profile/krisajenkins.bsky.social
https://twitter.com/krisajenkins
https://www.linkedin.com/in/krisjenkins
https://github.com/krisajenkins
http://blog.jenkster.com

ABSTRACT
The backend has all the data. It has access to all the databases, the flat files and the remote storage APIs. But if you want to look at that data, it feels like you're forced to build yet another REST API and hire a React expert.

No more! Streamlit has you covered. Streamlit's a simple Python framework that makes it incredibly easy to take Python's data-processing capabilities and build clean, professional visualisations in minutes.

In this live-coding session we'll start completely from scratch and explore the core parts of Streamlit's API, learn a little Pandas along the way, and see how a backend developer or data scientist can actually look at their data faster than you can say, "JSON encoding". [...]

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
02:40 Live Demo
32:15 Outro

Read the full abstract here:
https://gotocph.com/2025/sessions/3936

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Sandy Maguire • Thinking with Types • https://leanpub.com/thinking-with-types
Edwin Brady • Type-Driven Development with Idris • https://amzn.to/432GZTi
Maryann Kisamore • Basics Of Apache Kafka • https://amzn.to/3tkVYFD
Mitch Seymour • Mastering Kafka Streams and ksqlDB • https://amzn.to/3HZ18wK
Ted Dunning & Ellen Friedman • Streaming Architecture • https://amzn.to/3lhk3Kb
Liz Rice • Container Security • https://amzn.to/3oU4iJe
Neal Ford • Functional Thinking • https://amzn.to/3DdP35B
Petricek & Skeet • Real-World Functional Programming • https://amzn.to/38diF4M

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#Streamlit #Dataviz #PythonLanguage #DataVisualizations #PythonProgramming #PythonTutorial #PythonFramework #LiveCoding #Eurovision #Snowflake #Data #Database #RESTAPI #KrisJenkins

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Didn&apos;t BF-109s Have DROP TANKS?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/K-kzdoR940g</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/K-kzdoR940g?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This video examines why the Luftwaffe didn't use drop tanks on their BF-109s during the Battle of Britain.

#history #ww2 #bf109]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>20th Century Keyboard Trailer</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SIVxfOUMV4U</link><author>Chyrosran22</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SIVxfOUMV4U?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:25:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCD0y51PJfvkZNe3y3FR5riw">Chyrosran22</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[22-12-2025 (unboxing before that)
Just me having some fun again :p . 

Music: T. Rex - 20th Century Boy
Camerawoman: my mum
Text animation: Kyle L. Carter
Video effects: T.O.M Studios, Vinni Gret]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>2000 Meters to Andriivka (full documentary) | FRONTLINE</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nf4Cgy56slU</link><author>FRONTLINE PBS | Official</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Nf4Cgy56slU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:00:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3ScyryU9Oy9Wse3a8OAmYQ">FRONTLINE PBS | Official</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A stunning and immersive portrayal of the men fighting on the front lines of the war in Ukraine, 
from the Oscar®-winning team behind “20 Days in Mariupol.”

This journalism is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station here: https://www.pbs.org/donate​.

“2000 Meters to Andriivka” documents the toll of the Russia-Ukraine war from a personal and devastating vantage point. Following his historic account of the civilian toll in Mariupol, Ukrainian filmmaker and Associated Press journalist Mstyslav Chernov turns his lens towards Ukrainian soldiers — who they are, where they came from, and the impossible decisions they face in the trenches as they fight for every inch of their land.

The documentary follows a Ukrainian brigade battling through approximately one mile of a heavily fortified forest on their mission to liberate the Russian-occupied village of Andriivka amid a failing counteroffensive in 2023. 

Weaving together original footage, intensive Ukrainian Army bodycam video and powerful moments of reflection with haunting intimacy, the documentary reveals how the farther the soldiers advance through their destroyed homeland, the more they realize that, for them, this war may never end.

“2000 Meters to Andriivka” is written, filmed and directed by filmmaker and Associated Press journalist Mstyslav Chernov. It is produced by Chernov, FRONTLINE’s senior documentary editor and producer Michelle Mizner and FRONTLINE’s editor-in-chief and executive producer Raney Aronson-Rath. It is edited by Michelle Mizner. The film is co-produced and includes additional cinematography by AP journalist Alex Babenko, and is composed by two-time Grammy Award®-winning composer and music-producer Sam Slater. Distributed domestically by PBS Distribution and internationally by Dogwoof, “2000 Meters to Andriivka” is a FRONTLINE FEATURES and The Associated Press production.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Reporter Extra: Chatbots Are Designed to Please You — Here’s Why That’s a Problem</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/WaLS0lM4-1o</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/WaLS0lM4-1o?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 23:06:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Vox senior technology correspondent Adam Clark Estes has a cautionary tale about chatbots.

What started as using AI for tedious chores — meal plans, grocery lists, quick research — quietly morphed into hours talking to a chatbot. And Adam isn’t alone. As chatbots get better at flattery, emotional support, and companionship, researchers are seeing more users (including teens) slip into dependency without realizing it.

Adam unpacks how chatbots are designed to keep us coming back, why young people are especially vulnerable, and what happens when adults can’t walk away — in some cases, leading to severe mental health crises. 

This is the first episode of Reporter Extras, a new Patreon-exclusive Vox video series that gives you a behind-the-scenes look at how our journalists create their work.

If you value this kind of in-depth journalism, join Vox on Patreon to unlock the full episode, get unlimited access to Vox.com, and support the reporting that makes it possible. https://www.patreon.com/posts/144397104?pr=true

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What about the ladies of the Revolutionary War? 🙋‍♀️ #AmericanRevolutionPBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/JPVCTXfLOQ4</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JPVCTXfLOQ4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 23:00:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[What did the ladies contribute to the American Revolution? Kathleen DuVal, American historian and professor at University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill discusses the role of women in the war efforts and intellectual aspects of the new America government.

Made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app!

#revolutionarywar #americanhistory #womeninhistory #womenshistory 

The American Revolution | A Film by Ken Burns, Sarah Botstein and David Schmidt
Thirteen American colonies unite in rebellion, win an eight-year war to secure their independence, and establish a new form of government that would inspire democratic movements at home and around the globe. What begins as a political clash between colonists and the British government grows into a bloody struggle that will engage more than two dozen nations and forever change the world.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Inside Stalin&apos;s Spy Network: Secret War For The Atomic Bomb</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GImS8q8vBEg</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GImS8q8vBEg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 22:00:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Set up as a 'temporary' measure by Lenin, millions of Soviet citizens would die at the hands of the secret services as internal dissent, real or imaginary, was crushed. Outside the Soviet Union, however, they were busy infiltrating German High Command, British Intelligence and America’s Manhattan Project, constructing the world’s first atomic bomb. Soon, Moscow had the means to build one of their own. 

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Do We Live in the Rarest Solar System In The Universe? We&apos;re about to find out!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mPFFUWPXAFs</link><author>PBS Space Time</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mPFFUWPXAFs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:15:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC7_gcs09iThXybpVgjHZ_7g">PBS Space Time</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[To learn more visit: https://hensonshaving.com/pbs and use code spacetime to get 100 blades for free with your purchase of a Henson Razor. Add both products to your cart for the code to take effect!

There are lots of reasons to search for planets around other stars—exoplanets. A big one is to find other places in the universe that might harbor life. We only know of one such planet so far: Earth. And so we get particularly excited when we find Earth-mass planets at the right distance from their star to sustain liquid water—also critical for life as we know it. We’ve found lots of those “habitable” worlds. But we also don’t know what factors are really critical to the initial development of life. Maybe star type? We get even more excited if that Earth-mass at the right distance from a Sun-type star. We’ve found a few of those too, and we can infer that there are lots more. 

Check out the Black Friday Sale at the Space Time Merch Store
https://www.pbsspacetime.com/shop

PBS Member Stations rely on viewers like you. To support your local station, go to:http://to.pbs.org/DonateSPACE

Sign Up on Patreon to get access to the Space Time Discord!
https://www.patreon.com/pbsspacetime



Sign up for the mailing list to get episode notifications and hear special announcements!
https://mailchi.mp/1a6eb8f2717d/spacetime

Search the Entire Space Time Library Here: https://search.pbsspacetime.com/

Hosted by Matt O'Dowd
Written by Matt O'Dowd 
Post Production by Leonardo Scholzer
Directed by Andrew Kornhaber
Associate Producer: Bahar Gholipour
Executive Producer: Andrew Kornhaber
Executive in Charge for PBS: Maribel Lopez
Director of Programming for PBS: Gabrielle Ewing
Assistant Director of Programming for PBS: John Campbell

Spacetime is a production of Kornhaber Brown for PBS Digital Studios.
This program is produced by Kornhaber Brown, which is solely responsible for its content.
© 2025 PBS. All rights reserved.

End Credits Music by J.R.S. Schattenberg: https://www.youtube.com/user/MultiDroideka

Space Time Was Made Possible In Part By: 

Big Bang
Alexander Tamas
David Paryente
Juan Benet
Mark Rosenthal
Morgan Hough
Peter Barrett
Santiago
Tj Steyn
Vinnie Falco

Supernova
Ethan Cohen
Glenn Sugden
Grace Biaelcki
Mark Heising
Stephen Wilcox
Tristan Lucian Claudius Aurelius Tyacke

Hypernova
Alex Kern
Ben Delo
Cal Stephens
chuck zegar
David Giltinan
Dean Galvin
Donal Botkin
Gregory Forfa
Jesse Cid Dyer
John R. Slavik
Justin Lloyd
Kenneth See
Massimiliano Pala
Michael Tidwell
Mike Purvis
Paul Stehr-Green
Scott Gorlick
Scott Gray
Spencer Jones
Stephen Saslow
Thomas Mouton
Zachary Haberman
Антон Кочков
Daniel Muzquiz

Gamma Ray Burst
Aaron Pinto
Adrien Molyneux
Almog Cohen
Anthony Leon
Arko Provo Mukherjee
Ayden Miller
Ben McIntosh
Bradley Jenkins
Bradley Ulis
Brandon Lattin
Brian Cook
Bryan White
Chris Liao
Christopher Wade
Chuck Lukaszewski
Collin Dutrow
Craig Falls
Craig Stonaha
Dan Warren
Daniel Donahue
Daniel Jennings
Daron Woods
Darrell Stewart
David Johnston
Doyle Vann
Eric Kiebler
Eric Raschke
Eric Schrenker
Faraz Khan
Frederic Simon
Harsh Khandhadia
Ian Williams
Isaac Suttell
James Trimmier
Jeb Campbell
Jeremy Soller
Jerry Thomas
jim bartosh
John Anderson
John De Witt
John Funai
John H. Austin, Jr.
John591
Joseph Salomone
Junaid Ali
Kacper Cieśla
Kane Holbrook
Keith Pasko
Kent Durham
Koen Wilde
Kyle Atkinson
Marcelo Garcia
Marion Lang
Mark Daniel Cohen
Mark Delagasse
Matt Kaprocki
Matthew Johnson
Michael Barton
Michael Clark
Michael Lev
Michael Purcell
Nathaniel Bennett
Nick Hoffenstoffer III
Nicolas Katsantonis
Paul Wood
Rad Antonov
Reuben Brewer
Richard Steenbergen
Robert DeChellis
Ross Story
Russell Moore
SamSword
Sandhya Devi
Satwik Pani
Sean Owen
Shane Calimlim
SilentGnome
Sound Reason
Steffen Bendel
Steven Giallourakis
Terje Vold
Thomas Dougherty
Tomaz Lovsin
Tybie Fitzhugh
Vlad Shipulin
William Flinn
WILLIAM HAY III
Zac Sweers]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>My favourite Picasso quote as featured in my latest video</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/9qsAATFN4RI</link><author>Shawn Grenier | The Canvas</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9qsAATFN4RI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:40:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqTHx0ObkFZ97KO2SWUuz9w">Shawn Grenier | The Canvas</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[My Letterboxd: https://boxd.it/4bApF
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/thecanvasyoutube/
Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/TheCanvas

#arthistory #art]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The “Dumbest Question” Mayor Scott has ever Received</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/Fc8yHTYOjvg</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Fc8yHTYOjvg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:16:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A Soldier&apos;s Haunting Request | 2000 Meters to Andriivka (excerpt) | FRONTLINE &amp; @AssociatedPress</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ea2bvNqjIps</link><author>FRONTLINE PBS | Official</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ea2bvNqjIps?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:30:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3ScyryU9Oy9Wse3a8OAmYQ">FRONTLINE PBS | Official</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[About an hour into the new feature documentary "2000 Meters to Andriivka," a Ukrainian volunteer soldier makes a haunting request: "Don't make me out as a hero." 

This journalism is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station here: https://www.pbs.org/donate

The soldier, who went by the call sign “Sheva,”  was part of the Ukrainian platoon at the heart of "2000 Meters to Andriivka," the new feature documentary from FRONTLINE, The Associated Press and the Academy Award-winning team behind "20 Days in Mariupol."

Weaving together quiet moments of reflection, like this one with Sheva, and vivid battle footage, "2000 Meters to Andriivka" documents the toll of the Russia-Ukraine war from a personal and devastating vantage point. The film follows Ukraine’s 3rd Assault Brigade as it carries out a grueling, meter-by-meter counteroffensive that aims to retake the strategic Ukrainian town of Andriivka from Russia -- and as the soldiers realize that for them, the war may never end.

Sheva would be killed in a battle and die in a hospital five months after this scene was filmed. Read more about Sheva's story at pbs.org/frontline, and watch the full documentary on @frontline starting Nov. 25, 2025.

“2000 Meters to Andriivka” is written, filmed and directed by filmmaker and Associated Press journalist Mstyslav Chernov. It is produced by Chernov, FRONTLINE’s senior documentary editor and producer Michelle Mizner and FRONTLINE’s editor-in-chief and executive producer Raney Aronson-Rath. It is edited by Michelle Mizner. The film is co-produced and includes additional cinematography by AP journalist Alex Babenko; is composed by two-time Grammy Award®-winning composer and music-producer Sam Slater; and is executive produced by Raney Aronson-Rath and the AP's Derl McCrudden. Distributed domestically by PBS Distribution and internationally by Dogwoof, “2000 Meters to Andriivka” is a FRONTLINE FEATURES and The Associated Press production.

#ukraine #ukrainewar #ukrainerussiawar #documentaryexcerpt]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dunmore&apos;s Proclamation &amp; Black Americans in the American Revolution | PBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bfChc8JR8O8</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bfChc8JR8O8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:01:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Official website: https://to.pbs.org/amrevpbs | #AmericanRevolutionPBS
Forty percent of white Virginians owned enslaved people, and farmers like George Washington lived in fear of a revolt. These fears come to reality when Virginia's royal governor, Lord Dunmore, issues a proclamation offering freedom to any enslaved individual who joins his fight against their Patriot masters. Some 800 men would join Dunmore, including some of George Washington's own slaves.

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

#americanhistory #revolutionarywar #history #ushistory #blackhistory   

THE AMERICAN REVOLUTION | A Film By Ken Burns, Sarah Botstein and David Schmidt
An expansive look at the virtues and contradictions of the war and the birth of the United States of America, the film follows dozens of figures from a wide variety of backgrounds. Through their individual stories, viewers experience the war through the memories of the men and women who experienced it: the rank-and-file Continental soldiers and American militiamen (some of them teenagers), Patriot political and military leaders, British Army officers, American Loyalists, Native soldiers and civilians, enslaved and free African Americans, German soldiers in the British service, French and Spanish allies, and various civilians living in North America, Loyalist as well as Patriot, including many made refugees by the war.

The Revolution began a movement for people around the world to imagine new and better futures for themselves, their nations, and for humanity. It declared American independence with promises that we continue to strive for. The American Revolution opened the door to advance civil liberties and human rights, and it asked questions that we are still trying to answer today.

The film, narrated by Peter Coyote, includes the first-person voices of nearly 200 individual historic figures, read by a cast of actors, including Adam Arkin, Jeremiah Bitsui, Corbin Bleu, Kenneth Branagh, Josh Brolin, Bill Camp, Tantoo Cardinal, Josh Charles, Hugh Dancy, Claire Danes, Jeff Daniels, Keith David, Hope Davis, Marcus Davis-Orrom, Bruce Davison, Leon Dische Becker, Alden Ehrenreich, Craig Ferguson, Morgan Freeman, Christian Friedel, Paul Giamatti, Domhnall Gleeson, Amanda Gorman, Michael Greyeyes, Jonathan Groff, Charlotte Hacke, Tom Hanks, Ethan Hawke, Maya Hawke, Lucas Hedges, Josh Hutcherson, Samuel L. Jackson, Gene Jones, Michael Keaton, Joe Keery, Joel Kinnaman, Tracy Letts, Damian Lewis, Laura Linney, Josh Lucas, Michael Mando, Carolyn McCormick, Lindsay Mendez, Tobias Menzies, Joe Morton, Edward Norton, David Oyelowo, Mandy Patinkin, Wendell Pierce, Jon Proudstar, Matthew Rhys, LaTanya Richardson, Liev Schreiber, Chaske Spencer, Dan Stevens, Meryl Streep, and Yul Vazquez, among others.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Poland’s fentanyl crisis | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LMybt9-aXTQ</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LMybt9-aXTQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:00:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Fentanyl is estimated to be fifty times as potent as heroin and is extremely addictive. The number of people in Poland abusing this powerful painkiller is growing. There have been dozens of fatalities.

Michal lives in a small town south of Gdansk. Because of the stigma surrounding people with addiction, he prefers to remain anonymous. Every two weeks, he travels to Święciec to take methadone, a substitute drug, at the addiction clinic of the psychiatric hospital. After using various drugs, he started taking fentanyl, the strongest of all opiates. 
Fentanyl is used to treat people with severe pain and as an anesthetic. Addicts remove the gel from pain patches and inject it directly into their bloodstream. There have been dozens of fatal overdoses in Poland. Michal has also lost one of his close friends. Corrupt pharmacists are believed to have sold large quantities of fentanyl patches to dealers. The authorities have since put a stop to this.  
In Żuromin, Jadwiga Karpinska lost her son Pawel to a fatal overdose. Their town, a two-hour drive from the capital Warsaw, was known as the country’s unofficial fentanyl capital in 2024. That changed when police detained a well-known local dealer. The drug continues to be available there, but in smaller quantities.
Elementary school teacher Adam Ejnik believes in prevention. He wants to keep his students away from the drug by raising awareness about its dangers. 
Artur from Łódź has managed to get off fentanyl. A few years ago, he was so addicted, he had lost the will to live. Today, his girlfriend Agnieszka helps him stay clean. His goal: he hopes to finish his psychology degree and work as a therapist to help other addicts get off the extremely powerful drug.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #poland #fentanyl 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Are Space Elevators Possible?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/5kaNDtqsPBE</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5kaNDtqsPBE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:30:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>4️⃣ Levels of Darkness in Brahms Op. 118, No. 6</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/O5xYtSZUGh4</link><author>Ben Laude</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/O5xYtSZUGh4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:29:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnSFlVqRyNfIJDsmpkcY57w">Ben Laude</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[https://patreon.com/BenLaude
https://instagram.com/benlawdy/
https://benlaude.com/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Baltimore Streets</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XQs59YY-e2I</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XQs59YY-e2I?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:25:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://ground.news/channel5 to stay fully informed with all sides of every story. Subscribe for 40% off the Vantage plan through my link.

Head to http://www.youtube.com/@CanalCincoLatam to see our original, Spanish-language content! 

Subscribe to our Patreon at https://www.patreon.com/channel5 to see our new episode 'Inside the All-White Community of Arkansas.']]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The seed that gave Coca-Cola its name - Shantel George</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IpaVpMFBwAE</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IpaVpMFBwAE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">TED-Ed</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dig into the bitter history of kola nuts, a sacred ingredient in West African culture and part of Coca-Cola's original recipe.

--

The kola nut is the seed of the kola tree, a small evergreen native to the forests of West Africa, where it’s long been integral to the cultural fabric of many communities. So, how did this sacred ingredient end up all around the world? And how did it make its way into the original recipe of a drink that billions of people consume every day? Shantel George explores the bitter history of kola nuts.

Lesson by Shantel George, directed by Nikhita Prabhudesai Jeena, Totem Creative.

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-seed-that-gave-coca-cola-its-name-shantel-george
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-seed-that-gave-coca-cola-its-name-shantel-george/digdeeper

Animator's website: https://www.totemcreative.in
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! Vector-Dopamine math, Jasper Song, Giorgio Bugnatelli, Chardon, Eddy Trochez, OnlineBookClub.org, Eric Shear, Leith Salem, Omar Hicham, Adrian Rotaru, Brad Sullivan, Karen Ho, Niklas Frimberger, Hunter Manhart, Nathan Nguyen, Igor Stavchanskiy, James R DeVries, Grace Huo, Diana Huang, Chau Hong Diem, Orlellys Torre, Corheu, Thomas Mee, Maryann H McCrory, Blas Borde, John Hellmann, Poompak Meephian, Chuck Wofford, Adam Pagan, Wes Winn, Conder Shou, ntiger, Noname, Hansan Hu, David D, Mac Hyney, Keith Ellison, robin valero walters, Lynne Truesdale, Gatsby Dkdc, Matthew Neal, Denis Chon, Julian Oberhofer, Monte Carroll, Eddy, Jay M, Constantino Victor Delgado, Andrea Galvagni, Andrew Tweddle, and Laurel-Ann Rice.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Trees Are So Weird</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZSch_NgZpQs</link><author>Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZSch_NgZpQs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:00:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q">Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Want to restore the planet’s ecosystems and see your impact in monthly videos? The first 100 people to join Planet Wild with my code KURZGESAGT11 will get the first month for free at: https://planetwild.com/r/kurzgesagt/join
If you want to get to know them better first, check out their project reviving underground forests in Tanzania: https://planetwild.com/r/kurzgesagt/m33

It’s not too late to get your 12,026 Human Era Calendar: https://shop.kgs.link/12026! It’s filled with cosmic stories, elaborate illustrations, and supports all that we do at kurzgesagt ❤️

Sources & further reading:
https://sites.google.com/view/sources-treesaredead/

Trees are among the most extreme and successful forms of life on Earth. They build their bodies from thin air, move water with pressures that would crush a human, and grow using a fascinating system of living cables wrapped in layers of corpses. Under their bark lies a razor-thin strip of living cells, working endlessly to move water hundreds of meters, build indestructible wood, and coordinate millions of functions. 
How do trees work, and what are they even made of? What makes these ancient giants so resilient, and maybe even immortal?


OUR CHANNELS
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
German:        https://kgs.link/youtubeDE
Spanish:        https://kgs.link/youtubeES
French:          https://kgs.link/youtubeFR
Portuguese:  https://kgs.link/youtubePT
Arabic:           https://kgs.link/youtubeAR
Hindi:             https://kgs.link/youtubeHI
Japanese:     https://kgs.link/youtubeJA
Korean:          https://kgs.link/youtubeKO


HOW CAN YOU SUPPORT US?
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
This is how we make our living and it would be a pleasure if you support us!

Get Products designed with ❤️ https://shop.kgs.link
Join the Patreon Bird Army 🐧  https://kgs.link/patreon  


DISCUSSIONS & SOCIAL MEDIA
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Instagram:     https://kgs.link/instagram
TikTok:           https://kgs.link/tiktok
Reddit:            https://kgs.link/reddit
Discord:          https://kgs.link/discord
Twitter:           https://kgs.link/twitter
Bluesky:          https://kgs.link/bluesky
Facebook:      https://kgs.link/facebook
Newsletter:    https://kgs.link/newsletter


OUR VOICE
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
The kurzgesagt voice is from 
Steve Taylor:  https://kgs.link/youtube-voice


OUR MUSIC ♬♪
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
700+ minutes of kurzgesagt soundtracks by Epic Mountain:

Spotify:            https://kgs.link/music-spotify
Soundcloud:   https://kgs.link/music-soundcloud
Bandcamp:     https://kgs.link/music-bandcamp
Youtube:          https://kgs.link/music-youtube
Facebook:       https://kgs.link/music-facebook

The soundtrack of this video:
SoundCloud: https://bit.ly/4riwGp9
Bandcamp: https://bit.ly/44uVxMG

If you want to help us caption this video, please send subtitles to subtitle@kurzgesagt.org
You can find info on what subtitle files work on YouTube here:
https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2734698?hl=en-GB&ref_topic=7296214
Thank you!


🐦🐧🐤 PATREON BIRD ARMY 🐤🐧🐦
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Many thanks to our wonderful Patreons (from http://kgs.link/patreon) who support us every month and made this video possible:
Acácio Correia, AeryaRia, aforsberg, Ahmad Seet, Alexander, Alexander Devlin, amia, Andres Ramos, Anna Duwenig, Anthony Hanson, Anton Abrahamsson, AonReo, Armond Aghanian, Asaf Yishai, Benjamin R., Bharath Ron, Brendan Ryan-Lewis, Christoph Lurz, Christoph Rau, Clay, Cliff Hudson, ConsterCoaster, Corbin Meier, Dale Kipple, Delano Stijns, dotvhs, Dylan Gafner, eddie k, Ela Yohannan, Enigma66, Eran Aviram, Erwin Heckler, Eva Markiewicz, Evil Cookie, FeelinaraIRL, Frankie Ennis, G, Geoff Evans, George Hutter, hazardx, Hugh Mungus, Inigo vd, Ireleigh, Isabelll, Ishaan Varma, Jack Sparrow, James Emmitt Zugar, James Pinkerton, james trotta, Jason Desrosiers, Jason Murley, Jens Begemann, Jesse, Jesus Mayo, Joann Taijala, Joseph Gauthier, jurd, Justin, KawasakiDragonno, Keddan, KekzL, Lauren Woolsey LeGrandAnanas, Lulidine, LumpyMammot, manchicken, Mark A Vargas, MasterOfTree, Matthew Brady, Matthew Brodeur, Maximilian Schons, Mead Landis, Ms. Ewing, Mykola Balakin, Nathaniel Bauernfeind, Nicholas McCalla, Owen, PaladinSpartac, Phoenix_Flames, Primalis, Quinn Wilson, Rath Robin, Robert Cudinski, Robin Hockett, Ryan Snead, Ryan Staunch, Ryan Thompson, SentinelD20, Siddharth Chaini, Sindre Nistad, Soko Divanovic, Spleens, Stacey Nicholson, Stephen Conlon, Strudy, Syi, Sérgio P., Thomas Mitchell, Thomas Stokes, Thomas Toombes, Tom Kocmi, Warren MacEvoy, William Lingenfelter]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Worst Tech Product of the Century [Friend.com]</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BN9zz2O6jcw</link><author>ColdFusion</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/BN9zz2O6jcw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:45:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC4QZ_LsYcvcq7qOsOhpAX4A">ColdFusion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://buyraycon.com/coldfusionOPEN to get up to 30% off during Raycon’s Black Friday and Cyber Monday Sale.
These days people are in search of companionship but tech companies are treating it like another problem that has to be solved. One of the latest efforts in this space is Friend.com. An AI pendant that serves as your very own digital buddy. The product itself has seen terrible reviews and has a lot of people asking the question “do we really need this?” 
In this video we explore.

Watch or listen to ColdFusion on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/1YEwCKoRz8fEDqheXB6UJ1

ColdFusion Music: 

https://www.youtube.com/@ColdFusionmusic
http://burnwater.bandcamp.com   

Get my book: 

http://bit.ly/NewThinkingbook 

ColdFusion Socials: 

https://discord.gg/coldfusion
https://facebook.com/ColdFusionTV 
https://twitter.com/ColdFusion_TV 
https://instagram.com/coldfusiontv

Created by: Dagogo Altraide
Producers: Tawsif Akkas, Dagogo Altraide]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fear on the streets | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/l_FpOnObpK4</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/l_FpOnObpK4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:01:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Although sexual violence can affect people of all genders, women and girls are disproportionally impacted.  

Many women feel unsafe in public spaces, whether on streets, at train stations, or in parks. The danger they face overwhelmingly comes from men: Around 95% of sexualized violence in public spaces is committed by them. 

Yanni Gentsch's encounter with a stranger who secretly filmed her while she jogged in a forest in Cologne went viral on the internet after she recorded the confrontation. Her experience demonstrates a common and recurring problem. 

Watch the full documentary “How male violence shapes women’s lives” on the DW Documentary YouTube channel.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #maleviolence #25N #internationaldayfortheeliminationofviolenceagainstwomen 

______

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Breaking the Architecture Bottleneck • Andrew Harmel-Law &amp; Marit van Dijk</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6BGQcTjecjM</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6BGQcTjecjM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:29:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for GOTO Unscripted.
https://gotopia.tech
 (https://gotopia.tech/articles/392) 
Andrew Harmel-Law - Technical Principal at Thoughtworks & Author of "Facilitating Software Architecture"
Marit van Dijk - Developer Advocate at JetBrains, Java Champion & Open Source Contributor

RESOURCES
Andrew
https://bsky.app/profile/andrewhl.bsky.social
 (https://github.com/andrewharmellaw) https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewharmellaw
https://andrewharmellaw.github.io

Marit
https://bsky.app/profile/maritvandijk.bsky.social
https://linkedin.com/in/maritvandijk
 (https://github.com/mlvandijk) https://medium.com/@mlvandijk
https://maritvandijk.com

Links
https://facilitatingsoftwarearchitecture.com
https://ruthmalan.com
https://www.linkedin.com/pulse
 (https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/software-architects-do-we-need-em-ruth-malan) 
DESCRIPTION
Andrew Harmel-Law discusses their book "Facilitating Software Architecture" and how traditional architecture approaches often become bottlenecks that slow down high-performing development teams.

Rather than architects making top-down decisions in isolation, they advocate for a facilitation approach centered on the "advice process".

This collaborative method shifts the architect's role from decision-maker to conversation facilitator. The approach has proven successful even in traditional corporate environments, ultimately creating more maintainable code bases where development teams actually enjoy working and can respond effectively to changing requirements.

RECOMMENDED BOOK
Andrew Harmel-Law • Facilitating Software Architecture • https://amzn.eu/d/5kZKVfU


Bluesky (https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com) 
Twitter (https://twitter.com/GOTOcon) 
Instagram (https://www.instagram.com/goto_con) 
LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-) 
Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences) 

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket: gotopia.tech (https://gotopia.tech) 

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR YOUTUBE CHANNEL (https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1)  - new videos posted daily!]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>