<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Youtube</title><link>https://konrad.website/liveboat-github-runner/</link><description></description><item><title>Islam’s Greatest Stories of Love | Full Documentary | PBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QBBjiDKMI6A</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/QBBjiDKMI6A?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 01:00:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A young woman devastated by the loss of her father seeks solace from five of Islam's greatest love stories, which unravel the mysteries of the Taj Mahal, reveal an unsung hero in Malcolm X's life, and show how love can change the world. 

More from this documentary: https://www.pbs.org/show/islams-greatest-stories-of-love/

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

#theology #islam #lovestory 

Islam's Greatest Stories of Love
An extraordinary exploration of love's boundless power to heal, inspire, and transform. At the heart of the film is Ariella, a brilliant young Muslim scholar whose life is upended by the tragic loss of her father. Shattered but determined, she embarks on a bold journey to uncover answers to life's most profound questions: What is love? Can it endure across time and adversity? And how do we rebuild after losing it? Along the way, Ariella is captivated by five astonishing tales from the Islamic tradition — stories that redefine love's meaning.

She delves into an epic poem of star-crossed love as tragic as Romeo and Juliet and unravels the mysteries of the Taj Mahal. She discovers a largely unknown story about how family love shaped Malcolm X and finds empowerment in the remarkable partnership of the Prophet Muhammad and his wife Khadija. Woven through these rich narratives is Ariella’s own quest to rediscover faith, hope, and the courage to love again. With breathtaking storytelling and universal resonance, Islam’s Greatest Stories of Love invites viewers on a journey as unforgettable as the stories it unveils, reminding us that love is not just an emotion; it is a force.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Andrew Goes to Hobo Convention</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/ql9CTlGqmLA</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ql9CTlGqmLA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 23:01:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Gaza’s hunger crisis is officially a famine #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/6DVbgHcklOs</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6DVbgHcklOs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:14:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The UN-backed Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC) system — the world’s leading authority on hunger crises — has officially determined that there is a famine in Gaza. Here’s what that means.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Aryan Origins: Himmler&apos;s Hunt For The Lost City Of Atlantis</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IETLORsmAbM</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IETLORsmAbM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:00:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Heinrich Himmler believed that the Aryan race was descended from the Atlanteans. He claimed that the inhabitants of Atlantis fled to the Himalayas when their city sank. So a German expedition was sent to Tibet to prove this.

Do you love uncovering the past, exploring historic sites, and venturing to distant lands? Join History Hit today and stream hundreds of exclusive documentaries, with new releases every week. Plus, enjoy ad-free access to our podcast network for even more history every week.

Head over to https://bit.ly/45CPh5u to embark on your journey through history!

This channel is part of the Little Dot Studios Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Egon Schiele: Great Art Explained</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uLHZZmTXhPM</link><author>Great Art Explained</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/uLHZZmTXhPM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 18:06:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCePDFpCr78_qmVtpoB1Axaw">Great Art Explained</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[My book Great Art Explained is ready to pre-order now worldwide 
My other channel, Great Books Explained here - https://www.youtube.com/@greatbooksexplained371 
Please consider supporting this channel on Patreon (and getting exclusive and uncensored content), thanks! https://www.patreon.com/user?u=53686503 
or if you prefer a one-off donation - https://paypal.me/GreatArtExplained?country.x=GB&locale.x=en_GB 
Alternatively, every video has a "thanks" button under it- I appreciate it! 

Egon Schiele was one of the most intense and controversial artists of the early 20th century. A shy, reserved child turned rebellious visionary. He scandalised Vienna with raw, often unsettling depictions of the human body. His work is filled with twisted forms and existential angst, reflecting an obsession with mortality, sexuality, and identity - especially his own. 
His self-portraits are unlike anything that came before them: emaciated, contorted and confrontational. With sunken eyes and twisted limbs - they were not intended to flatter, but to disturb. So, what drove this young artist to depict himself so mercilessly?

IMPORTANT!  
Subscribe and click the bell icon to be notified! https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCePD... 

I would like to thank all my Patreon supporters, in particular Alan Stewart, Alexander Velser, AMSN, Andrei Surei, Anja Zeutschel, Bria Nicole Art, Brian J Rich, David Asabreu, Ed Gobbi, "Elias', Eric Mann, Francis Song, Griffin Evans, Jemma Theivendran, Joe Kool, Jon Hanzen, Julio Cardenas, Kibibi Shaw, Louise Tait, Matthew Bondaryk, Mitch Kosowski, Monte St Johns, New Curiosity, Paul Ark, Paul Waterman, Daniel Rakovski, Sam Blakelock, Sean Welgemoed, Stephen Beresford, Tanya Moore, Theresa Garfink, and Toni Ko. 


"What a brilliant series this is" - Stephen Fry on Twitter (X) 

CREDITS 
Script co-written by Laura Beardsell-Moore Opening 
Animation and Title Sequence by Brian Adsit (instagram https://instagram.com/brian_vfx?utm_m... and Behance www.behance.com/badsit88) 
Additional animation (Schiele’s works) by Carlo Vega (http://www.instagram.com/carlovega)
Recording by Robert Lewis 

VIDEOS 
All the videos, songs, images, and graphics used in the video belong to their respective owners and I or this channel do not claim any right over them. 

MUSIC 
Arnold Schoenberg: Verklärte Nacht

BOOKS 
Schiele: The Midnight Soul of the Artist 
Egon Schiele by Frank. Whitford by Reinhard Steiner 
Schiele: 1890-1918: Desire and Decay by Wolfgang Georg Fischer
The Faces of Egon Schiele: Self Portraits by Elizabeth Leoplod and Stefan Kutzenberger
Egon Schiele: Last Years 1914-1918 by Kerstin Jesse, Jane Kallir, et al.

Copyright Disclaimer under section 107 of the Copyright Act of 1976, allowance is made for “fair use” for purposes such as criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching, scholarship, education and research. Fair use is a use permitted by copyright statute that might otherwise be infringing.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>This material gets tougher as you break it</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AFXLZ7FEJc4</link><author>Veritasium</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/AFXLZ7FEJc4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:11:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA">Veritasium</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The strange natural material that reshaped the world. Sponsored by Ground News -
Go to https://groundnews.com/Ve to see through media misconceptions and get all sides of every story. Subscribe to save 40% off the unlimited Vantage Plan through our link.

If you’re looking for a molecular modelling kit, try Snatoms, a kit I invented where the atoms snap together magnetically - https://ve42.co/SnatomsV

▀▀▀
A huge thanks to Professor James Busfield, Dr. Katrina Cornish, and Dr. Judit Puskas

We’re incredibly grateful to Toby Samples and the team at ARDL for their time and expertise. 

Thanks also to Joe Jackson, Dr. Kevin Krause, Dr. Peter Polyak, Donald Shultz, Professor Robert Weiss for all their help on the project.

▀▀▀
0:00 Where does rubber come from?
2:59 What is rubber?
5:10 Why is rubber so stretchy?
6:29 The problem with natural rubber
9:02 Cured Rubber
15:23 Vulcanisation
18:41 What rubber is used in tires?
22:54 How fungi could destroy the world economy
29:17 Synthetic rubber vs natural rubber
38:20 Why are some people allergic to latex? 

▀▀▀
References: https://ve42.co/RubberRefs

Images & Video: https://ve42.co/RubberImgRefs

▀▀▀
Special thanks to our Patreon supporters:
Adam Foreman, Albert Wenger, Alex Porter, Alexander Tamas, Anton Ragin, armedtoe, Balkrishna Heroor, Bertrand Serlet, Blake Byers, Bruce, Dave Kircher, David Johnston, David Tseng, Evgeny Skvortsov, Garrett Mueller, Gnare, gpoly, Ibby Hadeed, Jeromy Johnson, Jon Jamison, JT, Juan Benet, Keith England, KeyWestr, Kyi, Lee Redden, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Matthias Wrobel, Meekay, meg noah, Michael Bush, Michael Krugman, Orlando Bassotto, Paul Peijzel, Richard Sundvall, Robert Oliveira, Sam Lutfi, Tj Steyn, Ubiquity Ventures, Walter Flinn, and wolfee.

▀▀▀
Writers - Sulli Yost & Casper Mebius
Producer & Director - Sulli Yost
Editors - Jack Saxon & Peter Nelson
Camera Operators - Adam Bonomo, Jacob Ruocchio-Cole, Henry van Dyck, Thomas Matheis, Derek Muller & Sulli Yost
Animators -  Allama Nandi, Andrew Neet, Emma Wright, Ivy Tello, Fabio Albertelli & Rokas Viksraitis
Illustrators - Jakub Misiek & Maria Gusakovich
Assistant Editor - James Stuart
Researchers - HyoJeong Choi, Callum Cuttle & Gabe Strong
Thumbnail Designers - Ren Hurley, Ben Powell & Abdallah Rabah
Production Team - Zoe Heron, Casper Mebius, Josh Pitt, Rob Beasley Spence, Henry van Dyck & Sulli Yost
Executive Producers - Casper Mebius & Derek Muller
Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Images, Pond5 
Music from Epidemic Sound]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Piece Played at Both JFK&apos;s and Stalin&apos;s Funerals</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xc2TM8VcCVk</link><author>Ben Laude</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/xc2TM8VcCVk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:10:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnSFlVqRyNfIJDsmpkcY57w">Ben Laude</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The full release of Season 2 Episode 5 is COMING SOON!

The Chopin Podcast: https://chopinpodcast.com
Chopin Foundation: https://chopin.org

0:00 Chopin's most famous (and morbid) tune
5:42 IV. Finale: Presto
9:58 III. "Marche funèbre": Lento
18:13 II. Scherzo
25:00 I. Grave – Doppio movimento
35:09 From Miami to Warsaw

Created and hosted by Ben Laude. Special thanks to Ethan Chilton and Abby Tilton for their assistance in the production of this video.

This podcast is produced in partnership with the Chopin Foundation of the United States, which presents the National Chopin Competition every 5 years. For more, visit https://chopin.org

The Chopin Foundation is a national non-profit organization founded by its President, Blanka A. Rosenstiel in 1977, and inspired by the first US Chopin Competition she presented in Miami in 1975. Support the Chopin Foundation: https://chopin.org/donate

Access uncut interviews with Garrick Ohlsson and other guests:
https://patreon.com/BenLaude

https://www.facebook.com/chopinpodcast
https://www.instagram.com/benlawdy]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How aid organizations are censoring their language under pressure from Israel | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=esnH6FY2tUs</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/esnH6FY2tUs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[When it comes to Gaza, international aid organizations face an agonizing choice: Tone down their rhetoric or risk being denied the permit they need to support Palestinians. 
 
Over the course of several months, DW reviewed internal emails, messages and guidelines, and corroborated claims by analyzing the organizations’ websites, explainer pages and over 100 public statements. DW Investigations found that several aid organizations have increasingly restricted their advocacy on Gaza - banning entire words and phrases from their public messaging. 

If you have a tip, feel free to contact DW's investigative unit here: https://www.dw.com/en/do-you-have-confidential-information-that-you-want-to-share-with-dw/a-61899300

For the latest news, visit the DW News channel https://www.youtube.com/dwnews or the DW website: https://www.dw.com/ 

#documentary #investigation #reporter #dwstories #dwdocumentary
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What Prison Was Like Throughout History | Compilation</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BcrUF58bmVI</link><author>Weird History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/BcrUF58bmVI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 14:00:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc-N24Y5OA0gqbjBwe1ttfA">Weird History</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Prisons are meant to keep the bad guys locked up. But sometimes even our most beloved celebrities have been locked up. And SOME prisons through history have been so scary they inspire horror stories! Come take a trip with us as we look at all things prisons - the most infamous prisons in history,  Female prison ships, what its like to be in solitary, and even what people experience on Death Row. Oh, hey, you will even find out what it was like to be a prison guard at Alcatraz! Enjoy!

Be sure to subscribe to the Weird History Newsletter: https://bit.ly/WeirdHistoryNews

Chapters
00:00:00 - What It Was Like To Be Held On The Most Dangerous Island Prison Colony In History
00:10:15 - What It Was Like to Be a Civil War Prisoner
00:20:28 - What It Was Like To Be A Prison Guard at Alcatraz
00:31:03 - What It's Like to Live on Death Row
00:40:48 - What Being a Prisoner In the Tower of London Was Like
00:49:36 - The Lady Juliana | The 18th-Century All-Women Prison Ship
00:59:26 - The Scariest Prisons in History
01:11:09 - What It's Like To Be In Solitary Confinement
01:22:23 - What It Was Like To Be An Inmate At Alcatraz

#prison #compilation  #weirdhistory]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>&quot;Residues&quot; &amp; &quot;The Architect’s Paradox&quot; • Barry O&apos;Reilly &amp; Jacqui Read</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iDzUXzOYAmE</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iDzUXzOYAmE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for the GOTO Book Club.
http://gotopia.tech/bookclub

Read the full transcription of the interview here
 (https://gotopia.tech/episodes/369) 
Barry O'Reilly - Founder at Black Tulip Tech and Author of "Residues" & "The Architect's Paradox"
Jacqui Read - Software Architect, Speaker & Author of "Communication Patterns"

RESOURCES
Barry
https://bsky.app/profile/technologytulip.bsky.social
https://www.linkedin.com/in/barry-o-reilly-b924657
https://www.blacktulip.se

Jacqui
https://bsky.app/profile/tekiegirl.bsky.social
https://jacquiread.com
https://fosstodon.org/@tekiegirl
https://www.linkedin.com/in/jacquelineread
https://github.com/tekiegirl

DESCRIPTION
In this GOTO Book Club interview, Jacqui Read discusses with Barry O'Reilly his books "Residues: Time, Uncertainty, and Change in Software Architecture" and "The Architect's Paradox". He explains how uncertainty defines the architect's role and introduces residuality—a method where architects deliberately stress their conceptual models until they collapse, then optimize the resulting "residues" or leftovers to create more resilient systems.

Unlike traditional software engineering approaches, that try to eliminate uncertainty through rigid requirements, residuality embraces random stressors (even far-fetched scenarios like giant lizards) to uncover architectural fault lines.

O'Reilly argues that this playful yet mathematically sound approach produces more robust architectures than conventional methods, and his second book explores how inherited philosophical thinking often undermines software architecture's effectiveness in complex business contexts.

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Barry O'Reilly • Residues
 (https://leanpub.com/residuality) Barry O'Reilly • The Architect's Paradox
 (https://leanpub.com/architectsparadox) Jacqui Read • Communication Patterns
 (https://amzn.to/3E37lvv) Anne Currie & Jamie Dobson • The Cloud Native Attitude
 (https://amzn.to/3R0exeT) Gregor Hohpe • The Software Architect Elevator
 (https://amzn.to/3F6d2ax) Gregor Hohpe • Enterprise Integration Patterns, Vol 2 (https://amzn.to/3TNedQ3) 


Bluesky (https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com) 
Twitter (https://twitter.com/GOTOcon) 
Instagram (https://www.instagram.com/goto_con) 
LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-) 
Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences) 

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket: gotopia.tech (https://gotopia.tech) 

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR YOUTUBE CHANNEL (https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1)  - new videos posted daily!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How China’s Xiaomi Beat Apple and Is Taking on Tesla</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i0Xrj1ILCHw</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/i0Xrj1ILCHw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 08:00:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Chinese smartphone giant Xiaomi may not be a household name globally, but it’s succeeded where Apple failed by launching its own electric car. That’s a feat Apple couldn't accomplish despite a decade of effort and billions of dollars spent. Now, Xiaomi is turning its sights to Tesla.

Bloomberg Originals explains why Xiaomi is betting big on EVs.

00:00 Introduction
01:41 What is Xiaomi 
03:46 Why electric cars?
04:45 How the tech company did it
07:00 Why its cars are popular
08:12 China’s EV ecosystem
09:00 Xiaomi’s global ambitions 

#Xiaomi #EV #China #automotive #SU7 

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for $1.99/month for the first 3 months: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals

Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Are We Sending NUKES to the MOON??</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/bSsHi_6i4mY</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bSsHi_6i4mY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 21:29:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Andrew meets a Juggalo Hobo</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/9q90qGzNqMM</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9q90qGzNqMM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 21:19:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why We’re Putting Nuclear Reactors on the Moon</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RWL2efggMY0</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/RWL2efggMY0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 21:12:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://ground.news/startalk to stay fully informed on the latest Space and Science news. Save 40% off through our link for unlimited access to the Vantage plan this month.

Why are we putting nuclear reactors on the moon? Neil deGrasse Tyson breaks down NASA’s plan to put nuclear power on the moon and The Artemis Mission’s plan to establish a base there. Are we in a new space race? 

Timestamps:
00:00 - What’s Up With Nuclear Reactors on the Moon? 
2:10 - The New Space Race
4:43 - Establishing a Base with the Artemis Program
8:58 - Why a Station on the Moon? 
10:20 - Why We’re Targetting the South Pole

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Victors And The Defeated | End Of The War In Color Uncensored Episode 05</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PAvkOn2mVfI</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/PAvkOn2mVfI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 21:00:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[We look at the aftermath of World War II in Berlin in July 1945, from the destruction of Berlin and the Allied occupation to the struggles of Berliners - especially women - to rebuild their lives amid ruins, rationing, and uncertainty about the city's future. This episode also covers the Soviet victory parade in Moscow and the tense beginning of Allied negotiations at the Potsdam Conference to decide Germany's and Europe's fate.

Do you love uncovering the past, exploring historic sites, and venturing to distant lands? Join History Hit today and stream hundreds of exclusive documentaries, with new releases every week. Plus, enjoy ad-free access to our podcast network for even more history every week.

Head over to https://bit.ly/45CPh5u to embark on your journey through history!

This channel is part of the Little Dot Studios Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We Asked the Public Who’s To Blame for the Medieval Plague</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zBVpeZe94Fs</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/zBVpeZe94Fs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 19:01:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">History Hit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Rats? Children? The Mongols? The Black Death swept across the world with terrifying speed, but who (or what) was really to blame?

Louise Quick, with the help of the public and medieval historians Dr Eleanor Janega and Helen Carr, is on a mission to uncover the true culprit behind one of the deadliest pandemics in human history: the Black Death.

0:00 - What was the Black Death?
6:58 - The Rat Myth: Were Rodents to Blame?
12:37 - Poor Hygiene & Medieval Sanitation Myths
20:34 - How Global Trade Spread the Plague
27:00 - Ancient Biological Warfare: The Mongol Theory
34:21 - The Final Verdict: Who was Responsible?

Discover the past on History Hit with ad-free exclusive podcasts and documentaries released weekly presented by world renowned historians Dan Snow, Suzannah Lipscomb, Lucy Worsely, Mary Beard and more. Watch, listen and read history wherever you are, whenever you want it. Available on all devices: Apple TV, Amazon Prime Video, Android TV, Samsung Smart TV, Roku, Xbox, Chromecast, and iOs & Android.

If you'd like to watch more great history content like this head on over to History Hit using the following link https://eu1.hubs.ly/H0gW80Z0 to sign up to our History SVOD service.

#WhosToBlame #HistoryHit #BlackDeath #Medieval]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>🤯 Did #Horowitz play the BEST polonaise of ALL TIME?? 🏆 (ft. @jdistler2)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/FCfK96BEy6c</link><author>Ben Laude</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FCfK96BEy6c?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:58:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnSFlVqRyNfIJDsmpkcY57w">Ben Laude</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[🎵: CHOPIN Polonaise in F-sharp minor, Op. 44

Learn more: www.chopinpodcast.com

https://patreon.com/BenLaude/
https://instagram.com/benlawdy/
https://benlaude.com/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Gathering of the Hobos</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NJdriaH2Kgw</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NJdriaH2Kgw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:52:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://ground.news/channel5 to stay fully informed with all sides of every story. Subscribe for 40% off the Vantage plan through my link. 

If you'd like to watch 'Gathering of the Twins,' head to our Patreon - https://patreon.com/channel5 ..

And if you want tickets to our upcoming tour 'C5 Carnival,' head to  https://channel5.news/pages/carnival]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Who Has the Right to Vote in America? | Civics Made Easy</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=regpMUdl_QA</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/regpMUdl_QA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:01:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode of Civics Made Easy, Ben Sheehan uncovers the surprising – and often overlooked – true history of voting rights in America. From the founding era to Reconstruction to Civil Rights to today, this is the story that may not have been fully taught in school. Case in point: Americans don’t actually have a constitutional right to vote for president…

Whether you're a history nerd, a civic junkie, or just curious about how our democracy evolved, this deep dive will challenge what you thought you knew.

🔔 Don’t forget to like, subscribe, and hit the bell so you don’t miss future episodes of Civics Made Easy on PBS.

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

#votingrights #voting #law 

Civics Made Easy
Hosted by Ben Sheehan, breaks down the complex world of American government and civic participation. Each episode transforms intricate concepts into clear, digestible lessons, equipping viewers with the essential knowledge to actively participate in their democracy. Designed to empower and inform, the series makes understanding civics both accessible and engaging for all.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Superpower laughter - How humor makes us strong | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JWFPr2oaeVQ</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JWFPr2oaeVQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[We associate laughter with jokes or humor. Laughter is both contagious and a social behavior: people laugh 30 times more often in company. The documentary shows how neuroscience and psychology have discovered that humor makes us stronger.

In London, neuroscientist Sophie Scott has dedicated herself to researching laughter. "Laughter plays an important role in building and maintaining social relationships. It reduces stress and relaxes us. It is an important behavior to understand," she says.  This is why laughter is also interesting for psychology. A research team at the Alpen-Adria-Universität Klagenfurt is exploring how humor can help in psychotherapy. Humor strengthens the relationship between therapists and patients, which can actually reduce symptoms.

Others have also discovered the positive interpersonal effect for themselves: the "Humor hilft heilen" ("humor helps to heal”) foundation, founded by German doctor and TV presenter Eckart von Hirschhausen, conducts workshops in hospitals, among other places. Humor trainers teach nursing staff how to cope better with the everyday demands of their jobs. It's not about constantly cracking jokes. Rather, it’s about lightening interactions between nursing staff and patients.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #laughter #laughing 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Can saunas make you live longer? - Max G. Levy</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7c-OXc6H7us</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7c-OXc6H7us?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:00:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">TED-Ed</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Explore how saunas can affect your body, and dig into the health benefits and limitations of this millennia-old tradition.

--

Finnish sauna, Roman balneae, Japanese onsen, and Indigenous American sweat lodges are just a few examples of how cultures across the globe have long considered exposure to extreme temperatures therapeutic. But today scientists are only just beginning to unravel how and why this may be the case. So, what exactly is happening in your body when you feel the heat? Max G. Levy investigates.

Lesson by Max G. Levy, directed by Noam Sussman, Ali Kellner, Homework Studio.

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/can-saunas-make-you-live-longer-max-g-levy
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/can-saunas-make-you-live-longer-max-g-levy/digdeeper

Animator's website: https://www.homeworkstudio.ca
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! John Hellmann, Poompak Meephian, Chuck Wofford, Adam Pagan, Wes Winn, Conder Shou, ntiger, Noname, Hansan Hu, David D, Mac Hyney, Keith Ellison, robin valero walters, Lynne Truesdale, Gatsby Dkdc, Matthew Neal, Denis Chon, Julian Oberhofer, Monte Carroll, Eddy, Jay M, Constantino Victor Delgado, Andrea Galvagni, Andrew Tweddle, Laurel-Ann Rice, Fernando A. Endo, Helen Lee, pam morgan, sarim haq, Gerardo Castro, Michel-Ange Hortegat, Enes Kirimi, Amaury BISIAUX, ND, Samyogita Hardikar, Vanessa Graulich, Vandana Gunwani, Abdulmohsin Almadi, AJ Lyon, Geoffrey Bultitude, Mi Mi, Thomas Rothert, Brian Elieson, Oge O, Weronika Falkowska, Nevin Spoljaric, Sid Chanpuriya, Anoop Varghese, David Yastremski, and Noah Webb.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We Won’t Explore the Galaxy...</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/UNunBadMlHQ</link><author>Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UNunBadMlHQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q">Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[... but AI will. 

#kurzgesagt
#inanutshell #kurzgesagt_inanutshell #learnwithshorts #science #space #spaceexploration 

Sources & further reading: 
https://sites.google.com/view/kgs-tiktok-sources

Follow us for more sciencey content! 🦆

OUR CHANNELS
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
German:        https://kgs.link/youtubeDE
Spanish:        https://kgs.link/youtubeES
French:          https://kgs.link/youtubeFR
Portuguese:  https://kgs.link/youtubePT
Arabic:           https://kgs.link/youtubeAR
Hindi:             https://kgs.link/youtubeHI
Japanese:     https://kgs.link/youtubeJA
Korean:          https://kgs.link/youtubeKO


HOW CAN YOU SUPPORT US?
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
This is how we make our living and it would be a pleasure if you support us!

Get Products designed with ❤ https://shop.kgs.link/shorts
Become a Part of kurzgesagt by joining the Patreon Bird Army 🐧  https://kgs.link/patreon  


DISCUSSIONS & SOCIAL MEDIA
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Instagram:     https://kgs.link/instagram
TikTok:           https://kgs.link/tiktok
Reddit:            https://kgs.link/reddit
Discord:          https://kgs.link/discord
Twitter:           https://kgs.link/twitter
Bluesky:          https://kgs.link/bluesky
Facebook:      https://kgs.link/facebook
Newsletter:    https://kgs.link/newsletter


OUR VOICE
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
The Kurzgesagt voice is from 
Steve Taylor:  https://kgs.link/youtube-voice


OUR MUSIC ♬♪
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
700+ minutes of Kurzgesagt Soundtracks by Epic Mountain:

Spotify:            https://kgs.link/music-spotify
Soundcloud:   https://kgs.link/music-soundcloud
Bandcamp:     https://kgs.link/music-bandcamp
Youtube:          https://kgs.link/music-youtube
Facebook:       https://kgs.link/music-facebook]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How to Get People Excited about Functional Programming • Russ Olsen &amp; James Lewis • GOTO 2024</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0SpsIgtOCbA</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0SpsIgtOCbA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded at GOTO Copenhagen 2024. #GOTOcon #GOTOcph
https://gotocph.com

Russ Olsen - Author of "Getting Clojure" & "Eloquent Ruby" @russolsen3122 
James Lewis - Software Architect & Director at Thoughtworks

RESOURCES
Russ
https://bsky.app/profile/russolsen.bsky.social
https://hachyderm.io/@russolsen
https://github.com/russolsen
https://www.linkedin.com/in/russolsen
http://russolsen.com

James
https://bsky.app/profile/boicy.bovon.org
https://linkedin.com/in/james-lewis-microservices
https://github.com/boicy
https://www.bovon.org

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
00:53 How Russ got started with functional programming
05:55 Russ' new book
11:05 Clojure
14:46 Q&A
24:15 Misconceptions about functional programming
28:25 To the Moon
34:20 Q&A
37:34 Mechanical vs Software Engineering
38:23 Agile & TDD
40:28 Outro

Read the full abstract here:
https://gotocph.com/2024/sessions/3522

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Russ Olsen • Getting Clojure • https://amzn.to/3J8zI8s
Russ Olsen • Eloquent Ruby • https://amzn.to/37gOhcG
Russ Olsen • Design Patterns in Ruby • https://amzn.to/3r2uBjW
Barry O'Reilly • Unlearn • https://amzn.to/3O3DQeI
Jez Humble, Joanne Molesky & Barry O'Reilly • Lean Enterprise • https://amzn.to/3Cpt6ET
Sarah Wells • Enabling Microservice Success • https://amzn.to/4aa8xrv
Martin Fowler • Refactoring • https://amzn.to/3EVcHXQ
Matthew Skelton & Manuel Pais • Team Topologies • http://amzn.to/3sVLyLQ

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#RussOlsen #JamesLewis #Clojure #lisplang #Agile #TDD #ChaosEngineering #FunctionalProgramming #CategoryTheory #FPvsOOP #Programming #SoftwareEngineering #TodayInTech

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Was It Even Possible To Shoot Down A B-29?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/HQm1MFZ9sA8</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HQm1MFZ9sA8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 11:00:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Marchfeld, 1278: Europe&apos;s Most Decisive Medieval Battle</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JlIXPTeknXk</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JlIXPTeknXk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 21:00:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In 1278, a monumental battle occurred between Rudolph of Habsburg, the new German King, and Ottokar II, the Bohemian King of the Přemyslid dynasty, in Eastern Austria. The conflict between Rudolph and Ottokar had been building for five years, representing a final showdown between two powerful rulers who could not coexist. Rudolph's victory marked a turning point in European power dynamics, establishing the Habsburgs as a dominant dynasty with lasting political impact, particularly in Central Europe. Despite the enormous scale of the battle, few traces have been found, but archaeologists hope modern technology will unveil more details.

Do you love uncovering the past, exploring historic sites, and venturing to distant lands? Join History Hit today and stream hundreds of exclusive documentaries, with new releases every week. Plus, enjoy ad-free access to our podcast network for even more history every week.

Head over to https://bit.ly/45CPh5u to embark on your journey through history!

This channel is part of the Little Dot Studios Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>International adoptions - A global scandal | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pUUaGCP4j5Q</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pUUaGCP4j5Q?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:01:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In the last 60 years, over a million "orphans” have been adopted by Western families. Many of them are now discovering that their past is a lie. International adoptions are at the center of an unprecedented scandal.

This scandal is far-reaching. It involves children stolen from their mothers during the Pinochet dictatorship, as well as people described as Africa's "fake orphans”. The film follows investigative journalists, activists and researchers in South Korea, Sweden, France, Chile, Germany and Switzerland. How was this huge, lucrative market able to flourish? And why does it still exist today?

Even today, women are manipulated, threatened or deceived into giving up their babies - often with the blessing of state authorities. The fraudulent practices persist despite the Hague Convention, which has governed international adoption since 1993. That is because the system is flawed and encourages corruption.

In many cases, these practices come to light mainly due to pressure from adopted children who have grown into adults. After discovering the dubious conditions of their adoptions, they begin to search for their birth parents and demand explanations. These searches are often easier to conduct these days, thanks to social media, the Internet and the availability of genealogy websites.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #adoption #orphans 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We&apos;ve Never Seen a Comet Do This</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WsTuti1ezpc</link><author>Astrum</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/WsTuti1ezpc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-9b7aDP6ZN0coj9-xFnrtw">Astrum</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Comet 29P keeps exploding, and scientists are trying to figure out why. 
If you love learning about science as much as I do, head to http://brilliant.org/astrum to start for free. You'll also receive 20% off a premium annual subscription, giving you unlimited access to everything on Brilliant.

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Between Jupiter and Neptune lurks Centaur 29P, an icy comet that won't stop exploding. Its wild cryovolcanic outbursts can make it flare 300 times brighter in a matter of hours, but the reason for these random eruptions has long been a mystery. Now, recent discoveries from the James Webb Telescope have provided a clue to the secret trigger powering the chaos. Join us as we investigate the strange case of the solar system's most explosive comet.

▀▀▀▀▀▀

0:00 Exploding Comet
1:13 Centaur 29P
3:08 Violent Eruptions
5:19 Cryovolcanism
7:51 Predicting Eruptions
9:28 Jets of Gas
10:54 Amorphous vs Crystalline Ice
14:48 The Future

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Astrum's newsletter has launched! Want to know what's happening in space? 
Sign up here: https://astrumspace.kit.com 

▀▀▀▀▀▀
 
Astrum Displate Posters: https://astrumspace.info/Displates 
Astrum Infographic Artwork: https://electrify.art/collections/astrum  
Astrum Merch: https://astrum-shop.fourthwall.com/ 

Join us on the Astrum discord: https://discord.gg/TKw8Hpvtv8 

A huge thanks to our Patreons who help make these videos possible. Sign-up here to support the channel: https://bit.ly/4aiJZNF 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Astrum Podcast on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/6jPRrbq3o3dpvBb173ZTKi?si=a90d3efe3b704c83 

Astrum Earth: https://youtube.com/@AstrumEarth 
Astrum Extra: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumextra 

Astrum Spanish: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumespanol 
Astrum Portuguese: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChn_-OwvV63mr1yeUGvH-BQ 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

References:
"Massive eruption from icy volcanic comet detected in solar system", via livescience.com https://astrumspace.info/29Perupts
"CO Gas and Dust Outbursts from Centaur 29P/Schwassmann–Wachmann", via iop.org https://astrumspace.info/COoutbursts
"Our solar system’s centaurs are half-asteroid, half-comet", via astronomy.com https://astrumspace.info/centaurs
"NASA’s Webb Reveals Unusual Jets of Volatile Gas from Icy Centaur 29P" https://astrumspace.info/unusualjets29P
"Centaur 29P/Schwassmann-Wachmann 1 and its near-nucleus environment from a stellar occultation", via arxiv.org https://astrumspace.info/Centaur29P
"MISSION 29P – Centaur comet observing campaign news", via britastro.org https://astrumspace.info/29Pobservations
"This mysterious comet's super-bright outbursts have astronomers puzzled", via livescience.com https://astrumspace.info/strangeoutbursts
"Anatomy of outbursts and quiescent activity of Comet 29P/Schwassmann–Wachmann", via sciencedirect.com https://astrumspace.info/anatomyofoutbursts
"Centaur 29P Outgassing (NIRSpec)", via webbtelescope.org https://astrumspace.info/JWSTcentaur29P
"29P/Schwassmann–Wachmann 1: A Rosetta Stone for Amorphous Water Ice and CO :left_right_arrow: CO2 Conversion in Centaurs and Comets?", via iop.org https://astrumspace.info/29Picevolcano


▀▀▀▀▀▀

Credits:
Writer: Julia Masselos
Video Editor: Matheus L. Heberlê
Researcher: Edie Abrahams
Script Editor: Damaris McColgan
Thumbnail Designer: Peter Sheppard
Channel Manager: Georgina Brenner
Production Manager: Raquel Taylor
Head of Astrum: Jess Jordan
Creator of Astrum: Alex McColgan

With special thanks to:
NASA/ESO/ESA

#Astrum #Space #Comet #Centaur29P]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Have you tried Alligator? 🐊 #RecipePBS #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/EIIFdt83Ipo</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EIIFdt83Ipo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Coby shares a recipe for Alligator Sauce Piquante, a traditional Louisiana dish he has shared over the years with his Navy veteran brothers. His recipe for Alligator Sauce Piquante contains alligator meat, bell peppers, onions, tomato, andouille sausage and shrimp.

Made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app!

#cajun #louisiana #alligator #navy #veteran 

The Great American Recipe
An uplifting cooking competition that celebrates the multiculturalism that makes American food unique and iconic. Hosted by Alejandra Ramos, the series gives talented home cooks from different regions of the country the opportunity to showcase their beloved signature dishes and compete to win the national search for “The Great American Recipe.” Judges Tiffany Derry, Tim Hollingsworth and Francis Lam bring their professional insights and deep culinary knowledge to encourage and support the contestants along the way.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Untold Story of the Martini-Henry (Part One) with experts Neil Aspinshaw &amp; Jonathan Ferguson</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tjq4yj_mzuo</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tjq4yj_mzuo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 15:15:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Royal Armouries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In this special episode, Jonathan is joined by Neil Aspinshaw, noted author of The Martini-Henry: For Queen and Empire, to explore the fascinating variants of the experimental .402" calibre Martini-Henry.

Why did the British Army shrink the calibre from .450" to .402"?
What problems were they trying to solve after the Zulu, Afghan, and Sudan campaigns?
And how close did this “improved” Martini come to replacing the service rifle of its age?

This is Part One of a two-part story, join us again next week for the conclusion!

0:00 Intro 
0:21 Neil & For Queen and Empire
1:35 What is .402" Calibre and Why?
4:58 Issues with .450" Calibre
10:53 Martini-Henry 1881 Pattern .402"
14:15 Sights inc. New Hanging Sight
16:52 Hanging Sight (The Right Way Up...)
21:29 Ad-hoc Button Safety   
27:12 Martini-Henry 1883 Pattern .402"
29:30 Sandy Sudan Sensationalisation
32:40 Rifling 
34:09 Martini-Henry 1886 Pattern .402"
35:10 The Bayonet Scandal of '84
37:03 The 'Perfected' Enfield Martini
41:45 Safety 
44:23 Enfield Quick Loader
49:09 Conclusions
53:53 End of Part 1

Neil’s book: The Martini-Henry: For Queen and Empire – the definitive guide to this legendary rifle: https://martini-henry-society.myshopify.com/products/the-martini-henry-for-queen-and-empire-by-neil-aspinshaw-600009

#MartiniHenry #BritishArmy #FirearmsHistory #WhatIsThisWeapon

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>🤔 What’s a #Chopin thumb smash? 👍</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/AjYMdIXkLXQ</link><author>Ben Laude</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/AjYMdIXkLXQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 15:13:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnSFlVqRyNfIJDsmpkcY57w">Ben Laude</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Chopin Competition jury member Garrick Ohlsson breaks down the second of 16 ways that Chopin revolutionized modern piano playing.

https://patreon.com/BenLaude/
https://instagram.com/benlawdy/
https://benlaude.com/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Cannibalism Through the Lens of Cultural Relativism</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/tfVs6CEkS9U</link><author>Horses</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tfVs6CEkS9U?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 15:01:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrx2zrPjhGRi9TwszZiLwEg">Horses</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Find the full, uncensored version of this essay and more at: ⁠https://horses.land]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Reason The Allies Won WW2</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FwWDIfgkaH4</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FwWDIfgkaH4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 14:47:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This video takes an in depth look at the Second World War, the biggest conflict in human history. Why did the Allies win the war? Or might a better question be - why did the Axis lose it?

00:00 Why did the Axis lose?
00:36 Axis strategy
01:33 Allied strategy
02:27 War begins in Asia
03:01 War begins in Europe
3:59 Blizkrieg
5:28 The big problem
7:16 Germany invades the USSR
9:15 Japan attacks Pearl Harbor
10:59 The turning point
11:52 The war at sea
13:27 The air war
14:59 The land war
16:38 Endgame
18:31 Why the Allies won WW2

See our objects for yourself. Plan your visit to IWM London: 
https://www.iwm.org.uk/visits/iwm-london

Explore and licence the film clips used in this video: 
https://film.iwmcollections.org.uk/collections/_LaBPgM9g

Follow IWM on social media:
x.com/I_W_M
instagram.com/imperialwarmuseums
facebook.com/iwm.london
tiktok.com/@imperialwarmuseums

Credits:

Hitler in Paris image, Bundesarchiv, Bild 183-H28708 / CC BY-SA 3.0 DE https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/de/deed.en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Abalone, sharks and survival | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/TeQVsw_A8O8</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TeQVsw_A8O8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:01:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Pāua, New Zealand’s black foot abalone, is more than just seafood. To Māori, it’s taonga: a treasure from the god of the sea. And on international markets, it’s sold as a luxury delicacy. Abalone divers can make up to €200,000 a year. But diving for these sea snails isn’t easy – and it’s far from safe. Divers brave cold waters and life-threatening encounters with great white sharks. Would you risk your life for this kind of treasure? 

Watch the full documentary “Treasure islands in the Pacific - From the Chatham Islands to Enewetak (2/2)” on the DW Documentary YouTube channel.   

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #pacificocean #sharks #abalone 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Unforgiving Tools Help Your Programming Discipline with Michael Feathers</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/3Z1uq0Vj5Ys</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/3Z1uq0Vj5Ys?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 12:00:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out the full version on our YouTube channel now! #GOTOcon #SoftwareEngineering #Legacy #LegacyCode #Effectiveness #Testing #TDD #CodeQuality #CLangguage #Pascal #DDD #QA #ComputerScience #MichaelFeathers #ChristianClausen #Programming #ViralProgrammingShorts #Viral #ViralShorts #TodayInTech #GOTO

Full version available here:
https://youtu.be/P_6eDL1aqtA

Michael Feathers - Author of “Working Effectively with Legacy Code” &  Chief Architect at Globant

RECOMMENDED BOOK
Michael Feathers • Working Effectively with Legacy Code • https://amzn.to/3ZFQoMU
Christian Clausen • Five Lines of Code • https://amzn.to/3s2zjyg
Kent Beck • Test Driven Development • https://amzn.to/36kchvd

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Texas Democrat Rep. Nicole Collier was confined in the Capitol overnight #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/D5DAR_fDm7s</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/D5DAR_fDm7s?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 22:27:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Texas state Rep. Nicole Collier, a Democratic legislator, refused to sign a permission slip to allow around-the-clock escort from the Department of Public Safety. This was the latest event in a series of escalations between Texas Republicans and Democrats. Earlier in August, over 50 Democrats left Texas to stop the redrawing of congressional maps that would benefit the GOP. #texas #democrats #republicans #congress

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ark Royal: The Engineering Genius Behind WW2&apos;s Greatest Aircraft Carrier</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mxz1NjfVki4</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Mxz1NjfVki4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 21:00:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dive into the incredible history of HMS Ark Royal, the groundbreaking British aircraft carrier that redefined naval warfare in WW2. From her innovative design and construction challenges to her legendary battles against U-boats, the Luftwaffe, and the mighty Bismarck, discover why Ark Royal became the ship Hitler feared most. This documentary reveals the untold stories of courage and innovation that shaped the future of naval power.

Do you love uncovering the past, exploring historic sites, and venturing to distant lands? Join History Hit today and stream hundreds of exclusive documentaries, with new releases every week. Plus, enjoy ad-free access to our podcast network for even more history every week.

Head over to https://bit.ly/45CPh5u to embark on your journey through history!

This channel is part of the Little Dot Studios Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Who likes pineapple on pizza?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/Cn-8wT5bMCQ</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Cn-8wT5bMCQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 17:57:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Answering Questions About Our Flat Universe, If the Milky Stopped Rotating &amp; More</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qmfR2aXHLtg</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qmfR2aXHLtg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 17:55:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[If you crunched the asteroid belt into one object, would it make a planet? Neil deGrasse Tyson and cohost Chuck Nice answer fan questions about the shape of the universe, the origin of matter, the Casimir Force, pizza toppings, and more!

What are gluons and gravitons made of? Can a carbon atom orbit a human? Why do aliens always use Earth time in movies? We speculate whether aliens should use Earth time and whether cryopods make sense in relativistic travel.  Could binary star systems support stable planetary orbits?

We explore binary star systems, pizza topping debates, and the shape of the universe. Does the universe curve so that you would loop back to your origin? Neil breaks down time at the speed of light, the crushing gravity of neutron stars, and whether ships could harvest hydrogen from cavitation. Where does matter come from in the Many-Worlds interpretation? Is the entire universe expanding or just the observable part?

What happens if the Milky Way stops spinning? What is the Casimir Force, and why does empty space press metal plates together? If you crunched the asteroid belt into one object, would it even be a planet? We tackle whether time and space could have existed independently before the Big Bang, and close with advice for physics students navigating uncertain science funding.

Thanks to our Patrons Keith Edwards James Murphy, River Harlan, Dashing Design Diva, Zach Ross, Federico Varano, Mark Ballard, Andres Franco-Osorio, Pascal, Emmanuel Cooper, Silvester Dimitrov, Ryan Eldridge, Ricky Isbell, David Hall, Angela Johnson, Demetrius Goosbey II, Morris Griffing, Cole Carter, Adam Huber, J B, Don Bailey, Tom Reed, Aaron Palmer, Odin Drengr, Demba Mdoye, Clay Mattson, Jason aka asmrpeople, Sage, Angel Garcia, Richard Swenson, Rich Elkerton, Kirby Sorensen, Mike Kakeeh, Kodi, John Kremer, Dwayne Boychuk, Jordan Burnam, Brittany Johnson, Aidan M, jared higbee, Theo Chambers, Levi Furber, Kelly, Hubert Dąbrowski, Julio Cataño, StellarScout, Margot Lane, Joudi Saadeh, David Foy, Jacob Sopko, Dell Rabinowitz, and Dominic Strong for supporting us this week.

Timestamps: 
00:00 - Introduction: Grab Bag
01:26 - Energy in Gluons and Gravitons
04:08 - Can a Carbon Atom Orbit a Human? 
06:03 - Alien Time
11:30 - The Likelihood of 2001: A Space Odyssey
13:34 - Pizza Toppings Debate
15:09 - The Shape of the Universe
17:30 - Cryopods & The Speed of Light
20:26 - A Spoonful of Neutron Star
22:09 - Collecting Hydrogen and Oxygen from Cavitation
26:55 - Where Does Matter Come from in Parallel Universes? 
28:43 - Whole Universe vs. Observable Universe
30:57 - If the Milky Way Stopped Rotating
34:20 - The Casamir Force
38:42 - The Entire Asteroid Belt Clumped Together
41:13 - Could Space and Time Have Been Separate?
43:59 - The State of Science Funding

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Portugal fights severe wildfires | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8u23r_y_J-A</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8u23r_y_J-A?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:07:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Innovative prevention policies are being implemented in Portugal to combat devastating forest fires. After the deadly wildfires that raged in 2017, the country developed measures that now serve as a model for other European nations.

André Mota is one of 31,000 volunteer firefighters in Portugal. He was called out on October 15, 2017, when a devastating wildfire reached the town of Santa Comba Dão, where he lives. The experience left a lasting impression on him. Today, he is responsible for civil protection in his home region of Viseu and coordinates prevention measures.
Growing up, Verónica Catarino witnessed wildfires firsthand. Today, she heads up a special training program at the national firefighting school, where she teaches students how meteorological and geographical factors influence wildfires.
Miguel Jerónimo works for the NGO GEOTA, supporting reforestation projects across Portugal. Part of his job involves clearing areas of eucalyptus trees - especially in the southern region of Algarve - and planting native species such as cork oaks, strawberry bushes and chestnut trees, because mixed forests are more resilient against fire.

#documentary  #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #portugal #wildfire 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mood lighting, mating, and murder: The scintillating lives of fireflies - Emily A. Geest</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XsFP8fpuQR4</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XsFP8fpuQR4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">TED-Ed</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dig into the science of how and why fireflies glow, and how their bioluminescent signals differ between males and females.

--

The first firefly is thought to have lived over 100 million years ago, illuminating the night with a glowing green light. And today, there are around 2,000 firefly species, found all over the world, from forests and grasslands to marshes and deserts. So, why do these insects glow? Emily A. Geest digs into the bioluminescent signals of fireflies.

Lesson by Emily A. Geest, directed by Lou Morton.

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/what-makes-fireflies-light-up-at-night-emily-a-geest
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/what-makes-fireflies-light-up-at-night-emily-a-geest/digdeeper

Animator's website: https://louisjmorton.com/Films-Index
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! Sandra Tersluisen, Zhexi Shan, Bárbara Nazaré, Andrea Feliz, Victor E Karhel, Sydney Evans, Latora, Noel Situ, emily lam, Sid, Niccolò Frassetto, Mana, I'm here because of Knowledge Fight Facebook group., Linda Freedman, Edgardo Cuellar, Jaspar Carmichael-Jack, Michael Burton, VIVIANA A GARCIA BESNE, The Vernon's, Olha Bahatiuk, Jesús Bíquez Talayero, Chels Raknrl, Sai Pranavi Jonnalagadda, Stuart Rice, Jing Chen, Vector-Dopamine math, Jasper Song, Giorgio Bugnatelli, Chardon, Eddy Trochez, OnlineBookClub.org, Eric Shear, Leith Salem, Omar Hicham, Adrian Rotaru, Brad Sullivan, Karen Ho, Niklas Frimberger, Hunter Manhart, Nathan Nguyen, Igor Stavchanskiy, James R DeVries, Grace Huo, Diana Huang, Chau Hong Diem, Orlellys Torre, Corheu, Thomas Mee, Maryann H McCrory, and Blas Borde.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Drug To Master Reality</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u4LUix-BU0s</link><author>Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/u4LUix-BU0s?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q">Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://brilliant.org/nutshell/ to dive deeper into these topics and more for free + get 20% off the premium subscription! 
This video was sponsored by Brilliant. Thanks a lot for the support!

🚨 IT’S HERE! The LIMITED EDITION Alien Alert Pin just dropped on the kurzgesagt shop: https://shop.kgs.link/AcceptMission
Keep it close. Watch the light. If it turns red, whatever you do, do NOT ignore it. Humanity is counting on you.

Sources & further reading:
https://sites.google.com/view/sources-amphetamines/

From study sessions to dance floors, amphetamines can feel like a shortcut to superhuman focus and energy. Why do they work so well? What happens to your body once you take them? And what toll does it take on your health?


OUR CHANNELS
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
German:        https://kgs.link/youtubeDE
Spanish:        https://kgs.link/youtubeES
French:          https://kgs.link/youtubeFR
Portuguese:  https://kgs.link/youtubePT
Arabic:           https://kgs.link/youtubeAR
Hindi:             https://kgs.link/youtubeHI
Japanese:     https://kgs.link/youtubeJA
Korean:          https://kgs.link/youtubeKO


HOW CAN YOU SUPPORT US?
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
This is how we make our living and it would be a pleasure if you support us!

Get Products designed with ❤️ https://shop.kgs.link
Join the Patreon Bird Army 🐧  https://kgs.link/patreon  


DISCUSSIONS & SOCIAL MEDIA
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Instagram:     https://kgs.link/instagram
TikTok:           https://kgs.link/tiktok
Reddit:            https://kgs.link/reddit
Discord:          https://kgs.link/discord
Twitter:           https://kgs.link/twitter
Bluesky:          https://kgs.link/bluesky
Facebook:      https://kgs.link/facebook
Newsletter:    https://kgs.link/newsletter


OUR VOICE
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
The kurzgesagt voice is from 
Steve Taylor:  https://kgs.link/youtube-voice


OUR MUSIC ♬♪
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
700+ minutes of kurzgesagt soundtracks by Epic Mountain:

Spotify:            https://kgs.link/music-spotify
Soundcloud:   https://kgs.link/music-soundcloud
Bandcamp:     https://kgs.link/music-bandcamp
Youtube:          https://kgs.link/music-youtube
Facebook:       https://kgs.link/music-facebook

The soundtrack of this video:
SoundCloud: https://bit.ly/4lAMQpY
Bandcamp: https://bit.ly/4fIIwnd

If you want to help us caption this video, please send subtitles to subtitle@kurzgesagt.org
You can find info on what subtitle files work on YouTube here:
https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2734698?hl=en-GB&ref_topic=7296214
Thank you!


🐦🐧🐤 PATREON BIRD ARMY 🐤🐧🐦
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Many thanks to our wonderful Patreons (from http://kgs.link/patreon) who support us every month and made this video possible:
frazer hughes, Joshua, Harri, Rene Wende, Panda, PenguinDutchman710, Leo McGill, Sean Sands, TGMChrist, Chris, Keaton Ramjit, 최정훈, cheng cheng, Berglind Rúnarsdóttir, Iulius Cheesar, Slyreus, Mohamad Nossier, Prakarn Nisarat, Thoa Nong, Bruno Bröcker, Gaël Beck, Lexi Baugher, Freddie, Emmanuel Russell, Sebastian Colantoni]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Building Bridges: From Developer to Developer Advocate • David Edoh-Bedi &amp; James Beswick</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1T3w7UxeNMo</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1T3w7UxeNMo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 12:21:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for GOTO Unscripted.
https://gotopia.tech

Read the full transcription of this interview here
 (https://gotopia.tech/articles/368) 
David Edoh-Bedi - Developer Relations at Stripe
James Beswick - Head of Developer Relations at Stripe

RESOURCES
David
https://x.com/edohbedi_d
https://www.linkedin.com/in/edohbedi
https://edoh-bedi.com

James
https://bsky.app/profile/jbesw.bsky.social
https://twitter.com/jbesw
https://linkedin.com/in/jamesbeswick

Links
https://stripe.dev

DESCRIPTION
James Beswick (Head of Developer Relations at Stripe) talks with David Edoh-Bedi (Developer Advocate) about his professional journey from growing up in Togo to working at Microsoft and eventually Stripe.

The conversation explores David's transition from software engineering to developer advocacy, highlighting the importance of empathy, communication skills, and technical knowledge in the role.
They discuss the challenges of working with large legacy systems, the complexities of payment processing, and how the software development landscape has evolved from library-focused development to API-centric approaches.

The interview provides valuable insights for developers considering a career path in developer relations and those integrating complex systems like payment processing into their applications.

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Simon Brown • Software Architecture for Developers Vol. 2
 (https://leanpub.com/visualising-software-architecture) David Farley • Modern Software Engineering
 (https://amzn.to/3GI468M) Kim, Humble, Debois, Willis & Forsgren • The DevOps Handbook
 (https://amzn.to/47oAf3l) Simon Wardley • Wardley Maps
 (https://amzn.to/45U8Upr) Simon Wardley • Wardley Mapping, The Knowledge
 (https://amzn.to/3XQEeDu) David Anderson, Marck McCann & Michael O'Reilly • The Value Flywheel Effect
 (https://amzn.to/3VcHxC) Mike Amundsen • Restful Web API Patterns & Practices Cookbook
 (https://amzn.to/3C74fpH) 
CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1


Bluesky (https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com) 
Twitter (https://twitter.com/GOTOcon) 
Instagram (https://www.instagram.com/goto_con) 
LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-) 
Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences) 

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket: gotopia.tech (https://gotopia.tech) 

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR YOUTUBE CHANNEL (https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1)  - new videos posted daily!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Germany Was TERRIFIED Of The Mosquito</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/sXrnaf5TwM8</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/sXrnaf5TwM8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 11:01:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Can you swim in shade balls?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/zQ2ZJuUJeyo</link><author>Veritasium</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/zQ2ZJuUJeyo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 08:35:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA">Veritasium</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[I bought 10,000 shade balls and tried to swim in them. 

They appear to act like a non-Newtonian fluid: rigid under high shear stress, but they flow like a liquid under low shear.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Battle Erupts Over Brooklyn’s Industry City | Full Documentary | POV | PBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbJqZBE7Lwg</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vbJqZBE7Lwg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 01:30:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Residents of Sunset Park, Brooklyn face rising rents, a legacy of environmental racism and the loss of the industrial jobs that once sustained their community. When a global developer purchases a massive industrial complex on the waterfront and lays plans for an “innovation district,” a battle erupts over the future of the neighborhood and of New York City itself. 

Emergent City | POV

Discover more about this documentary: https://www.pbs.org/pov/films/emergentcity/

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW PBS:
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/pbs/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS
Shop: https://shop.pbs.org/

FOLLOW POV
Facebook: https://facebook.com/povdocs
X: https://twitter.com/povdocs
Instagram: https://instagram.com/povdocs

#documentary #nyc #brooklyn #housing 

POV (@povborders) 
POV (a cinema term for “point of view”) is television’s longest-running showcase for independent nonfiction films. POV premieres 14-16 of the best, boldest and most innovative programs every year on PBS. Since 1988, POV has presented over 500 films to public television audiences across the country. POV films are known for their intimacy, their unforgettable storytelling and their timeliness, putting a human face on contemporary social issues.

This film was co-produced with ITVS.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Lost Art Of The Sword: The Story Of A Legendary Weapon</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cPDoSa3rNkg</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cPDoSa3rNkg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 21:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Medieval and Renaissance blade, a profound and beautiful object handcrafted by master artisans of old. An object of great complexity, yet one with a singular use in mind- it is designed to kill. The truth of the sword has been shrouded in antiquity, and the Renaissance martial arts that brought it to being are long forgotten. The ancient practitioners lent us all they knew through their manuscripts. As gunslingers of the Renaissance they were western heroes with swords, and they lived and died by them. Yet today their history remains cloaked under a shadow of legend.

Do you love uncovering the past, exploring historic sites, and venturing to distant lands? Join History Hit today and stream hundreds of exclusive documentaries, with new releases every week. Plus, enjoy ad-free access to our podcast network for even more history every week.

Head over to https://bit.ly/45CPh5u to embark on your journey through history!

This channel is part of the Little Dot Studios Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>WW2&apos;s Deadliest Weapons: Allies vs Axis</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=itgAO64EcWU</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/itgAO64EcWU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 19:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">History Hit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Firearms Expert Jonathan Ferguson teams up with historian Luke Tomes to shoot some of the most iconic weapons of the Second World War belonging to the German Wehrmacht, US, British and Soviet Armies. 

Discover the past on History Hit with ad-free exclusive podcasts and documentaries released weekly presented by world renowned historians Dan Snow, Suzannah Lipscomb, Lucy Worsely, Mary Beard and more. Watch, listen and read history wherever you are, whenever you want it. Available on all devices: Apple TV, Amazon Prime Video, Android TV, Samsung Smart TV, Roku, Xbox, Chromecast, and iOs & Android.

If you'd like to watch more great history content like this head on over to History Hit using the following link https://eu1.hubs.ly/H0gW80Z0 to sign up to our History SVOD service.

#ww2history #ww2weapons #jonathanferguson 

00:00:00 GERMAN ARMY WEAPONS
00:01:58 Luger P08
00:12:36 Karabiner 98k
00:24:15 StG 44
00:34:33 MP 40
00:47:52 US ARMY WEAPONS
00:50:11 Colt M1911
01:00:58 M1903 Springfield Sniper Rifle
01:07:25 M1 Garand
01:15:57 M1 Thompson
01:32:29 SOVIET ARMY WEAPONS
01:34:52 Tokarev TT-33 Pistol
01:45:50 Mosin-Nagant Bolt-Action Rifle
01:59:44 PPSh-41 
02:12:10 Degtyaryov 'DP' MG
02:24:14 BRITISH ARMY WEAPONS
02:26:27 Webley Revolver Mk VI
02:36:05 Lee-Enfield No. 4 Mk I Bolt-Action Rifle
02:46:03 Sten Gun Mk II
02:56:45 Bren LMG]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>#GarrickOhlsson: How #Chopin changed the piano forever 🎹💥</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/8iaHzry12_M</link><author>Ben Laude</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8iaHzry12_M?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 18:33:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnSFlVqRyNfIJDsmpkcY57w">Ben Laude</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Chopin Competition jury member Garrick Ohlsson breaks down the first of 16 ways that Chopin revolutionized modern piano playing.

https://patreon.com/BenLaude/
https://instagram.com/benlawdy/
https://benlaude.com/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>This Dinosaur Courtship Could Break Bones | Walking with Dinosaurs (1999) | BBC Earth Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LRP1Ef0WDkw</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LRP1Ef0WDkw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 15:00:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This female Diplodocus is finally large and strong enough to mate. As the season begins, colossal male dinosaurs battle for her attention. And the winner earns the chance to pass on his genes...

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

This clip is taken from Walking with Dinosaurs (1999).

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>So, what exactly is the “New Right?” | The Gray Area</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OUaKLRO33-I</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/OUaKLRO33-I?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A loose movement of radical intellectuals is driving American politics.  They’re called the “New Right,” and they share a basic hostility to American liberal democracy, a real desire to fundamentally overhaul it, and real influence in the White House. But why do they think that? How much influence do they really have? And what would a response to their rising prominence look like?

Today’s guest is Laura Field, a political theorist who’s spent a lot of time in the conservative intellectual world cataloging the wild world of far-right thinking for her book Furious Minds: The Making of the MAGA New Right.

She speaks with guest host Zack Beauchamp, author of Vox newsletter On The Right, about why ordinary Americans should really, definitely, and absolutely care what a handful of thinkers are putting out on obscure Substacks and YouTube channels.

Subscribe to our channel! http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on Facebook: http://goo.gl/U2g06o
Or Twitter: http://goo.gl/XFrZ5H]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>