<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Youtube</title><link>https://konrad.website/liveboat-github-runner/</link><description></description><item><title>How One Trump Ally May Make Billions on Public Land</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0TIVKBpfj1w</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0TIVKBpfj1w?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 2 Mar 2026 09:00:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Pentagon is pushing to develop a domestic supply of antimony, a metal critical to making ammunition that’s often found alongside gold. That could be a bonanza for billionaire hedge fund manager and Donald Trump supporter John Paulson, whose company owns a key Idaho mine.

Read more about Paulson and the Stibnite gold mine here on Bloomberg: https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2025-12-19/billionaire-john-paulson-gets-a-gold-mine-in-us-s-critical-minerals-rush

#Trump #Gold #Military #USMilitary #China #US #Antimony
--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>You Can&apos;t Feel Wet</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/DJ_5_JS9_Rs</link><author>Veritasium</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DJ_5_JS9_Rs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 2 Mar 2026 02:00:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA">Veritasium</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Put on a glove and dip your hand into icy water. You'll notice it still feels wet? 

But the glove is waterproof, how does this work?

That's because wet isn't a feeling, we use other sensory information to feel water...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Erich Isselhorst: The Hunt For The Nazi Doctor Who Tortured Allied Spies</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G37S8qg1TFE</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/G37S8qg1TFE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 22:00:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Discover the chilling true story of the hunt for Dr Erich Isselhorst and Dr. Werner Rohde, the infamous Nazi doctors responsible for the horrific executions of British SAS and SOE agents at Natzweiler concentration camp. Major Bill Barkworth and Vera Atkins lead a relentless, clandestine investigation across postwar Germany to bring them and other Nazi war criminals to justice. This documentary unearths the grotesque details of these WWII atrocities, from lethal injections to burning bodies, revealing the grim determination required to expose those who committed unspeakable acts behind enemy lines. 

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson on Obama’s civil rights legacy</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/45znHNR7MKI</link><author>FRONTLINE PBS | Official</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/45znHNR7MKI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 22:00:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3ScyryU9Oy9Wse3a8OAmYQ">FRONTLINE PBS | Official</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[“It’s one of those mountain peak moments in American history.” In an interview with FRONTLINE for “The Choice 2008,” the Rev. Jesse Jackson reflected on Barack Obama’s historic presidential candidacy and the moments in history that led up to it. Funeral services for Jackson, who died earlier this month, are being held throughout this week.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rep. Ro Khanna on Iran and the War Powers resolution #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/sHnijFPL5lk</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/sHnijFPL5lk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 21:06:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[“This is exactly what Donald Trump ran against. He said, ‘No more endless wars.’”

Democratic Rep. Ro Khanna of California talked with Vox’s Astead Herndon ahead of this weekend’s strikes on Iran about the War Powers Act, which would force the White House to seek congressional approval before any type of military offensive.  

You can watch their full interview wherever you get your podcasts or here on YouTube.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Shia LaBeouf bursts into tears at mention of Jesus</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/Tjq6RnQNW2Q</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Tjq6RnQNW2Q?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 21:02:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Shia LaBeouf on the Epstein Files</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/zpgGXYzQge8</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/zpgGXYzQge8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 18:44:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How is ADHD different for women and girls? #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/sHItspuk6C0</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/sHItspuk6C0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 18:01:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[It turns out not all ADHD symptoms are created equal. While boys have more overt symptoms like hyperactivity and impulsivity, girls’ symptoms are often more internal, like a lack of focus or disorganization. This can lead to girls being underdiagnosed for ADHD compared to their male peers. 

“The symptoms that girls often experience aren't leading teachers to call home. Those are not the things that are leading teachers to express concerns,” said Dr. Julia Schechter, a clinical psychologist and associate professor at the Duke University School of Medicine, who runs the Duke Center for Girls and Women with ADHD.

Explain It to Me host Jonquilyn Hill spoke with Dr. Schechter to find out more about why women and girls are less likely to have their ADHD acknowledged. 

Learn more by tuning into Explain It to Me wherever you get your podcasts. 

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The fate of bull calves - From surplus to Alpine savior | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Q0rmr1tlBc</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6Q0rmr1tlBc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[For a cow to produce milk, she must give birth to a calf. Female calves later become dairy cows themselves, while male calves are surplus to the dairy industry’s requirements. They’re packed into trucks and suffer in transit on their way to fattening facilities.

Cows must calve once a year to produce milk. However, male calves are unwanted, considered waste products of the dairy industry. They’re often sent to fattening farms, mostly outside the EU. A farmer, a scientist and a butcher want to change this. Instead of sending the animals to factory farms where they’re fattened with soy or corn, the bull calves are sent to the pastures and alpine meadows of the Alps.
 
Along with a small group of farmers, restaurateurs and retailers, dairy farmer Marcel Renz is trying to change the dairy system in southern Germany. He wants to improve animal welfare, shorten transport distances and produce good quality meat that customers are willing to pay a little more for.

For people who buy their meat from butcher Hannes Hönegger, this is a positive. The butcher works with small, traditional organic farms that rely on what’s known as dual-purpose breeds, animals not bred solely for performance. Here, cows and calves are suitable for both milk and meat production, just as they were in the past. They feed almost exclusively on what grows in the pastures. In this way, they also contribute to the protection of nature in the Alps - from the Allgäu to South Tyrol.
 
Thomas Zanon's bull calves are among the lucky ones. No long journeys, no fattening with soya or maize. Instead, they graze on his mountain pasture - a small herd that he’s rescued from the dairy industry. Thomas Zanon's main job is as an assistant professor of livestock farming at the University of Bolzano in Italy. Taking all factors into account, he says, milk is by no means inferior to milk substitutes made from oats or soya. The rescued bull calves on his alpine pasture are not only happy animals: They also embody a new approach to sustainable milk production.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Unluckiest Coincidence Of The Civil War</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tT2xB0qzXCo</link><author>Weird History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tT2xB0qzXCo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 15:01:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc-N24Y5OA0gqbjBwe1ttfA">Weird History</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sometimes fate has strange designs on the lives of mortal men. You think you’re just a wholesale grocer one day and the next? You have a front row seat to the largest domestic military conflict in American history.  And that’s exactly what happened to a man named Wilmer McLean… who holds the bizarre distinction of owning the property where the Civil War began, and the property where the Civil War ended…

Be sure to subscribe to the Weird History Newsletter: https://bit.ly/WeirdHistoryNews

#civilwar #abrahamlincoln #civilwarhistory #weirdhistory #manassas]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Shia LaBeouf sits down with Andrew</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/CnIApxK7tbU</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CnIApxK7tbU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 14:57:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Boxes Are Easy. Arrows Are Hard. What Software Architecture Really Is About – @samnewman4355</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/vuUV1mHXtsM</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vuUV1mHXtsM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 13:01:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out the full version on our YouTube channel now! #GOTOcon #SamNewman #SoftwareArchitecture #Asynchronous #EDA #EventDrivenArchitecture #Programming #SoftwareEngineering #TodayInTech #ViralProgrammingShorts #Viral #ViralShorts #TodayInTech #GOTO

Software architecture isn’t just boxes and diagrams — it’s the arrows between them.
A sharp take on synchronous vs asynchronous and request/response vs event-driven systems, and why debates like Apache Kafka vs GraphQL usually miss the real question.

Full version available here:
https://youtu.be/IawEKBxjs14

Sam Newman - Microservices Expert & Author of "Building Microservices" & "Monolith to Microservices" @samnewman4355 

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Sam Newman • Building Resilient Distributed Systems • https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/building-resilient-distributed/9781098163532
Sam Newman • Monolith to Microservices • https://amzn.to/2Nml96E
Sam Newman • Building Microservices • https://amzn.to/3dMPbOs

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The RAM Crisis Keeps Getting Worse</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-YNk9_e4pg4</link><author>ColdFusion</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-YNk9_e4pg4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 01:58:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC4QZ_LsYcvcq7qOsOhpAX4A">ColdFusion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Visit https://brilliant.org/coldfusion for 20% off a premium subscription.
In this episode we cover the insane supply shortage of RAM due to the AI buildout. It'll be the price and availability of a lot of consumer electronics over the next year.

Watch or listen to ColdFusion on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/1YEwCKoRz8fEDqheXB6UJ1


ColdFusion Music: 

https://www.youtube.com/@ColdFusionmusic
http://burnwater.bandcamp.com   

ColdFusion Socials: 

https://discord.gg/coldfusion
https://facebook.com/ColdFusionTV 
https://twitter.com/ColdFusion_TV 
https://instagram.com/coldfusiontv

Created by: Dagogo Altraide
Producers: Tawsif Akkas, Dagogo Altraide]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Shia LaBeouf on the Reason Behind His Arrest</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/IAcsM4dbBwg</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IAcsM4dbBwg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 00:53:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Shia LaBeouf on his Jail Experience</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/sdWuYnqWZhw</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/sdWuYnqWZhw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 22:49:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Real Saint Patrick: Fact vs Fiction</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NRhFYpqcIJ8</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NRhFYpqcIJ8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 22:00:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The true story of St. Patrick is a gripping saga of survival, transformation, and spiritual warfare. Kidnapped by pirates and sold into slavery, Patrick escaped only to return to the land of his captivity to challenge the powerful Druid elite. This documentary uncovers the historical man behind the icon, exploring how a former slave toppled ancient pagan traditions and laid the foundations for the Celtic Christian Church in a world of tribal violence and mystery.

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why didn’t Democrats release the Epstein files under Biden? #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/SIS-EOznEgM</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SIS-EOznEgM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 21:00:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[“They weren’t rushing to expose all of this.”

Democratic Rep. Ro Khanna of California tells Vox’s Astead Herndon that Democrats should have pushed harder to release the Epstein files during the Biden administration. 

You can watch their full interview wherever you get your podcasts or here on YouTube.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Trump’s case for the Iran war makes no sense #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/ILBV-kPgt2Y</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ILBV-kPgt2Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 19:27:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The US has launched a war on Iran. But why? The short answer is nobody really knows. Vox’s Zack Beauchamp explains why the incoherence at the heart of Trump’s latest, biggest war is particularly scary.

You can read more coverage: https://www.vox.com/politics/481028/us-iran-war-trump-case-israel

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Is AI Hiding Its Full Power? With Geoffrey Hinton</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l6ZcFa8pybE</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/l6ZcFa8pybE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:01:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://ground.news/startalk to stay fully informed on the latest Space and Science news. Save 40% off through our link for unlimited access to the Vantage plan this month.

T-Mobile 5G Home Internet. https://T-Mobile.com/HomeInternet

How did we go from digital computers to AI seemingly everywhere? Neil deGrasse Tyson, Chuck Nice, & Gary O’Reilly dive into the mechanics of thinking, how AI got its start, and what deep learning really means with cognitive and computer scientist, Nobel Laureate, and one of the architects of AI, Geoffrey Hinton. 

Hinton explains the fundamental shift from logic-based rule programming to the biological approach: building systems that learn the way a brain does. Learn about the history of computer science that led to the breakthroughs we have today. We break down the structure of artificial neural networks and the meaning of AI buzzwords like “deep learning” really mean. You’ll learn about the layering of data processing and how the first layer of neurons might detect a simple edge, the second a beak, and the third a bird’s head. 

Hinton explains the light bulb moment of backpropagation, the mathematical breakthrough using calculus to send force backward to strengthen previous connections. Is this a process we share with neural nets? We discuss whether AI thinks like us and explore why AlphaGo succeeded in beating us at our own game by generating its own data and whether LLMs will hit a ceiling as they run out of human-written text. Can AI reason? What does it mean for something or someone to think?

As the science turns toward the future, we tackle heavy questions regarding the massive energy demands of data centers and whether AI can reinvent solar technology to save itself. Hinton discusses the "Volkswagen Effect," where a model might strategically underperform to avoid being unplugged. We dive into consciousness to ask if subjective experience is just a byproduct of complex perception and if chatbots already possess it. What are the upsides as well as the downsides? The singularity isn’t imminent yet... but the "yet" is doing a lot of heavy lifting.

Thanks to our Patrons Kylie Jonasson, Bryan Pfeifer, Anton Couzens, Brad Smith, Jeffdrumseitz, Richard Vaughan, sSHEScience©, Ben Mondoux, Julien Ballez, Tom, Matteo Berlanda, Dr. Cool Young Booger Results Murray, Shawndra Hill, Mike Easter, Charles Shields, Xander-Tony Kehr, Chase Busha, Leah, Justin Harris, Stephen Schultz, Jason West, ImaPerson, Argie Weatherington, Ted Barnett, MD, Lizzie O'Grady, Kimja, Paul Baltatescu, Hanna Cantley, Bill Hoffman, FreddieAbdon, Trish, Muath, Timeless Angel, Dxly, Michael Fuery, Tom Hadrava, Guy Eran, Max Murphy, Cristy Nourash, Donita Buchheit, Kel, Screaming Firehawk, Patricia Churchland, Mikael Stenberg, Dale Duncan, Ghostpacho, Nathan Lehenbauer, James Schaedler, Andrew G, Samuel Sladkovský, Punished Leno, Chris L, George Papura, Miguel Basto, Brittney Starkey, David Rouisse, WTFbro Podcast, Marvin, Jason Driscoll, Yasyoc, Donte Jones, Trevor, Andrew, Jared Harrison, Terence Garrod, TheCrassDragon, Daithon Brown, Perkins, Brendan Gost, Daria Shkrabachenko, Tania Cortes Alonso, JD, Jacob Westman, Lacey Rae Castleberry, Isaac Castrillo, Eric Bouliane, Tim The Secular Humanist, João Sampaio, Aegor, Evan Schreier, Amanda Burris, Allen Arthur, Vikas Jain, Jeroen Wilms, Nathan Schepker, Sverre Moe, Ruth Crisp, Legend Omega, B Dubbz, Jay Youmans, Nite Stalker, Adrian Hungate, Marguerite Nesfield, Michael Engelman, Scott Donner, Diamir Elliott, Warsame Giuled, Kansas Dan, Rey Pierantoni, and Rick Servello for supporting us this week.

Timestamps: 
00:00 - Introduction: Geoffrey Hinton
03:00 - Approaches to Make and Intelligent System
07:19 - How Artificial Neural Nets Work
14:12 - Making a Neural Net By Hand
24:41 - Backpropigation Breakthrough
33:44 - Why AI Seemed to Arrive So Fast
34:39 - What is Thinking?
37:50 - Is AI Better at Learning? 
47:41 - Can We Humanize AI?
50:58 - Setting Up Guardrails
54:04 - Is AI Lying to Us? 
58:47 - Will AI Be the End of Us All?
01:00:51 - Does AI Hallucinate? 
01:04:36 - The Upside
01:08:13 - Will AI Create More AI? 
01:10:17 - AI Nuclear Winter: Will We Unite?
01:15:10 - 2024 Nobel Prize in Physics
01:16:44 - The Price of Replacing All the Jobs
01:22:50 - Achieving Consciousness
01:28:37 - The Work to Be Done Before the Singularity

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn
Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Africa - Hotspot of the Cold War | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OoGhXmDVv0Y</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/OoGhXmDVv0Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:00:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In the collective memory, the Cold War is the conflict between the United States and the Soviet Union. However, one thing is often forgotten: the two superpowers also set their sights on the African continent.

To this day, the Cold War is remembered as an East-West conflict that was fought in the form of proxy and guerrilla wars in Asia and Latin America. However, one aspect of this confrontation is often forgotten: the United States and the Soviet Union also set their sights on Africa, which became a new arena for their power struggle, against the backdrop of decolonization. 
Left-wing political forces gained strength in African countries in the 1960s. Moscow seized the opportunity and invested heavily in East African Somalia, for example. The situation was similar in Angola. And Moscow triumphed.
With Ronald Reagan as the new president, the United States began preparing its return to the African continent in 1981. The timing was favorable, as communism had been devastating in Africa: the collectivization of agriculture in Ethiopia, for example, led to a famine that cost 500,000 people their lives. 
As more and more African countries turned away from the Soviet model, Moscow could only stand by and watch. Ultimately, Mikhail Gorbachev's reforms could not prevent the collapse of the USSR in 1991.
The end of the East-West conflict offered many countries in Africa the opportunity to take control of their own destiny once again. However, to avoid being exploited and manipulated by world powers once more, the continent had to learn the lessons of the Cold War era.


#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How a Small Wine Importer Smashed Trump’s Tariffs</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ChdQciz1gns</link><author>Patrick Boyle</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ChdQciz1gns?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:30:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCASM0cgfkJxQ1ICmRilfHLw">Patrick Boyle</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out Even Realities ➡️ https://evenrealities.bio/1998a1

#EvenRealities#EvenG2#EvenR1#MyEvenG2#everydaydisplay#smartglasses#aiglasses#displaysmartglasses

In this episode, we explore the legal and economic fallout of the Supreme Court's landmark decision to strike down the "Liberation Day" tariffs, a move that has left the administration scrambling for a "Plan B". We dive into the "David vs. Goliath" story of VOS Selections, the tiny wine importer that successfully challenged the President's use of emergency powers, and examine why the new 10% flat-rate replacement may actually provide a competitive boost to China and Brazil while penalizing America's closest allies. From the bizarre world of "National Security Cabinets" to the $175 billion refund headache currently being exploited by "vulture" investors, we break down how tweeting out tariffs met its match in the U.S. Constitution.

Patrick's Books:
Statistics For The Trading Floor:  https://amzn.to/3eerLA0
Derivatives For The Trading Floor:  https://amzn.to/3cjsyPF
Corporate Finance:  https://amzn.to/3fn3rvC 

Ways To Support The Channel
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/PatrickBoyleOnFinance
Buy Me a Coffee: https://www.buymeacoffee.com/patrickboyle

Visit our website: https://www.onfinance.org
Follow Patrick on Twitter Here: https://bsky.app/profile/pboyle.bsky.social

Business Inquiries ➡️ sponsors@onfinance.org

Patrick Boyle On Finance Podcast:
Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/7uhrWlDvxzy9hLoW0EYf0b
Apple: https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/patrick-boyle-on-finance/id1547740313
Google Podcasts: https://tinyurl.com/62862nve

Join this channel to support making this content:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCASM0cgfkJxQ1ICmRilfHLw/join]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Shia LaBeouf Interview</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4K9RDZg4y7o</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4K9RDZg4y7o?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:26:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://ground.news/channel5 to stay fully informed with all sides of every story. Subscribe for 40% off the Vantage plan through my link.

And to buy tickets to the C5 Carnival, head to https://channel5.news/pages/carnival

FEB 28 - BOSTON, MA (Chevalier Theatre)
MARCH 1 - DETROIT, MI (Royal Oak Theatre)
MARCH 7 - ST. PAUL, MN (Fitzgerald Theatre)
MARCH 8 - SALT LAKE CITY, UT (Wiseguys Comedy Club)
MARCH 13 - CHICAGO, IL (Riviera)
MARCH 14 - PITTSBURGH, PA (Stage AE)
MARCH 15 - PHILADELPHIA, PA (Fillmore)
MARCH 20 - TACOMA, WA (Temple Theatre)
MARCH 21 - LOS ANGELES, CA (Wiltern)
MARCH 27 - SAN FRANCISCO, CA (PFA)
MARCH 28 - PORTLAND, OR (Roseland)
APRIL 2 - AUSTIN, TX (Paramount)
APRIL 3 - DALLAS, TX (Granada)
APRIL 4 - DENVER, CO (Paramount)
APRIL 11 - VANCOUVER, BC (Vogue)
APRIL 18 - ATLANTA, GA (Centre Stage)
APRIL 23 - EL PASO, TX (Lowbrow Palace)
APRIL 24 - PHOENIX, AZ (Celebrity Theatre)
APRIL 25 - SAN DIEGO, CA (Observatory)
APRIL 26 - ALBUQUERQUE, NM (El Rey)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How did the US opioid crisis start? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/3gDms3O7ZeA</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/3gDms3O7ZeA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The United States has a huge drug problem. Opioids have caused hundreds of thousands of deaths. While headlines often blame illegal drug trafficking by Latin American cartels, the crisis actually began 30 years ago, quite legally, in the United States.  

The Sackler family, former owners of Purdue Pharma, brought the highly addictive painkiller OxyContin onto the market, unleashing one of the greatest health disasters in US history. Using hundreds of sales reps, they pressured doctors in poorer areas to prescribe the drug. This is considered the first wave of the US opioid crisis.

In 2025, the Sackler family reached a deal to pay $7.4 billion over 15 years and give up all control of the company. They are also barred from selling opioids in the United States. The Sackler family has continued to deny any wrongdoing. 

Watch the documentary “Opioid crisis in the US - Parts 1 & 2” on our channel.

#dwdocumentary #dwdocs #US 
______

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rep. Ro Khanna wants Democrats to distance themselves from the “Epstein class” #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/HUZXKhtLegk</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HUZXKhtLegk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Democratic Rep. Ro Khanna of California is locked into two major issues: the Epstein files and artificial intelligence. 

He talked with Vox’s Astead Herndon about how Democrats need to distance themselves from the “Epstein class” and how the government needs to be doing more to regulate AI for this week’s Saturday episode of Today, Explained. 

You can watch their full interview wherever you get your podcasts or here on YouTube.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rep. Ro Khanna takes on the “Epstein class” | Today, Explained</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7ciJkd3R-yo</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7ciJkd3R-yo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 13:00:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Our politics are deeply divided — there’s Democrat vs. Republican, there’s left vs. right. But maybe the biggest divide in our politics is the insider vs. outsider divide.

That’s only gotten more noticeable in recent months, as issues like the Epstein files and artificial intelligence have pitted the elites against everyone else. Rep. Ro Khanna (D-CA) is at the center of both of those issues. He wrote the Epstein Files Transparency Act. He brought one of Jeffrey Epstein’s abuse survivors to this week's State of the Union address. And he’s coined the term “the Epstein class” — the group of wealthy and connected individuals that he wants to bring to accountability. Even if they’re fellow Democrats.

Khanna represents Silicon Valley in his district, so he has worked with companies like Google and Meta for years. That puts him at the forefront of one of the important political and economic questions of the coming year: Is AI about to put us all out of work? And is the government prepared to do anything about it?

00:00 Intro
1:52 Advocating for Epstein survivors
4:31 Forcing the release of the Epstein Files
5:23 Pushing for a vote on Iran strikes
6:32 Should Dems work with Trump?
9:41 Holding the “Epstein class” accountable
15:03 Should Dems have done more to stop Epstein?
18:10 Tech leaders and income inequality
19:03 Is there an AI tsunami?
19:42 Are Dems anti-AI?
22:00 CA tax on billionaires
23:56 Is Khanna making a presidential bid?

Today, Explained publishes video episodes every Saturday tackling key issues in politics and culture. Subscribe to Vox’s YouTube channel to get them. New episodes of Today, Explained drop every day of the week on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite listening app.

If you enjoy our reporting and want to hear more from Vox journalists, sign up for our Patreon at patreon.com/vox. Each month, our members get access to exclusive videos, livestreams, and chats with our newsroom.

Subscribe to our channel! http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on Facebook: http://goo.gl/U2g06o
Or Twitter: http://goo.gl/XFrZ5H]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The INSANE Firepower of HMS Invincible</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/GhugfJzZCGk</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GhugfJzZCGk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:00:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This is a clip from a 1980's Royal Navy instructional film. You can view the full film on IWM Film: https://film.iwmcollections.org.uk/record/34518 

#warships #navy #iwm #history #80s]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Angels 👼 VS. Demons 👹 in Chopin Scherzo 3</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/f5UTaoEZ_AM</link><author>Ben Laude</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/f5UTaoEZ_AM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 11:05:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnSFlVqRyNfIJDsmpkcY57w">Ben Laude</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[https://patreon.com/BenLaude
https://instagram.com/benlawdy/
https://benlaude.com/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ATK Hex80 review (Owlab Ti Magnetic)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=czI7ZKpDtFk</link><author>Chyrosran22</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/czI7ZKpDtFk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 06:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCD0y51PJfvkZNe3y3FR5riw">Chyrosran22</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Skip to 8:01 for a typing demonstration. 
Today we look the ATK Hex80, an interesting combination of a rather conservatively styled case with very showy keycaps and RGB. Hope you enjoy the video! :)

Intro by Kyle Carter
Outro by Facundo Cabanne

My keyboard reviews: http://bit.ly/1TbOtft
My switch teardowns: http://bit.ly/2C1QGHz
My TOP X videos: http://bit.ly/2FmpZfd
My XL typing demos: https://bit.ly/2OoAW3w
My tutorials and featurettes: https://bit.ly/2OrkLUh
My unboxing videos: https://bit.ly/2TSrr0m

I'm Thomas and I do videos and reviews on mechanical keyboards ranging from the most sickening modern RGB gaming keyboards to vintage hardware relics, or sometimes keycaps or keyswitches ranging from Cherry MX to Alps SKCM to IBM buckling springs and anything in between.

Follow me on Twitter for updates on my keyboard videos! https://twitter.com/chyrosran22

The practice sentence was: "Hello my name is Thomas and I'm typing on an ATK Gear Hex80 keyboard right now. This thing lights up like a Christmas tree even though the chassis looks so clean - an interesting idea!"]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Rev. Jesse Jackson on Barack Obama as a presidential candidate</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EqRZmzBheg4</link><author>FRONTLINE PBS | Official</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EqRZmzBheg4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3ScyryU9Oy9Wse3a8OAmYQ">FRONTLINE PBS | Official</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Rev. Jesse Jackson (1941-2026) was a civil rights icon who launched two U.S. presidential campaigns, in 1984 and 1988, ending the second run as the runner-up for the Democratic nomination — two decades before Barack Obama became the first Black major party presidential nominee, and subsequently, the first Black U.S. president.

Jackson spoke to FRONTLINE’s Jim Gilmore on Aug. 13, 2008, for our documentary, "The Choice 2008," which you can watch here: https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/frontline/documentary/choice2008/

This journalism is made possible by viewers like you. Donate to FRONTLINE now: https://bit.ly/47DFzCb

And support your local PBS station here: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Jackson had worked alongside the Rev. Martin Luther King, Jr. in the Southern Christian Leadership Conference, and was appointed to lead Operation Breadbasket, a program aimed at addressing economic concerns of Black Americans. In the years after King’s assassination, Jackson formed the Rainbow PUSH Coalition, a civil rights organization pushing for equity in the economic and political spheres for Black Americans. He died in February 2026 at the age of 84.

The interview has been edited for length and clarity. See a more complete description of our process here: https://to.pbs.org/4lVZKzA

This interview is being published as part of FRONTLINE’s Transparency Project, an effort to open up the source material behind our documentaries. Read more about this project here: https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/frontline/about-frontlines-transparency-project/

Explore more of our extended interviews in this playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL_pPc6-qR9ZzEepVsKZsT58XiLb38Tttr

#JesseJackson #BarackObama #USPolitics

Subscribe on YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/user/PBSfrontline
Sign up for our newsletter: https://frontline.org/newsletter
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/frontlinepbs
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/frontline
Bluesky: https://bsky.app/profile/frontlinepbs.bsky.social

FRONTLINE is produced at GBH in Boston and airs nationwide on PBS.

The editor-in-chief and executive producer of FRONTLINE is Raney Aronson-Rath.

Funding for FRONTLINE is provided through the support of PBS viewers and by the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, with major support from Ford Foundation. Additional support for FRONTLINE is provided by the Abrams Foundation, Park Foundation, John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, Heising-Simons Foundation, and the FRONTLINE Trust, with major support from Jon and Jo Ann Hagler on behalf of the Jon L. Hagler Foundation, and additional support from Koo and Patricia Yuen.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Firsthand Accounts Of The Thirty Years&apos; War</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dvDl5JaOHXI</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/dvDl5JaOHXI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 22:00:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In 1618, a comet appeared in the sky, signaling the start of the 30 Years War - the deadliest conflict in European history before the World Wars. This premium documentary explores the brutal reality of a continent torn apart by religious fervor and political ambition. Through the miraculous survival of Peter Hagendorf’s diary, we witness the harrowing journey of a mercenary surviving the plague, the bloody Battle of Lutzen, and the fall of legendary figures like Gustavus Adolphus and Wallenstein. This is the story of how modern Europe was forged in fire.

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rep. Ro Khanna on what’s in and out of the Epstein files #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/TfSYQrsKrRY</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TfSYQrsKrRY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 21:00:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A large share of the Epstein files may now be out in the public, but there are still plenty that remain unreleased. 

Vox’s Astead Herndon spoke with Democratic Rep. Ro Khanna of California who says  what has been released is “not a good look for the elite class.” 

You can watch their full interview on Saturday, here on YouTube.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Surprising Way Leopard Geckos Mate | Life in Cold Blood | BBC Earth Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O82SyuHI1zQ</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/O82SyuHI1zQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:00:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sir David Attenborough gives us unique insight into the leopard gecko's elaborate courtship routine and temperature-based sex determination of their eggs. 

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

Taken from: Life in Cold Blood (2008)

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Violence against women in India - A system of inequality | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sbWCiX_ys3s</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/sbWCiX_ys3s?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:01:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In India, more than 80 women are raped every day. This number is probably just the tip of the iceberg. In most cases, the crimes are not reported - whether out of shame, fear of the perpetrator, or mistrust of the police and the justice system.

In the west of the country, in the wealthy and conservative state of Gujarat, the story of 17-year-old Kinjal portrays an India in which rape is apparently considered a "trivial offense.” 
Three years ago, the young girl, who belongs to the Dalit community - a group considered "untouchables,” who occupy the lowest social status, at the bottom of the caste system -- was raped by the son of a landowner from a higher caste. 
To cover up the incident, the rapist's family offered Kinjal's parents land and 100,000 euros - a fortune. But Kinjal's father rejected the compromise, preferring to take the case to court. 
This rare act of courage was considered an affront by the higher castes. As a sign of his struggle, he decided not to cut his hair again until the perpetrator was convicted. 
Kinjal and her family were supported by Manjula Pradeep. The activist, who is also a Dalit, has dedicated her life to defending women who have been raped. Her goal, as yet unattained, is that each victim she helps will be the last. 
For six months, a camera crew accompanied Kinjal and her family in their search for justice. A glimpse behind the scenes in India, where the violence of the caste system and the weight of tradition determine the lives of hundreds of millions of women.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #india 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Most Shocking Moments In History | Compilation</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GSkKbe_Y96Y</link><author>Weird History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GSkKbe_Y96Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc-N24Y5OA0gqbjBwe1ttfA">Weird History</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[History is FULL of shocking moments. In the past, they were written about, then came video. Today we are offering a compilation of some of the more shocking moments in hour history - Wild events caught on Live TV, Shocking Facts about the Death of John Lennon, crazy deathbed confessions, and even getting into the history of Cannibalism! What do you find crazy in this world of ours? Let us know in the comments! 



Chapters: 
00:00:00 - 10 Most Shocking Events That Happened On Live TV 
00:10:11 - Shocking Facts About John Lennon's Death 
00:21:00 - The Original Wizard of Oz Books Are Shockingly Violent 
00:26:05 - The Shockingly Dark History of Chippendales 
00:37:31 - The Most Shocking Deathbed Confessions In History 
00:48:21 - Shocking Facts About the Space Shuttle Challenger Disaster 
00:59:07 - The Shocking History of Lipstick, The Outlawed Royal Cosmetic 
01:09:52 - The Shocking History of Cannibalism 

Be sure to subscribe to the Weird History Newsletter: https://bit.ly/WeirdHistoryNews

#shockingmoments #compilation #weirdhistory]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Gen Z men want kids (and women don’t) #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/grdT_YuL1cg</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/grdT_YuL1cg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:40:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The cliché is always that it's men who are afraid of commitment and having kids. But a Pew Research poll just shows that, for Gen Z, it's the women who are more hesitant to start a family. 

Is the "motherhood penalty" finally scaring women away, or are men just seeing family life through a different lens? Sean Illing and Anna North break down why the "lost generation" is suddenly so divided.

Listen to The Gray Area with Sean Illing on Mondays and Fridays wherever you get your podcasts or here on YouTube.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Gen Z men want babies. Gen Z women don’t. | The Gray Area</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k_tSL4L01i4</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/k_tSL4L01i4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:01:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A lot of Gen Z men sound surprisingly excited about fatherhood. A lot of Gen Z women…do not. 

And that divide — and the national handwringing about it — says a lot about the changing status of men and women in this country, and the uncomfortable realization that for American policymakers, not all children are created equal. 

Today’s guest on The Gray Area is Vox reporter and bestselling novelist Anna North, who covers kids, parenting, and American family life. She writes the Vox newsletter Kids Today, and her latest chart-topping novel is Bog Queen. She recently reported on the gap between young men and young women on parenthood and what that might tell us about gender roles, relationships, and the future of family formation in a politically polarized country.

Host: Sean Illing (@SeanIlling)
Guest: Anna North, Staff Writer, Vox

3:30 The poll that revealed a massive parenting gender gap in Gen Z.
11:20 Why "Tradwife" content and traditional values are finding a new audience.
15:43 The Gen Z family split
23:11 The "Care Crisis" and the trauma of modern immigration enforcement on children.
26:15 The future of the American family in 2026 and beyond.

We would love to hear from you. To tell us what you thought of this episode, email us at thegrayarea@vox.com or leave us a voicemail at 1-800-214-5749. Your comments and questions help us make a better show. 

And you can watch new episodes of The Gray Area on YouTube. New episodes drop every Monday and Friday.

Listen to The Gray Area ad-free by becoming a Vox Member: vox.com/members. 

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Subscribe to our channel! http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on Facebook: http://goo.gl/U2g06o
Or Twitter: http://goo.gl/XFrZ5H]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>SW Design, Architecture &amp; Clarity at Scale • Sam Newman, Jacqui Read &amp; Simon Rohrer</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vUL7iijIqes</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vUL7iijIqes?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:27:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This conversation was recorded at GOTO Copenhagen 2025.
https://gotocph.com

Sam Newman - Author of Building Microservices & Monolith to Microservices
Jacqui Read - Author of Communication Patterns: A Guide for Developers and Architects
Simon Rohrer - Global Head of Enterprise Tech Architecture and Ways of Thinking

ORIGINAL TALK TITLE
Software Design, Architecture & Giving Clarity at Scale

RESOURCES
Sam
https://twitter.com/samnewman
https://www.linkedin.com/in/samnewman
http://samnewman.io
http://samnewman.io/blog
https://github.com/snewman

Jacqui
https://bsky.app/profile/tekiegirl.bsky.social
https://jacquiread.com
https://fosstodon.org/@tekiegirl
https://www.linkedin.com/in/jacquelineread
https://github.com/tekiegirl

Simon
https://bsky.app/profile/simon.bvssh.com
https://mastodon.social/@simonr
https://x.com/sirohrer
https://www.linkedin.com/in/simonrohrer
https://github.com/sirohrer
https://www.soonersaferhappier.com

Links
https://acedmodel.com

ABSTRACT
In this session, we will explore the nature of software design - what is it, and where is the intersection with architecture? We’ll also look at the importance of communicating context, design, and architecture across an organization.

If you’d like to do some advanced reading, head over to acedmodel.com for more.

Both Jacqui and Simon will be sharing their expertise and experiences, but this session is also all about your questions. Come along, and get involved! [...]

Read the full abstract here:
https://gotocph.com/2025/sessions/3932

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Jacqui Read • Communication Patterns • https://amzn.to/3E37lvv
Sam Newman • Building Resilient Distributed Systems • https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/building-resilient-distributed/9781098163532
Sam Newman • Monolith to Microservices • https://amzn.to/2Nml96E
Sam Newman • Building Microservices • https://amzn.to/3dMPbOs
Jonathan Smart, Zsolt Berend, Myles Ogilvie & Simon Rohrer • Sooner Safer Happier • https://amzn.to/3Emm9p2


Bluesky (https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com) 
Twitter (https://twitter.com/GOTOcon) 
Instagram (https://www.instagram.com/goto_con) 
LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-) 
Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences) 

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket: gotopia.tech (https://gotopia.tech) 

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR YOUTUBE CHANNEL (https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1)  - new videos posted daily!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Trump&apos;s Tariffs Got a Reality Check</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0S35WwkQ6gQ</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0S35WwkQ6gQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:00:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Supreme Court’s ruling that Donald Trump illegally used an emergency law to launch his global trade war last April has thrown US trade policy into further turmoil. As the president scrambles to chart a new path, we look at what a year of threats, tariffs, retreats and deals both concrete and nebulous have accomplished. 

0:00 Introduction 
2:06 Supreme Court’s ruling
2:58 Refunds & prices
4:03 Trump’s economic goals
6:02 Foreign policy 
7:43 Midterms & what next

#trump #economy #supremecourt 
--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Neutrality At All Costs: Portugal&apos;s Dangerous Game In WW2</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W5UljWnMHlo</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/W5UljWnMHlo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 22:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Portugal managed to get through all of World War II without firing a single shot. Caught in a vise between the Axis and the Allies, Antonio Salazar, the country’s strongman, used every trick in the book to get his country through unscathed. In this war of nerves in which anything went, the Portuguese dictator took brilliant advantage of the only weapon available to maintain his country’s independence: neutrality.

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Casey Means and the no good, very bad month for MAHA #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/HWVwbfrq6IM</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HWVwbfrq6IM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 21:49:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Although the US is about to hit 1,000 measles cases — which puts us on pace to surpass last year’s total — President Donald Trump’s nominee for surgeon general, Casey Means, presented a wishy-washy stance on whether children should get the MMR vaccine at her confirmation hearing on Wednesday. 

This is a reflection on the greater MAHA movement, which initially grew popular because it was identifying some real concerns that many Americans have, but has now been taking some big losses that look increasingly out of touch as the nation’s public health situation deteriorates.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Was Epstein Behind QANon?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/w7vExJ0oRHY</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/w7vExJ0oRHY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 21:28:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Water Evaporates Even When It’s Cold</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fcKLK69wiQw</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/fcKLK69wiQw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 20:39:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Why does water evaporate when it's not boiling? Neil deGrasse Tyson and Chuck Nice break down Maxwellian Distributions of Velocities how particles move differently when adding heat. Is the universe one big mosh pit for particles? 

Timestamps:
00:00 - Maxwellian Velocity Distributions
00:31 - Gas Particle Most Pit
03:48 - Velocity Curves
04:29 - Evaporating Pools & Ice Cubes
07:11 - A Mixture of Gasses
09:13 - Nobody Talks About It
10:02 - Velocity Has Directions

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>shoutout bam</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/E-3g2vlZzNw</link><author>Horses</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/E-3g2vlZzNw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 19:52:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrx2zrPjhGRi9TwszZiLwEg">Horses</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New Scan of Titanic Wreck Reveals Secrets Hidden for a Century</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qW1R1_VpeoE</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qW1R1_VpeoE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">History Hit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Titanic scan reveals ground-breaking details of ship's final hours with @Magellan-gg 

Join historians Dan Snow and Tim Maltin as they delve into the Titanic’s wreck site, guided by Magellan’s cutting-edge 2022 scan.

Built from over 700,000 individual photographs, this extraordinary “point cloud” is the most detailed scan of the Titanic ever captured, offering everyone the opportunity to explore the wreck from the safety of their own homes.

Want to find out more about Magellan, the team behind these remarkable scans? You can find out more on the below links:

Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/MagellanLtd 

Magellan Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/@Magellan-gg/featured

And for those interested, you can dive in for yourself via the Titanic ROV Pilot on steam:

https://store.steampowered.com/app/3397800/vROVpilot_TITANIC/

00:01:24 The Stern
00:02:35 The Ship Splitting 
00:04:03 The Debris Field
00:04:52 The Handrail 
00:05:48 Port Holes
00:07:00 The Boilers
00:12:55 Lifeboat Davits
00:16:38 Cargo Cranes
00:19:32 Engine Cylinder 
00:22:52 Water Tank
00:24:15 Engine Room Hatch 
00:28:32 Steam Whistle
00:32:32 Recovery Basket 

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world-renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.

Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ/join

#titanic #titanichistory #titanicdisaster]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Is Uranus Actually a Rock Giant?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wKcMvR2C0oA</link><author>Astrum</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wKcMvR2C0oA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:08:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-9b7aDP6ZN0coj9-xFnrtw">Astrum</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[New discoveries about Uranus reveal something surprising hidden inside its core.
Join the adventure with Alex and discover more from DwarfLab at: https://bit.ly/3ObkGXK. And don't forget to use the code ASTRUM5 for 5% off!

▀▀▀▀▀▀

A rare alignment is approaching, offering a fresh opportunity to study Uranus. Although only visited once by Voyager 2, cutting-edge telescopes and modern data methods mean new discoveries are still pouring in. So what is really hiding beneath the clouds of this mysterious pale blue giant?

▀▀▀▀▀▀

0:00 Uranus Update
4:10 Ice Giant or Rock Giant?
6:44 Uranus’s Bizarre Storms
11:05 Coldest Planet?
13:03 Protoplanet Collision
14:39 Corkscrew Magneto-tail 
17:24 New Moons
19:19 Bullseye Rings
20:57 2025 Occultation

▀▀▀▀▀▀

To stay on top of space news, sign up to the Astrum newsletter: https://astrumspace.kit.com 
 
Astrum Displate Posters: https://displate.com/astrumspace?art=5f04759ac338b  
Astrum Merch: https://astrum-shop.fourthwall.com/ 

Join us on the Astrum discord: https://discord.gg/TKw8Hpvtv8 

A huge thanks to our Patreons who help make these videos possible. Sign-up here to support the channel: https://bit.ly/4aiJZNF 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Astrum Podcast on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/6jPRrbq3o3dpvBb173ZTKi?si=a90d3efe3b704c83 

Astrum Earth: https://youtube.com/@AstrumEarth 
Astrum Extra: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumextra 

Astrum Spanish: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumespanol 
Astrum Portuguese: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChn_-OwvV63mr1yeUGvH-BQ 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

References:
Uranus Facts”, via science.nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/uranusfacts 
“Icy or Rocky? Convective or Stable?”, via arxiv.org https://astrumspace.info/uranusinterior 
“Record-Breaking Storm Activity on Uranus in 2014”, via adsabs.harvard.edu https://astrumspace.info/uranusstorms 
“20-Year Hubble Study of Uranus Yields New Atmospheric Insights”, via science.nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/hubbleuranus 
“Solar Wind Heating for Uranus: Decades-Long Mystery Solved”, via imperial.ac.uk https://astrumspace.info/uranussolarwind 
“The Energy Balance of Uranus”, via academic.oup.com https://astrumspace.info/uranusenergy 
“Giant Impact on Early Uranus”, via iopscience.iop.org https://astrumspace.info/uranusimpact 
“New Moon Discovered Orbiting Uranus Using NASA’s Webb Telescope”, via science.nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/webburanus 
“Uranus: Rings of Dark Particles”, via jpl.nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/uranusrings 
“Planetary Alignment Provides NASA Rare Opportunity to Study Uranus”, via nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/uranusoccultation

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Credits:
Writer: Patricia Ward
Video Editor: Barnaby Egan
Researcher: Shourya Shrivastava
Script Editor: Damaris McColgan
Thumbnail Designer: Peter Sheppard
Publishing Lead: Georgina Brenner
Production Manager: Raquel Taylor
Edit Producer: Poppy Pinnock
Head of Astrum: Jess Jordan
Creator of Astrum: Alex McColgan

With special thanks to:
NASA/ESO/ESA

#Astrum #Space #Uranus]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ralph Waldo Emerson&apos;s Concept of Self Reliance</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/Zx6YKwkwPbI</link><author>Horses</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Zx6YKwkwPbI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrx2zrPjhGRi9TwszZiLwEg">Horses</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Find more at: ⁠https://horses.land]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Economic powerhouse China - How dependent is Europe? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jzu3uVPIRiE</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Jzu3uVPIRiE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:00:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[China is pushing into European markets - and striving for ever greater military power. This has already had an impact on the internal and external security of Western countries. How dependent is Germany on China?

Fancy some iced tea? It'll be delivered by drone. A tree falls onto the road? The driverless taxi swerves out of the way. The rapid development of artificial intelligence and automation in the megacity of Shenzhen shows how high-tech China is integrating innovation into everyday life. Digitalization is everywhere, in a country where administrative procedures are carried out via mobile phone. 
But the example of Shenzhen also shows that western countries are in danger of being left behind by China in key technologies such as AI, robotics and electric cars. 
Behind all this advancement lies a great deal of state planning - as well as possible attempts to exert influence. 
This film shows how China is creating economic and technological dependencies, for example when it comes to so-called "rare earths" and "technology metals.” These are not only indispensable for photovoltaics, wind power and robotics: Many armaments also depend on these raw materials, which are supplied almost exclusively by China.
Chinese manufacturers of batteries and electric cars are also focusing on Hungary as a location to conquer the European market. Factories are being built there, partly to circumvent EU customs duties. The country is actively courting Chinese investment. Within the EU, Hungary repeatedly blocks tougher measures against China. This is putting pressure on Germany's automotive industry.
The film explores the question of how dependent Germany is on China and what risks this poses for security and cyber security. What are the strengths and weaknesses of this global power? China competes with the US for leadership in the world, and has long been a security policy challenge for the West. The documentary looks at the two countries’ economic ties, political goals and interrelations -- down to the hyper-local level. Experts from Europe, the US and China provide insights and answers.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #china #europe 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The biggest mistake lottery winners make</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wxf_pKCOCBo</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wxf_pKCOCBo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 16:00:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">TED-Ed</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dig into the pros and cons of annuity and lump sum lottery payouts, and find out the most common mistakes lottery winners make.

--

After winning the lottery, one of the first decisions you’d have to make is how you want your winnings to be paid out. You can choose the full jackpot amount, paid out in annual installments over 30 years. Or you can take a much smaller lump sum paid out immediately. So, which is the better option? Explore the financial implications of annuity and lump sum payments.

Directed by Anton Bogaty.

This video made possible in collaboration with Gifted Savings
Learn more about how TED-Ed partnerships work: https://bit.ly/TEDEdPartner

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-biggest-mistake-lottery-winners-make
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-biggest-mistake-lottery-winners-make/digdeeper

Animator's website: https://antonbogaty.com
Music: https://www.workplaywork.com
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! Thomas Mungavan, Jaron Blackburn, Venkat Venkatakrishnan, ReuniteKorea, Aaron Henson, Rohan Gupta, Begum Tutuncu, Brian Richards, Jørgen Østerpart, Tyron Jung, Carsten Tobehn, Katie Dean, Ezgi Yersu, Gerald Onyango, alessandra tasso, Doreen Reynolds-Consolati, Manognya Chakrapani, Ayala Ron, Eunsun Kim, Phyllis Dubrow, Ophelia Gibson Best, Paul Schneider, Joichiro Yamada, Henrique Cassús, Karthik Cherala, Clarence E. Harper Jr., Vignan Velivela, Ana Maria, Exal Enrique Cisneros Tuch, Tejas Dc, Khalifa Alhulail, Martin Stephen, Jose Henrique Leopoldo e Silva, Mandeep Singh, Abhijit Kiran Valluri, Morgan Williams, Devin Harris, Pavel Zalevskiy, Karen Goepen-Wee, Filip Dabrowski, Barbara Smalley, Megan Douglas, Tim Leistikow, Ka-Hei Law, Hiroshi Uchiyama, Mark Morris, Misaki Sato, EdoKun, SookKwan Loong, and Bev Millar.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>This Parasite Won’t Die</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/MP4RUzRnobg</link><author>Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MP4RUzRnobg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q">Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Malaria has killed humans for millennia. From DDT to bed nets, vaccines, and genetically modified mosquitoes, we’ve pushed back... but resistance and climate change threaten progress. The war isn’t over.

#kurzgesagt
#inanutshell #kurzgesagt_inanutshell #learnwithshorts #science #malaria #malariaawareness #malariatreatment 

Sources & further reading: 
https://sites.google.com/view/kgs-tiktok-sources

Follow us for more sciencey content! 🦆

OUR CHANNELS
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
German:        https://kgs.link/youtubeDE
Spanish:        https://kgs.link/youtubeES
French:          https://kgs.link/youtubeFR
Portuguese:  https://kgs.link/youtubePT
Arabic:           https://kgs.link/youtubeAR
Hindi:             https://kgs.link/youtubeHI
Japanese:     https://kgs.link/youtubeJA
Korean:          https://kgs.link/youtubeKO


HOW CAN YOU SUPPORT US?
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
This is how we make our living and it would be a pleasure if you support us!

Get Products designed with ❤ https://shop.kgs.link/shorts
Become a Part of kurzgesagt by joining the Patreon Bird Army 🐧  https://kgs.link/patreon  


DISCUSSIONS & SOCIAL MEDIA
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Instagram:     https://kgs.link/instagram
TikTok:           https://kgs.link/tiktok
Reddit:            https://kgs.link/reddit
Discord:          https://kgs.link/discord
Twitter:           https://kgs.link/twitter
Bluesky:          https://kgs.link/bluesky
Facebook:      https://kgs.link/facebook
Newsletter:    https://kgs.link/newsletter


OUR VOICE
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
The Kurzgesagt voice is from 
Steve Taylor:  https://kgs.link/youtube-voice


OUR MUSIC ♬♪
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
700+ minutes of Kurzgesagt Soundtracks by Epic Mountain:

Spotify:            https://kgs.link/music-spotify
Soundcloud:   https://kgs.link/music-soundcloud
Bandcamp:     https://kgs.link/music-bandcamp
Youtube:          https://kgs.link/music-youtube
Facebook:       https://kgs.link/music-facebook]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>FLORIDA</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-hlkzIaF0nU</link><author>Horses</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-hlkzIaF0nU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrx2zrPjhGRi9TwszZiLwEg">Horses</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://ground.news/horses to break out of echo chambers, understand different perspectives, and combat polarization with Ground News. Save 40% on their unlimited access Vantage plan for yourself or as a gift this holiday season.

www.horses.land

sources:
Land of Sunshine... Mormino
Cracker: Spanish Florida Style, Lewis
Do It Yourself Deathscape, Steinberg
A Concise History of Florida, Clark
The Swamp, Grunwald]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>