<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>World News</title><link>https://konrad.website/liveboat-github-runner/</link><description></description><item><title>Pentagon, Powell, Walmart, DC troops and Gaza&apos;s children</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pmFmM-cPUdE</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pmFmM-cPUdE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 10:23:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Pentagon’s intelligence chief has been fired in the latest purge by President Donald Trump's administration. Fed Chair Jerome Powell hints at a rate cut in September. Walmart’s earnings reveal shifting consumer behavior under Trump’s tariff policy. National Guard presence alters Washington DC’s tourist season. And Gaza’s children face starvation as aid struggles to meet demand. 








Listen to ⁠⁠⁠⁠On Assignment⁠⁠⁠⁠ (https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/on-assignment/)  podcast here.



Sign up for the Reuters Econ World newsletter ⁠⁠⁠⁠here⁠⁠⁠⁠ (https://www.reuters.com/newsletters/reuters-econ-world/) .
Listen to the Reuters Econ World podcast ⁠⁠⁠⁠here⁠⁠⁠⁠ (https://nam02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flink.chtbl.com%2FAbxd8GDx&data=05%7C02%7CBilkisu.Labaran%40thomsonreuters.com%7Ce10c8f8bd99243c4053408ddbdf9de52%7C62ccb8646a1a4b5d8e1c397dec1a8258%7C0%7C0%7C638875603061524319%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJFbXB0eU1hcGkiOnRydWUsIlYiOiIwLjAuMDAwMCIsIlAiOiJXaW4zMiIsIkFOIjoiTWFpbCIsIldUIjoyfQ%3D%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&sdata=lyEYvXuqKWupkoUekpcvNZmYtsBjcHiWzfQSbK2Mx5U%3D&reserved=0) .



Find the Recommended Read ⁠⁠⁠⁠here⁠⁠⁠⁠ (https://www.reuters.com/world/us/how-unraveling-two-pentagon-projects-may-result-costly-do-over-2025-08-13/) .



Visit the Thomson Reuters Privacy Statement for information on our privacy and data protection practices. 



You may also visit megaphone.fm/adchoices to opt out of targeted advertising.


 


Learn more about your ad choices. Visit megaphone.fm/adchoices (https://megaphone.fm/adchoices)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Crawley family car among &apos;Downton Abbey&apos; memorabilia being auctioned off | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/NrfY8AAhmfE</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NrfY8AAhmfE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A ‘Downton Abbey’ auction preview opened in London, exhibiting costumes and props from the British television period drama and its spinoff films. "Every lot tells a story and is a very important part of the 'Downton Abbey' provenance," said Charlie Thomas, Bonhams' UK Group Director.

#downtonabbey #auction #crawleyfamily #bonhams #memorabilia #News #Reuters #Newsfeed

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Could Trump&apos;s Tariffs Cause AriZona to Raise Iced Tea Prices?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jX2yQ0lP918</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/jX2yQ0lP918?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 09:01:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Don Vultaggio, AriZona Beverage Company Co-Founder & Chairman, discusses how much longer he can keep the iced tea's 99 cent price tag and how President Trump's tariffs are threatening to increase this price. Vultaggio also talks about how aluminum tariffs specifically are affecting his company and whether or not the company plans to absorb the costs. He speaks with Tyler Kendall and Michael Shephard on the late edition of Bloomberg's "Balance of Power."
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>General Staff: Russia has lost 1,075,160 troops in Ukraine since Feb. 24, 2022</title><link>https://kyivindependent.com/general-staff-russia-has-lost-1-075-160-troops-in-ukraine-since-feb-24-2022</link><author>/u/Sufficient_Brush_473</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 08:19:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Russia has lost 1,075,160 troops in Ukraine since the beginning of its full-scale invasion on Feb. 24, 2022, the General Staff of Ukraine's Armed Forces reported on Aug. 22.The number includes 840 casualties that Russian forces suffered over the past day.According to the , Russia has also lost 11,129 tanks, 23,164 armored fighting vehicles, 59,512 vehicles and fuel tanks, 31,858 artillery systems, 1,472 multiple launch rocket systems, 1,210 air defense systems, 422 airplanes, 340 helicopters, 52,935 drones, 28 ships and boats, and one submarine.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>600 Kilometers of Courage: The Baltic Way Protest</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1mxutym/600_kilometers_of_courage_the_baltic_way_protest/</link><author>/u/Brilliant-Nerve12</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 07:15:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Space Tech; Spar&apos;s Refocus; Creative Industry | Bloomberg Next Africa</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1vHTnPWN48w</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1vHTnPWN48w?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 07:00:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[On this month's episode we hear from one company looking to on take Elon Musk's Starlink as the main space-tech provider on the continent. We also dig into the state of the consumer. With help from Bloomberg Economics, Next Africa looks at the variables impacting retail purchasing. The show also gets unfettered access to one of the continent's largest retail brands, Spar Group, whose CEO is eyeing more expansion. Plus, Investing Africa talks to a fund manager that sees value in the creative sector.
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>4chan will refuse to pay daily UK fines, its lawyer tells BBC</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cq68j5g2nr1o</link><author>/u/Street_Anon</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 03:14:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A lawyer representing the online message board 4chan says it won't pay a proposed fine by the UK's media regulator as it enforces the Online Safety Act.According to Preston Byrne, managing partner of law firm Byrne & Storm, Ofcom has provisionally decided to impose a £20,000 fine "with daily penalties thereafter" for as long as the site fails to comply with its request."Ofcom's notices create no legal obligations in the United States," he told the BBC, adding he believed the regulator's investigation was part of an "illegal campaign of harassment" against US tech firms.Ofcom has declined to comment while its investigation continues."4chan has broken no laws in the United States - my client will not pay any penalty," Mr Byrne said.Then in August, it said it had issued 4chan with "a provisional notice of contravention" for failing to comply with two requests for information.Ofcom said its investigation would examine whether the message board was complying with the act, including requirements to protect its users from illegal content.4chan has often been at the heart of online controversies in its 22 years, including misogynistic campaigns and conspiracy theories.Users are anonymous, which can often lead to extreme content being posted.In a statement posted on X, law firms Byrne & Storm and Coleman Law said 4chan was a US company incorporated in the US, and therefore protected against the UK law."American businesses do not surrender their First Amendment rights because a foreign bureaucrat sends them an email," they wrote."Under settled principles of US law, American courts will not enforce foreign penal fines or censorship codes. "If necessary, we will seek appropriate relief in US federal court to confirm these principles."They said authorities in the US had been "briefed" on their response to Ofcom's investigation.The statement concludes by calling on the Trump administration to invoke all diplomatic and legal levers to protect American businesses from "extraterritorial censorship mandates".Ofcom has previously said the Online Safety Act only requires services to take action to protect users based in the UK.Some American politicians - particularly the Trump administration, its allies and officials - have pushed back against what they regard as overreach in the regulation of US tech firms by the UK and EU. A perceived impact of the Online Safety Act on free speech has been a particular concern, but other laws have also been the source of disagreement.On 19 August, US Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard said the UK had withdrawn its controversial demand for a "backdoor" in an Apple data protection system - saying she worked with the President and Vice President to get the UK to abandon its plan.Two days later, US Federal Trade Commission chairman Andrew Ferguson warned big tech firms they could be violating US law if they weakened privacy and data security requirements by complying with international laws such as the Online Safety Act."Foreign governments seeking to limit free expression or weaken data security in the United States might count on the fact that companies have an incentive to simplify their operations and legal compliance measures by applying uniform policies across jurisdictions," he said.If 4chan does successfully fight the fine in the US courts, Ofcom may have other options."Enforcing against an offshore provider is tricky," Emma Drake, partner of online safety and privacy at law firm Bird and Bird, told the BBC. "Ofcom can instead ask a court to order other services to disrupt a provider's UK business, such as requiring a service's removal from search results or blocking of UK payments."If Ofcom doesn't think this will be enough to prevent significant harm, it can even ask that ISPs be ordered to block UK access."]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ukraine shoots down Russian Orlan &apos;mother drone&apos; carrying FPVs for first time, military says</title><link>https://kyivindependent.com/ukraine-shoots-down-russian-orlan-mother-drone-carrying-fpvs-for-first-time-military-says/</link><author>/u/St_Gregory_Nazianzus</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 02:56:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Ukrainian anti-aircraft gunners shot down a Russian Orlan drone carrying two first-person-view (FPV) drones under its wings for the first time, the 118th Separate Mechanized Brigade reported on Aug. 22. This marks the first time the Ukrainian military has destroyed a so-called "mother drone" carrying other UAVs, the brigade claimed. "Anti-aircraft gunners from the 118th Separate Mechanized Brigade destroyed an enemy Orlan drone carrying two FPV drones under its wings," the unit said in a Facebook post. "Prior to this, the pilots of the pursuit platoon had already shot down dozens of enemy reconnaissance drones — Orlan, Zala, and Supercam — but this was the first time they had managed to destroy a mother drone."The Orlan is a Russian-developed reconnaissance drone widely used by Russia in Ukraine. Feared by Ukrainian soldiers, it often serves to target Russian artillery attacks. It can travel 600 kilometers and climb to an altitude of 5,000 meters.Innovations in drone warfare are a key component of Ukraine's defense strategy against Russia. Kyiv is reportedly developing its own version of a drone-carrier in partnership with the German defense company Quantum Systems. The Sparta is designed to carry two FPV drones with a combat radius of 200 km (124 miles.)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Famine in Gaza city; Powell hints at rate cut, and more</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/theeconomistmorningbriefing/episodes/famine-in-gaza-city-powell-hints-at-rate-cut-and-more</link><author></author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/theeconomistmorningbriefing/e/68a91ad0718453410e8257a5/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJpbiI6Imh0dHBzOi8vczMuYW1hem9uYXdzLmNvbS9hc3NldHMucGlwcGEuaW8vc2hvd3MvNjJlMjg2YTkzNGQ0ZDkwNmUzODc0MjRiLzE3NTU5MTI3OTE4MTQtOGFkZWZmYTQtZjcyZi00NDkzLTk3NWEtYjJlMzJmMTIwOWZhLXB1YmxpY0ludHJvLm1wMyIsIm91dCI6Imh0dHBzOi8vczMuYW1hem9uYXdzLmNvbS9hc3NldHMucGlwcGEuaW8vc2hvd3MvNjJlMjg2YTkzNGQ0ZDkwNmUzODc0MjRiLzE3NTU5MTI3OTU0MzEtY2EzZTk5MGItNDQ2YS00MWZkLWE0NjgtZWQ4NzI1MDU5NTJkLXB1YmxpY091dHJvLm1wMyIsInN0YXR1cyI6InB1YmxpYyJ9&amp;sig=uta4G0Q-w9eXmUoC5DfoKno0_CySb5VIvSX9FJHN3Gc" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 02:01:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.economist.com/audio/podcasts/the-world-in-brief">News - Daily Brief</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>😆 Dakota Johnson crashes co-stars&apos; interview for &apos;Splitsville&apos;</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/VB3Wa7XbNGU</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/VB3Wa7XbNGU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 00:00:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dakota Johnson pulled double duty as producer and star of the new relationship comedy "Splitsville," which follows two couples.
 
After her own interview with Reuters, she playfully appeared in the background while her co-stars, Michael Angelo Covino and Kyle Marvin, were being filmed.
  
#dakotajohnson #splitsville #interview #michaelangelocovino #kylemarvin

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Wall Street cheers Powell&apos;s speech | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AU8MRc95MqM</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/AU8MRc95MqM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 23:52:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Wall Street's main indexes ended higher, with the blue-chip Dow hitting a record closing high.
#News #wallstreet #powell #Reuters #Newsfeed 

Read the story here: https://reut.rs/4fNzCVw 

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Cowboy Capitalism | Powell at Jackson Hole, Jackson&apos;s Billionaires, Chevron CEO, Dallas Finance Boom</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2vrZIzYDiXo</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2vrZIzYDiXo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 23:51:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This week, former Reserve Bank of India governor Raghuram Rajan weighs in on Fed Chair Powell's remarks at the Fed's annual conference Jackson Hole. And, a look at the wealthiest county in the US - how do billionaires coexist with cowboy culture and the local community in Teton County? Plus, Chevron CEO Mike Wirth on the role of fossil fuels in the energy transition. Later, from Wall Street to "Y’all Street" - what Dallas is doing to attract financial firms and workers.

Chapters:
00:00:00 - Powell at Jackson Hole
00:11:06 - Jackson Hole Attracts Billionaires
00:23:51 - Chevron CEO on Demand for Oil
00:34:52 - Dallas Finance Boom
00:47:36 - The Jackson Hole Rodeo
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Howard credits &apos;White Lotus&apos; for inspiring &apos;Eden&apos; | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-qyJvmV_29A</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-qyJvmV_29A?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 23:51:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Oscar-winning filmmaker Ron Howard helms the new historical thriller ‘Eden,’ which boasts an ensemble cast including Jude Law, Vanessa Kirby, Ana de Armas, Sydney Sweeney and Daniel Bruhl.
#News #RonHoward #eden #whitelotus #Reuters #Newsfeed 

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>US Govt. Makes $8.9B Investment in Intel Stock | Balance of Power 8/22/2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hUaQ8JY7WDE</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hUaQ8JY7WDE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 23:37:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA["Balance of Power: Late Edition" focuses on the intersection of politics and global business. On today's show, Former Kansas City Fed President, Esther George, discusses whether or not when the Federal Reserve decides to cut rates will it risk Fed credibility. Dominic LeBlanc, president of the King's Privy Council for Canada and minister for Canada-US trade, explains why Canada is removing its retaliatory tariffs on a long list of US products that comply with the existing North American trade deal. Evelyn Farkas, former Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Russia, Ukraine, & Eurasia shares her thoughts on how much leverage President Trump has in stopping the war in Ukraine.

Chapters:
00:00:00 - Late Edition of Balance Power Begins
00:02:09 - Michael McKee Recapping Fed Chair Jerome Powell’s Speech, Powell Opens Door to Interest Rate Cut
00:04:18 - Skylar Woodhouse on US Govt. Makes $8.9B Investment in Intel Stock, Trump Saying He’ll Fire Lisa Cook if She Doesn’t Resign
00:07:49 - Esther George, Fmr. Pres. of the Fed. Reserve Bank of Kansas City, on Any Risk to Fed Credibility if Cut Rates, Impact of Tariffs on Inflation
00:15:54 - Dominic LeBlanc, Minister for Canada-US Trade, on PM Carney Removing Retaliatory Tariffs on US Products
00:24:57 - Power Moves: Vonnie Quinn Discusses Wall Street Having Best Day Since April on Fed Signal, Powell Remarks Reverse 5-Day S&P 500 Slide
00:29:08 - Evelyn Farkas, Fmr. Deputy Asst. Sec. of Defense for Russia & Ukraine, on How Pres. Trump Can Stop Ukraine War, Security Guarantees
00:38:16 - Power Brief: Top Stories Watching Tonight
00:40:25 - Political Panel Reaction to FBI Raids Home of Fmr. Trump Adviser John Bolton, US Investment in Intel, Trump Reignites Pressure on The Fed
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>&apos;The Thursday Murder Club&apos; celebrates older adults | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KclQLMgdOzw</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KclQLMgdOzw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 23:10:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Actor Helen Mirren, who stars in 'The Thursday Murder Club,' a movie about a group of retirees who enjoy cracking unresolved murder cases, said it's great to see older adults celebrated on screen.
#News #thethursdaymurderclub #HelenMirren #Reuters #Newsfeed 

Read the story here: ttps://reut.rs/4fMbBhE

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Wall Street Rallies as Powell Opens Door to Rate Cut | The Close 8/22/2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CjfVuVQFvVQ</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CjfVuVQFvVQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 23:04:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Bloomberg Television brings you the latest news and analysis leading up to the final minutes and seconds before and after the closing bell on Wall Street. Today's guests are Crossmark Global Investments’ Bob Doll, Saronic Technologies’s Dino Mavrookas, DA Davidson’s Gil Luria, J.P. Morgan Asset Management’s David Kelly, Morgan Stanley’s Kathy Entwistle, Laffer Tengler’s Nancy Tengler, Futurum’s Daniel Newman, Capital Alpha Partners’ James Lucier.

Chapters:
00:00:00 - Bloomberg Market: The Close
00:03:29 - Crossmark Global Investments’ Bob Doll
00:09:20 - Saronic Technologies’s Dino Mavrookas
00:16:49 - Top Calls
00:18:26 - DA Davidson’s Gil Luria
00:23:08 - J.P. Morgan Asset Management’s David Kelly
00:30:38 - Anurag Rana, Bloomberg News
00:36:27 - Morgan Stanley’s Kathy Entwistle
00:43:23 - Closing Bell
00:57:25 - Laffer Tengler’s Nancy Tengler
01:05:52 - Mike Mckee, Bloomberg News
01:09:07 - Mark Gurman, Bloomberg News
01:11:28 - Futurum’s Daniel Newman
01:19:23 - Capital Alpha Partners’ James Lucier
01:25:38 - Chris Palmeri, Bloomberg News
01:28:26 - What to Watch
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Eswatini govt faces court challenge for accepting US deportees | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HsAv05iibsA</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HsAv05iibsA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:58:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Human rights lawyers and activists have sued the Eswatini government for making a secretive deal with President Trump's administration to accept third-country deportees from the US, which they claim was unconstitutional.
#News #Eswatini #US #Reuters #Newsfeed 

Read the story here: https://reut.rs/4muAJft 

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Putin sees &apos;light at the end of the tunnel&apos; in US ties | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QR_ueqzfHEQ</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/QR_ueqzfHEQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:41:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[President Vladimir Putin said there was ‘light at the end of the tunnel’ in Russia-US relations, signaling optimism that Russia can mend relations with the US and strike business deals.
#News #putin #US #russia #Reuters #Newsfeed 

Read the story here: https://reut.rs/4fOhGu9 

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Are Putin, Russia Misleading President Trump?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KLsDsL-X1UE</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KLsDsL-X1UE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:15:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Evelyn Farkas, former Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Russia, Ukraine, & Eurasia shares her thoughts on how much leverage President Trump has in stopping the war in Ukraine, and suggests that the President should enact secondary sanctions on Russia right away. She states that "the Russians have been misleading" President Trump and talks about what long term security guarantees the US and Europe can give Ukraine that Russia may agree to. Evelyn Farkas speaks with Tyler Kendall and Michael Shepard on the late edition of Bloomberg's "Balance of Power."
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Trump threatens intervention in Chicago | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6bUdf4LUp10</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6bUdf4LUp10?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:15:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[US President Trump said he would expand his crime crackdown to Chicago, using federal powers to intervene in another city governed by Democrats, and threatened to take full control of Washington, D.C., rather than only its policing.
#News #Trump #chicago #washingtondc #US #Reuters #Newsfeed 

Read the story here: https://reut.rs/45Og5Qj 

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>&apos;Urgent action&apos; needed to protect workers from heat, UN says | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yaUbCeXaukM</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/yaUbCeXaukM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:12:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Governments and employers should take urgent action to help protect the health of workers who are increasingly exposed to extreme heat, the United Nations said.
#News #UN #heat #Reuters #Newsfeed 

Read the story here: https://reut.rs/4mWTLLl 

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Draghi “From Ukraine to Gaza, the EU has been a mere spectator”</title><link>https://www.italpress.com/draghi-from-ukraine-to-gaza-the-eu-has-been-a-mere-spectator/</link><author>/u/Affectionate_Cat293</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:03:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[RIMINI (ITALPRESS/MNA) – “For years the EU believed that its economic weight, with 450 million consumers, would automatically translate into geopolitical power and influence in trade relations. This year will be remembered as the one in which that illusion came to an end. We had to accept U.S. tariffs, and we were pushed by our own ally to increase military spending – a decision perhaps necessary, but not in this form or at this pace.”Speaking at the 46th Meeting in Rimini, former Prime Minister Mario Draghi continued, “the EU played only a marginal role in peace negotiations over Ukraine. It was a mere spectator even as Iranian nuclear sites were bombed and the massacre in Gaza escalated.”According to Draghi, “Europe must move from being a spectator, or at best a supporting actor, to becoming a protagonist. That means reshaping its political organization, which is inseparable from its ability to meet economic and strategic goals. Economic reforms remain essential.”“Europe is the best opportunity we have for a future of peace and security. And as a democracy, it is you, it is us, the Europeans who set the priorities,” Draghi said.On fiscal policy, Draghi repeated his distinction between “good debt and bad debt,” but warned that in some areas national-level borrowing is no longer sufficient. He argued that only common European debt can finance large-scale projects in defense, energy, and emerging technologies.The former ECB president also pointed to a “brutal wake-up call” from Donald Trump, which he said reshaped relations with the U.S. “There is now a political, social, and psychological climate that gives hope for a new kind of political organization. We must learn to cooperate. Rigidity and passivity breed inaction – and that, as wève seen over the last 10-15 years, is Europès worst enemy.”“It is not surprising that skepticism toward Europe has reached new heights,” Draghi added. “But it is worth asking what lies at the heart of this skepticism. In my view, it is not directed at the values on which Europe was founded, but rather at the EU’s ability to defend those values. And that skepticism is partly justified: political structures are designed to address the challenges of their time, and when those challenges change, the structures themselves must change”.Vuoi pubblicare i contenuti di Italpress.com sul tuo sito web o vuoi promuovere la tua attività sul nostro sito e su quelli delle testate nostre partner? Contattaci all'indirizzo ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>📺 Amanda Knox tells her story in new TV series</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/-3LkTFfgC3I</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-3LkTFfgC3I?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Amanda Knox is setting the record straight in a new limited television series, "The Twisted Tale of Amanda Knox." The 38-year-old became a household name after she was convicted, and later acquitted, of the 2007 murder of her roommate, Meredith Kercher, in Italy. She served four years in jail before the conviction was annulled.
 
#amandaknox #tv #television #murder #legal

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Is Fed Credibility At Risk If Federal Reserve Decides to Cut Rates?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EBmCxsFkDvE</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EBmCxsFkDvE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:48:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Former Kansas City Fed President, Esther George, discusses whether or not when the Federal Reserve decides to cut rates will it risk Fed credibility. She also talks about Fed Chairman Jerome Powell’s speech at Jackson Hole, and how President Trump’s tariffs will impact inflation. Esther George speaks with Tyler Kendall and Michael Shepard on the late edition of Bloomberg’s “Balance of Power.”
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Trump says he knows little about search of John Bolton&apos;s home | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YMYKagZ0Dzw</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/YMYKagZ0Dzw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:37:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[US President Donald Trump said that he had limited knowledge of the FBI searching the home of his former aide John Bolton but called him a ‘lowlife’.
#News #Trump #johnbolton #US #Reuters #Newsfeed 

Read the story here: https://reut.rs/45wqa5F 

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ukrainian attack cuts Russian oil flows to Hungary, Slovakia | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4XLZtI2XE2M</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4XLZtI2XE2M?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:17:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Russian oil supplies to Hungary and Slovakia could be suspended for at least five days following the latest Ukrainian strike on a facility in Russia, the Hungarian and Slovakian governments said.
#News #ukraine #russia #hungary #slovakia #Reuters #Newsfeed 

Read the story here: https://reut.rs/3HnIyo4 

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>South African skydiver flies to global heights | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rE1n5GSOfiU</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/rE1n5GSOfiU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:13:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Soaring high above the jagged peaks of Table Mountain, South African wingsuit flyer Jean-Jacques Wallis is redefining the limits of human flight.
#News #skydiver #southafrica #Reuters #Newsfeed 

Read the story here: 

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Axiom Space CEO on retiring the International Space Station</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/c0h9ixYe2ag</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/c0h9ixYe2ag?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:08:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Tejpaul Bhatia, CEO of Axiom Space, discusses retiring the International Space Station and what it will mean for competition between the US and China in space. Watch our full interview here: https://bloom.bg/3Jx8I8h]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Springboks eager to bounce back after loss to Australia | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fu_qEL63A4w</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/fu_qEL63A4w?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:06:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[South Africa will have a fresh opportunity to put in a performance that goes some way toward making up for Rugby Championship loss, captain Jesse Kriel said.
#News #Springboks #australia #RugbyChampionship #Reuters #Newsfeed 

Read the story here: https://reut.rs/3UEy3Qf 

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A New Way to Trade Gold</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pZxEqZond8Q</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pZxEqZond8Q?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:00:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Abaxx Technologies CEO Josh Crumb says President Donald Trump's tariffs on some gold bars were good for their business. He says physical demand for gold from Singapore and Asia is high. He's on "Bloomberg The Close."
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Markets Rally On Powell’s Sept Cut Hint | Closing Bell</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ef4t_fwJ90c</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ef4t_fwJ90c?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 20:32:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Comprehensive cross-platform coverage of the U.S. market close on Bloomberg Television, Bloomberg Radio, and YouTube with Vonnie Quinn, Caroline Hyde, Tim Stenovec and Norah Mulinda.
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Wall Street Gets Rally Signal From Powell | Bloomberg Businessweek Daily 8/22/2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PmJtmcVp2Sg</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/PmJtmcVp2Sg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 20:17:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[On today's episode of Bloomberg Businessweek Daily, Tim Stenovec and Norah Mulinda discuss Jerome Powell's speech from Jackson Hole spurring huge movement in the market. Bloomberg's Molly Smith and Eric Weiner break down the Fed Chair's speech and its implications. Webtoon Chief Financial Officer David Lee talks partnering with Disney, and Axiom Space Chief Executive Officer Tejpaul Bhatia breaks down launching a data server to ISS and the future of commercial spaceflight.

Chapters:
00:00:00 - Bloomberg Businessweek Daily Starts
00:05:40 - Molly Smith and Eric Weiner on Powell ‘Adjusting Policy Stance,’ Markets Responding to Fed Chair’s Speech
00:21:19 - Webtoon CFO David Lee on Customer Demand, AI, Platform Growth as Company Partners with Disney
00:37:25 - Denitsa Tsekova Discusses Wall Street Getting Rally Signals from Powell it was Hoping for
00:41:38 - Axiom Space CEO Tejpaul Bhatia Talks Launching Data Server to ISS, Future of Commercial Spaceflight
00:50:52 - Denitsa Tsekova Sticks Around with Stocks on the Move
--------
Watch Bloomberg Radio LIVE on YouTube
Weekdays 7am-6pm ET
WATCH HERE: http://bit.ly/3vTiACF
 
Follow us on X: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Subscribe to our Podcasts:

    Bloomberg Daybreak: http://bit.ly/3DWYoAN
    Bloomberg Surveillance: http://bit.ly/3OPtReI
    Bloomberg Intelligence: http://bit.ly/3YrBfOi
    Balance of Power: http://bit.ly/3OO8eLC
    Bloomberg Businessweek: http://bit.ly/3IPl60i

Listen on Apple CarPlay and Android Auto with the Bloomberg Business app:
Apple CarPlay: https://apple.co/486mghI
Android Auto: https://bit.ly/49benZy
 
Visit our YouTube channels:
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/bloombergpodcasts
Bloomberg Television: https://www.youtube.com/@markets
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/bloomberg
Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Webtoon and Disney sign deal to bring Marvel, Star Wars comics to platform</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/XMsyR6dg_b8</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XMsyR6dg_b8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 20:16:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[WEBTOON surged after announcing a partnership with The Walt Disney Company that will bring iconic characters such as Marvel’s Spider-Man and Luke Skywalker of Star Wars to its platform. Here's what Webtoon CFO David Lee had to say about the partnership and creators' power on the platform https://bloom.bg/47EUlsE]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Can Dallas’ “Y’all Street” rival Wall Street?#shorts #dallas #wallstreet #finance #wealth</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/xSi-SeiQZ7Y</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/xSi-SeiQZ7Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 20:13:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dallas is expanding its presence as a financial hub, luring Wall Street firms with a pro-business culture and rapid growth. Watch "Wall Street Week" tonight at 6 p.m. ET https://bloom.bg/4oPSqrn]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Apple May Use Google Gemini AI to Power Revamped Siri</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1q_EPKg5_rA</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1q_EPKg5_rA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 19:48:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Apple is in early discussions about using Google Gemini to power a revamped version of its Siri voice assistant. The work is part of an effort to catch up in generative AI, a field where the company arrived late and then struggled to gain traction. Bloomberg's Denitsa Tsekova reports.
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>FTC Chair: Trump wants to &quot;unleash the animal spirits of American innovation in AI”</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/0LwXWF7kvj0</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0LwXWF7kvj0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 19:37:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[President Donald Trump wants to "unleash the animal spirits of American innovation in AI," says FTC Chair Andrew Ferguson. Watch our full interview here: https://bloom.bg/3HNKR3H]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Trump again gives Putin ‘a couple of weeks’ with no sign of Ukraine peace talks underway</title><link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/22/politics/putin-trump-two-weeks-peace-talks</link><author>/u/DrunkOnRamen</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 18:43:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[
            President Donald Trump said Friday he will give Russian President Vladimir Putin “a couple of weeks,” further extending his deadline for potential consequences against Moscow after urging the Russian leader to meet with his Ukrainian counterpart in hopes of ending the war.
    
            Asked by CNN’s Alayna Treene if there’s a possibility he does nothing if Putin doesn’t come to the table, Trump said, “We’ll see. I’ll see whose fault it is.”
    
            “If there are reasons why, I will understand that; I know exactly what I’m doing. We’re going to see whether or not they have a meeting, that will be interesting to see, and if they don’t, why didn’t they have a meeting? Because I told them to have a meeting,” Trump said.
    
            “But I’ll know in two weeks what I’m going to do,” Trump added, reprising a timeline he’s repeatedly issued to determine Putin’s willingness to end the war in Ukraine.
    
            His latest comments come as the momentum around peace talks has stalled, with no sign that the bilateral meeting the White House has pushed is happening. Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov said earlier on Friday that there were no plans for a meeting between the two leaders.
    
            After Trump met with Putin in Alaska last week and hosted Zelensky and European leaders at the White House earlier this week, he’d teased a bilateral meeting, potentially to be followed by a trilateral meeting he would join.
    
            “You understand that I wanted to have a meeting with those two. I could have been at the meeting, but a lot of people think that nothing’s going to come out of that meeting. ‘You have to be there.’ Maybe that’s true. Maybe it’s not, but we’re going to see in the meantime, people continue to die,” Trump said Friday.
    
            Trump repeated his two-week timeframe several times. “We’ll see what happens. I think in two weeks, we’ll know which way I’m going, because I’m going to go one way or the other, and they’ll learn which way.”
    
            Trump also pulled out from the Resolute Desk a photo of him and Putin in Anchorage, Alaska, that he said the Russian leader had sent him.
    
            “I was just sent a picture from someone who wants to be there very badly,” Trump said, referring to the World Cup. He’d convened reporters in the Oval Office to announce that the draw would be held at the Kennedy Center in December.
    
            “He’s been very respectful of me and of our country, but not so respectful of others,” Trump said, adding that he was going to sign the photo for Putin, who he suggested could be coming to the US for the World Cup.
    
            “He may be coming and he may not, depending on what happens. We have a lot of things happening over the next couple of weeks,” Trump said.
    
            Putin on Friday described his recent meeting with Trump as “very good” and said Russia sought an end to the fighting in Ukraine. However, he made no mention of whether he would attend bilateral talks with Zelensky.
    
            He added that Russian and US agencies were continuing to communicate and that he expects a “full-scale restoration” of their relationship.
    CNN’s Nina Subkhanberdina contributed to this report. This story has been updated with additional developments. ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Top Money-Saving Hacks for Raising Kids</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/wh2gfnfHJIY</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wh2gfnfHJIY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 18:00:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">News - Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Parenting demands a heaping dose of creativity—to entertain your kids, to foster their learning, to get them to eat vegetables. Applying a bit of that creativity to saving money can chip away at the massive expense of raising kids. And it might actually be fun. WSJ asked parents with kids of all ages for their best money-saving hacks.

#Parenting #Budgeting #Shorts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Trump’s intel chief freezes out Five Eyes allies on Ukraine</title><link>https://www.politico.eu/article/tulsi-gabbard-freeze-five-eyes-allies-on-ukraine-intel/</link><author>/u/HydrolicKrane</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:27:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Breach comes as European regulators and telecoms operators warn of rise in large-scale data leaks.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>“I’m very angry. You’re my great friend,” Trump replied to Orban’s complaints about the Druzhba pipeline attack. “I don’t like to hear this. I’m very angry. Tell this to Slovakia. You’re my great friend,” Trump wrote to the Hungarian prime minister.</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1mxb41o/im_very_angry_youre_my_great_friend_trump_replied/</link><author>/u/BkkGrl</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:25:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>4chan will refuse to pay daily UK fines, its lawyer tells BBC</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cq68j5g2nr1o</link><author>/u/ByGollie</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:01:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A lawyer representing the online message board 4chan says it won't pay a proposed fine by the UK's media regulator as it enforces the Online Safety Act.According to Preston Byrne, managing partner of law firm Byrne & Storm, Ofcom has provisionally decided to impose a £20,000 fine "with daily penalties thereafter" for as long as the site fails to comply with its request."Ofcom's notices create no legal obligations in the United States," he told the BBC, adding he believed the regulator's investigation was part of an "illegal campaign of harassment" against US tech firms.Ofcom has declined to comment while its investigation continues."4chan has broken no laws in the United States - my client will not pay any penalty," Mr Byrne said.Then in August, it said it had issued 4chan with "a provisional notice of contravention" for failing to comply with two requests for information.Ofcom said its investigation would examine whether the message board was complying with the act, including requirements to protect its users from illegal content.4chan has often been at the heart of online controversies in its 22 years, including misogynistic campaigns and conspiracy theories.Users are anonymous, which can often lead to extreme content being posted.In a statement posted on X, law firms Byrne & Storm and Coleman Law said 4chan was a US company incorporated in the US, and therefore protected against the UK law."American businesses do not surrender their First Amendment rights because a foreign bureaucrat sends them an email," they wrote."Under settled principles of US law, American courts will not enforce foreign penal fines or censorship codes. "If necessary, we will seek appropriate relief in US federal court to confirm these principles."They said authorities in the US had been "briefed" on their response to Ofcom's investigation.The statement concludes by calling on the Trump administration to invoke all diplomatic and legal levers to protect American businesses from "extraterritorial censorship mandates".Ofcom has previously said the Online Safety Act only requires services to take action to protect users based in the UK.Some American politicians - particularly the Trump administration, its allies and officials - have pushed back against what they regard as overreach in the regulation of US tech firms by the UK and EU. A perceived impact of the Online Safety Act on free speech has been a particular concern, but other laws have also been the source of disagreement.On 19 August, US Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard said the UK had withdrawn its controversial demand for a "backdoor" in an Apple data protection system - saying she worked with the President and Vice President to get the UK to abandon its plan.Two days later, US Federal Trade Commission chairman Andrew Ferguson warned big tech firms they could be violating US law if they weakened privacy and data security requirements by complying with international laws such as the Online Safety Act."Foreign governments seeking to limit free expression or weaken data security in the United States might count on the fact that companies have an incentive to simplify their operations and legal compliance measures by applying uniform policies across jurisdictions," he said.If 4chan does successfully fight the fine in the US courts, Ofcom may have other options."Enforcing against an offshore provider is tricky," Emma Drake, partner of online safety and privacy at law firm Bird and Bird, told the BBC. "Ofcom can instead ask a court to order other services to disrupt a provider's UK business, such as requiring a service's removal from search results or blocking of UK payments."If Ofcom doesn't think this will be enough to prevent significant harm, it can even ask that ISPs be ordered to block UK access."]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Air Force Roundels of European Countries [OC]</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1mx9pqk/air_force_roundels_of_european_countries_oc/</link><author>/u/forummapping</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 15:32:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Canada to remove many retaliatory tariffs on U.S. goods: source</title><link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/canada-removing-retaliatory-tariffs-1.7614909</link><author>/u/Puginator</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 15:21:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Canada will remove all tariffs on goods from the United States that are covered by the Canada-U.S.-Mexico Agreement (CUSMA) by Sept. 1, Prime Minister Mark Carney announced on Friday.The prime minister said Canada will maintain its tariffs on steel, aluminum and autos as the Liberal government works with the U.S. to craft a new trading relationship between the two countries.Carney said that despite the ongoing trade war, and U.S. tariffs on steel, aluminum, autos, copper, lumber and energy, 85 per cent of trade with the U.S. is still tariff-free — which is a better deal than other countries have. "As we work to address outstanding trade issues with the U.S., it is important we do everything we can to preserve this unique advantage for Canadian workers and their families," Carney said.WATCH | Carney says some retaliatory tariffs will be gone Sept. 1: "We want to be very good to Canada. I like Carney a lot. I think he's a good person and we had a very good talk yesterday," U.S. President Donald Trump said in the Oval Office Friday.Trump signed an executive order on July 31, raising tariffs on some Canadian goods to 35 per cent effective at 12:01 a.m. the next day. Canada might have been able to avoid the hike had it managed to strike a new trade deal with the U.S. by the Aug. 1 deadline, but that didn't happen.The Trump administration said the change was in response to fentanyl trafficking and Canada's decision earlier this year to hit back with counter-tariffs.  The Canadian government imposed retaliatory tariffs on U.S. goods three times since the trade war began, including counter-tariffs on $60 billion worth of U.S. consumer goods and additional tariffs on U.S. autos, steel and aluminum.The 35 per cent tariff rate only applies to goods not covered by CUSMA.First 'nation-building project' to be announced soonCarney referenced his conversation with Trump on Thursday, saying he got assurances from the U.S. president that by removing tariffs on U.S. imports compliant with CUSMA, discussions between the two countries will "intensify" to address "trade challenges in strategic sectors" still impacted by tariffs. Those discussions, Carney said, will happen alongside efforts to prepare for the official review of CUSMA that will happen next year by holding industry consultations starting next month in order to set priorities. Dominic LeBlanc, the minister responsible for Canada-U.S. trade, suggested to CBC's  that walking back the retaliatory tariffs will help ease tensions ahead of the CUSMA review.WATCH | LeBlanc says Canada has 'lots of cards' in negotiations with U.S.:"We have to get to that conversation in the most coherent posture possible and the prime minister's decision today very much lines up in that way," LeBlanc told guest-host Karina Roman.Carney also said his government will focus on strengthening the Canadian economy by expanding trade with other countries, doubling the pace of home-building and making investments in national defence.Earlier this year, Carney's government saw the passage of legislation that would streamline approvals for nation-building projects such as highways, railways, ports, airports, pipelines, critical minerals, mines, nuclear facilities and electrical transmission projects."The Canadian government will soon select the first in a series of new nation-building projects that will connect and transform our economy," he said on Friday.WATCH | It's time to 'stickhandle' with U.S., Carney says: Conservative Leader Pierre Poilievre criticized Carney's decision, accusing the prime minister of making "generous concessions" to the U.S. president without getting anything in return. "Today we learned that it is yet another capitulation and climb-down by Mark Carney, his elbows have mysteriously gone missing," he said Friday.Poilievre says either Carney has to admit that he was wrong all along or that he lied during the election campaign when he said he was the man who could get the best deal with Trump."He needs to explain which of those two things it is," Poilievre said. WATCH | Poilievre slams Carney's negotiating skills: The Conservative leader went on to say that his objective is to have all tariffs between Canada and the U.S. removed and he would have demanded that from Trump if he was prime minister."I would have gone to the president, respectfully, and said: 'You remove your tariffs, we remove ours. Let's sign an agreement that restores the great free-trading relationship that our two countries had for decades,'" he said.Unifor and Canadian Federation of Independent Business weigh inOntario Premier Doug Ford said he spoke with Carney after the announcement, telling him Canada needs an agreement with the U.S. that provides relief to the steel, auto, forestry and copper industries. "If the federal government can't achieve that, they need to hit back hard against U.S. tariffs and provide additional supports for the workers and businesses in these sectors," Ford said in a statement.The Canadian Federation of Independent Business (CFIB) welcomed Carney's announcement in a statement, calling it a "step in the right direction" that will "take the pressure off Canadian small businesses.""Many small business owners have told us that Canada's retaliatory measures were almost as damaging as the U.S. tariffs themselves," the CFIB's Corinne Pohlmann said in a statement. Pohlmann said that while the announcement provides some relief, Canadian companies have already paid millions of dollars in tariffs, and she urged the federal government to provide some of that revenue to small businesses impacted by the trade war. In a statement posted on X, Lana Payne, the president of Unifor, the largest private sector union in Canada with more than 300,000 members, said Carney's move was a mistake."Walking back counter-tariffs isn't an olive branch. It only enables more U.S. aggression," she said. "From the start, Unifor has demanded Canada's leverage be used to defend workers in this trade war," she added. "We should not give it away unless the U.S. also drops all punitive tariffs." This week, Cross Country Checkup is asking: Is Mark Carney playing it smart or selling Canada short by lifting many tariffs on U.S. goods? What grade are you giving him on managing Donald Trump? Leave your comment here and we may read it or call you back for our show on Sunday.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>CA vs. TX: The Redistricting Arms Race to Control Congress | WSJ</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r2Q4ZN-KSCE</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/r2Q4ZN-KSCE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 15:12:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">News - Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[President Trump has a narrow majority in the U.S. House of Representatives and Texas’s redistricting plan aims to give the GOP five new seats. California Democrats and Gov. Gavin Newsom are planning on redistricting to counter Trump’s push, with other states like New York, Missouri and Florida also looking to capture more seats. So what’s at stake for Congress?  

Matthew Klein, an analyst at the non-partisan Cook Political Report, breaks down the proposed Texas and California redistricting maps for the 2026 midterm elections and what it means for the balance of power in Congress.

Chapters:
0:00 The redistricting battle
0:26 How Republicans are redistricting in TX
1:20 Houston area
2:02 South Texas area
2:27 Dallas-Fort Worth area
2:54 Austin area
3:35 California’s response
4:15 Northern California area
5:11 Other states responses

News Explainers
Some days the high-speed news cycle can bring more questions than answers. WSJ’s news explainers break down the day's biggest stories into bite-size pieces to help you make sense of the news.

#Congress #Texas #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Swedish startup unveils Starlink alternative — that Musk can’t switch off</title><link>https://thenextweb.com/news/swedish-starlink-alternative-ru1-military-communications</link><author>/u/Goodlucksil</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 15:05:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A new pocket-sized Starlink alternative promises secure military communications — safe from interference by billionaire CEOs.The system, named the RU1, was unveiled today by Swedish startup TERASi. It’s billed as the world’s smallest and lightest mm-Wave radio, a form of communications that offers blazing-fast speeds and huge bandwidth.TNW City Coworking space - Where your best work happensA workspace designed for growth, collaboration, and endless networking opportunities in the heart of tech.Military control conflicts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Warsaw (Poland) in the morning</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1mx8bb3/warsaw_poland_in_the_morning/</link><author>/u/woronicz</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 14:39:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ukraine attacks pipeline that sends Russian oil to Hungary and Slovakia</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/aug/22/ukraine-attacks-pipeline-that-sends-russian-oil-to-hungary-and-slovakia</link><author>/u/Currency_Cat</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 14:01:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Ukraine has hit a key pumping station on the Druzhba oil pipeline bringing fuel to Europe from Russia, knocking out supplies to Hungary and Slovakia, the only remaining EU member states still receiving Russian oil.As Ukraine targets infrastructure crucial to Moscow’s war effort in response to the Russian onslaught, the commander of Ukraine’s Unmanned Systems Forces, Robert Brovdi, announced the attack on the Unecha pumping station in the Bryansk region.Bryansk’s premier, Alexander Bogomaz, said in a Telegram post that Ukraine fired Himars rockets and drones at the region in a combined attack.The Hungarian and Slovakian governments wrote to the European Commission, the EU executive, saying that Russian oil supplies could be suspended for at least five days owing to the damage.“The physical and geographical reality is that without this pipeline, the safe supply of our countries is simply not possible,” their foreign ministers, Péter Szijjártó and Juraj Blanár, said in a letter.The Ukrainian strike drew an angry reaction from Budapest, which gets more than half its crude oil from the Druzhba pipeline. Szijjártó wrote on Facebook it had been attacked “for the third time in a short time”.“This is another attack on the energy security of our country. Another attempt to drag us into war,” he said.Hungary’s prime minister, Viktor Orbán, has refused to join EU partners in backing Kyiv with political, economic and military support. Orbán visited Moscow last year for talks with the country’s president, Vladimir Putin, on a rare trip to Russia by a European leader.“Hungary supports Ukraine with electricity and petrol, in return they bomb pipeline that supply us,” Orbán wrote in English. “Very unfriendly move! We wish President Trump every success in his pursuit for peace!”Below the text was a handwritten message apparently written and signed by Trump: “Viktor – I do not like hearing this – I am very angry about it. Tell Slovakia,” it read. “You are my great friend – Donald.”The EU aims to phase out Russian oil and gas entirely by the end of 2027 but Budapest and Bratislava oppose such a move, arguing that Russian energy supplies are vital to their national economies.Despite a push by Trump to reach a deal to end the conflict, the three-and-a-half-year war continued unabated this week as Russia launched an air attack near Ukraine’s border with the EU on Thursday and continued its devastating assault on Ukrainian cities.Ukraine has repeatedly pounded Russian oil refineries among other targets, sending Russian wholesale petrol prices soaring to record highs in recent days. Moscow routinely targets Ukraine’s gas infrastructure, crucial for winter heating and as fuel for essential industries.The Druzhba pipeline begins in Russia and transports oil through Belarus and Ukraine to Slovakia and Hungary. It was the second time that supplies to the EU countries were interrupted this week.The Soviet-era pipeline, which runs through Belarus and Ukraine, also ships oil from Kazakhstan to Germany but its economy ministry said supplies of Kazakh oil were unaffected by the latest strike.Slovakia’s Moscow-friendly prime minister, Robert Fico, has adopted Kremlin lines and sided with Orbán as a pro-Russian voice in the EU.Reuters and the Associated Press contributed to this report]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ukrainian attack suspends Russian oil flows to Hungary, Slovakia</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/ukrainian-attack-suspends-russian-oil-flows-hungary-slovakia-2025-08-22/</link><author>/u/EsperaDeus</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:36:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic &apos;targeted by Serbian government and considers fleeing to Greece&apos; - after national icon offered backing to student protests</title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/sport/tennis/article-15020841/Novak-Djokovic-Serbian-government-fleeing-Greece-student-protests.html</link><author>/u/FantasticQuartet</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Novak Djokovic is reportedly considering moving permanently to Greece amid claims he has been targeted by the Serbian government for his support of student protests in the country.The 24-time Grand Slam singles champion has faced criticism from Serbian newspapers backing the country's president Aleksandar Vucic in recent months.Criticism of Djokovic has reportedly stemmed from his backing of student-led protests against Vucic last December.The protests were sparked by the collapse of a railway station canopy in Novi Sad in November, which killed 16 people.The disaster led to anger at the Serbian government and Vucic, who has been president for 12 year, with students blaming alleged corruption.Djokovic offered his backing to the protestors on social media, writing in December: 'As someone who deeply believes in the power of youth and their desire for a better future, I believe it's important that their voices are heard.Novak Djokovic is reportedly considering leaving Serbia after being 'targeted' by the GovernmentDjokovic is claimed to have become a target following his support of student protestors'Serbia has enormous potential, and its educated youth is its greatest strength. What we all need is understanding and respect. With you, Novak.'Djokovic then dedicated a victory at the Australian Open to a student who was hit by a car during a protest. In March, Djokovic wrote 'History, amazing' when sharing a photo of one of the largest protests to date with around 300,000 people participating.Djokovic was also seen at the Belgrade derby basketball match wearing a jumper with featuring the words 'students are champions'.The tennis star, who has not explicitly spoken out against Vucic or the Serbian Government, also had to distance himself from claims his post-match celebration at Wimbledon was linked to the protests.Djokovic had been seen celebrating with a pumping motion, which several had linked to the 'pump it' phrase used by students to keep putting pressure on the government.The 38-year-old claimed his celebration was between him and his children, linked to the song 'Pump It Up'.'I don't know how many of you guys know that. It's quite an old song, good rhythm,' Djokovic said at Wimbledon.'So yeah, we're pumping. We love pumping. We pump after every win. I don't know the name of the artist.'Djokovic was spotted wearing a jumper stating 'students are champions' at a basketball match earlier this yearThe 24-time Grand Slam champion denied suggestions his 'Pump it' celebration at Wimbledon was connected to the 'pump it' phrase used by students to pressure the governmentAccording to Germany newspaper NZZ, Djokovic's actions have led to the Serbian government 'setting their sights' on the tennis star.The report cited the Serbian tabloid newspaper Informer, which is loyal to Vucic, labelling Djokovic a 'disgrace' by supporting an alleged 'colour revolution' in March.The newspaper then branded Djokovic, one of the country's leading international figures, as a 'false patriot' after accusing him of 'fleeing to Greece'.Informer's claims followed reports last month that Djokovic is considering relocating his family to Greece through a Golden Visa programme, which allows non-EU citizens to live in the country in exchange for investment.Djokovic has met with Greek Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis on two occasions recently, with the first coming in Athens in June and the second occurring earlier this month on the island of Tinos.The star, who largely resides in Monaco, has played down reports of an imminent move to Greece. 'Obviously, there's a lot of speculation, but no, at the moment, not,' Djokovic said, when asked about the speculation during Wimbledon.'But who knows what could happen in the future. Yeah, it could happen.'Aleksandar Vucic has claimed he will continue to support Djokovic, but a report has claimed newspapers supporting the Serbian president have turned on the star in recent monthsSpeculation had grown after it was announced earlier this month that the Belgrade Open - owned by Djokovic's family - would be moving to Athens.'Despite great dedication and significant efforts, the conditions required to stage the tournament in the planned format and timeframe could not be secured, and it was therefore decided not to hold this year’s edition,' a statement read confirming the decision.'We are proud of everything achieved so far and deeply grateful to all those who were part of this project – especially our partners, sponsors, and the loyal audience that supported us throughout.'Criticism of Djokovic has marked a major shift in coverage of the star, who has been adored in Serbia throughout his career.Vucic, who had announced a museum would by built in honour of Djokovic after his Olympic gold medal last year, recently addressed his support of the protestors.'I will never say a bad word against him. He can support my opponents, but to say anything bad about him – I never will. It would be bad, stupid,' Vucic told Informer.'We will defeat that policy in the elections, but I will always cheer for him with all my heart.' ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rutte pledges NATO security for Ukraine</title><link>https://tvpworld.com/88479767/rutte-pledges-nato-security-for-ukraine-</link><author>/u/CrunchyBaconYum</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 12:44:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Norway, Sweden, Denmark, and Belgium will halt parcel shipments to the US starting August 23</title><link>https://www.businessinsider.com/some-european-postal-services-sellers-are-suspending-us-bound-shipments-2025-8</link><author>/u/World_of_Warshipgirl</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 12:40:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[If you have been eyeing something from overseas, you may want to click "buy now" today.Postal services operated by Norway, Sweden, Denmark, and Belgium — Posten Bring, PostNord, and bpost — said they will suspend parcel shipments to the US ahead of the end of a customs exemption that allows low-value packages to enter the country duty-free.The conundrum facing postal operators comes as the Trump administration prepares to suspend the "de minimis" exemption starting on August 29. The exemption used to allow international shipments under $800 to cross the border with minimal paperwork and no duties.Now, these shipments will face tariffs, and not every operator can handle the customs declaration paperwork, have a payment mechanism in place, or be responsible for returns should a receiver refuse to pay tariffs. It's unclear when the temporary freeze on shipments will resume."Due to the short timeframe to adapt to the new specific requirements, PostNord will temporarily halt shipments to the United States and Puerto Rico until a compliant solution has been developed and implemented," wrote the operator owned by the Swedish and Danish governments in a statement on Wednesday.Separately, Posten Bring, Norway's primary postal provider operated by the government, said in a statement that postal services have not been given clear instructions and solutions on how the duties will be paid or who would be responsible for returns. Therefore, Posten Bring sees suspension as the "only option."All three European postal services will suspend shipments starting August 23, which applies to all packages other than letters. This means that if you have a pending purchase that is not shipped by the deadline, your seller may need to cancel your order or arrange alternatives. But even if you're not purchasing from these specific European countries, your shopping options might still dwindle and become more costly.Etsy, the US e-commerce giant and a hub for independent crafters, posted a notice Wednesday that shipping label purchases for Australia Post, Canada Post, Evri, and Royal Mail for US-bound packages will be temporarily suspended starting August 25.Etsy wrote in a statement that these operators are unable to support prepaid duties at the moment, which may result in a large number of rejected packages due to unpaid duties and surprise costs for buyers not listed at checkout.Across social media platforms, many independent sellers based in the UK are also announcing that they can no longer support orders to the US, citing the introduction of an $80 flat fee plus handling charges for using Royal Mail to ship parcels to the US."We hope to resume shipping as soon as we can, but we really don't want our customers to be hit with an $80+ fee," wrote the Citrine Circle, a UK-based crystal shop, on Instagram. "It feels like the world is getting smaller and smaller."The White House did not immediately respond to a request for comment.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Norway, Sweden, Denmark, and Belgium will halt parcel shipments to the US starting August 23</title><link>https://www.businessinsider.com/some-european-postal-services-sellers-are-suspending-us-bound-shipments-2025-8</link><author>/u/World_of_Warshipgirl</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 12:39:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[If you have been eyeing something from overseas, you may want to click "buy now" today.Postal services operated by Norway, Sweden, Denmark, and Belgium — Posten Bring, PostNord, and bpost — said they will suspend parcel shipments to the US ahead of the end of a customs exemption that allows low-value packages to enter the country duty-free.The conundrum facing postal operators comes as the Trump administration prepares to suspend the "de minimis" exemption starting on August 29. The exemption used to allow international shipments under $800 to cross the border with minimal paperwork and no duties.Now, these shipments will face tariffs, and not every operator can handle the customs declaration paperwork, have a payment mechanism in place, or be responsible for returns should a receiver refuse to pay tariffs. It's unclear when the temporary freeze on shipments will resume."Due to the short timeframe to adapt to the new specific requirements, PostNord will temporarily halt shipments to the United States and Puerto Rico until a compliant solution has been developed and implemented," wrote the operator owned by the Swedish and Danish governments in a statement on Wednesday.Separately, Posten Bring, Norway's primary postal provider operated by the government, said in a statement that postal services have not been given clear instructions and solutions on how the duties will be paid or who would be responsible for returns. Therefore, Posten Bring sees suspension as the "only option."All three European postal services will suspend shipments starting August 23, which applies to all packages other than letters. This means that if you have a pending purchase that is not shipped by the deadline, your seller may need to cancel your order or arrange alternatives. But even if you're not purchasing from these specific European countries, your shopping options might still dwindle and become more costly.Etsy, the US e-commerce giant and a hub for independent crafters, posted a notice Wednesday that shipping label purchases for Australia Post, Canada Post, Evri, and Royal Mail for US-bound packages will be temporarily suspended starting August 25.Etsy wrote in a statement that these operators are unable to support prepaid duties at the moment, which may result in a large number of rejected packages due to unpaid duties and surprise costs for buyers not listed at checkout.Across social media platforms, many independent sellers based in the UK are also announcing that they can no longer support orders to the US, citing the introduction of an $80 flat fee plus handling charges for using Royal Mail to ship parcels to the US."We hope to resume shipping as soon as we can, but we really don't want our customers to be hit with an $80+ fee," wrote the Citrine Circle, a UK-based crystal shop, on Instagram. "It feels like the world is getting smaller and smaller."The White House did not immediately respond to a request for comment.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A Kosovo Albanian woman is evacuated with her newborn daughter in a column of refugees, 1999.</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1mx3sny/a_kosovo_albanian_woman_is_evacuated_with_her/</link><author>/u/holyrs90</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 11:22:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>